<icda>
<communities>
      <community user="smaiti">
         <title>Family Medical Community</title>
         <content><![CDATA[<h2 dir="ltr" style="color: rgb(41, 41, 41); font-family: 'Helvetica Neue', Helvetica, Roboto, Arial; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; letter-spacing: normal; orphans: auto; text-align: start; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: 1; word-spacing: 0px; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px;">General Family Medicine / Complex Medical Care</h2>

<p class="p1" dir="ltr">Family Medicine is the foundation of our practice, which allows us to form lasting, caring relationships with you and your family. For us, a better way to be treated means taking the time to listen, manage your health history, and provide options to help you make the right health care choices throughout all stages of life.</p>

<p class="p1" dir="ltr">Our family medicine physicians specialize in preventive care as well as diagnosis and management of acute and chronic illness. Services include but are not limited to the following:</p>

<ul dir="ltr">
	<li class="p1">Pre-natal care, labor and delivery</li>
	<li class="p1">Newborn, adolescent and adult wellness exams</li>
	<li class="p1">Treatment of acute injuries and conditions</li>
	<li class="p1">Diagnosis and disease management</li>
	<li class="p1">Health and wellness counseling</li>
</ul>

<h4 dir="ltr" style="color: rgb(41, 41, 41); font-family: 'Helvetica Neue', Helvetica, Roboto, Arial; font-size: 12px; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; letter-spacing: normal; line-height: 18px; orphans: auto; text-align: start; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: 1; word-spacing: 0px; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px;">Hours: 8 a.m. - 7 p.m., seven days a week</h4>

<p align="left" dir="ltr" style="margin: 5px 0px 0px; color: rgb(41, 41, 41); font-family: 'Helvetica Neue', Helvetica, Roboto, Arial; font-size: 12px; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; letter-spacing: normal; line-height: 18px; orphans: auto; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: 1; word-spacing: 0px; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px;"><strong style="font-weight: bold;">4th Floor, Care Wing</strong><br>
<strong style="font-weight: bold;">Tel:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 555-864-5928</strong><br>
<strong style="font-weight: bold;">Fax:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 555-864-5714</strong><br>
<strong style="font-weight: bold;">E-mail:&nbsp;<a href="mailto:GIMclinic@smh.ca" style="text-decoration: none; color: rgb(65, 120, 190);">GFMclinic@ibm.com</a></strong></p>

<h4 dir="ltr" style="color: rgb(41, 41, 41); font-family: 'Helvetica Neue', Helvetica, Roboto, Arial; font-size: 12px; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; letter-spacing: normal; line-height: 18px; orphans: auto; text-align: start; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: 1; word-spacing: 0px; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px;">&nbsp;</h4>]]></content>
         <type>public</type>
         <isExternal>false</isExternal>
         <logo>7e4a0360-0e68-4cf9-9ac1-b698ae9b770a.png</logo>
         <tags>clinic,diabetes,elderly,family_medicine,general,gfm,healthcare</tags>
         <members>
            <member role="owner" user="smaiti"/>
            <member role="owner" user="abauer"/>
            <member role="member" user="vhanley"/>
            <member role="member" user="tamado"/>
            <member role="member" user="simdray"/>
            <member role="member" user="samcurman"/>
            <member role="member" user="rferrar"/>
            <member role="member" user="pdumont"/>
            <member role="member" user="pclemmons"/>
            <member role="member" user="nolmos"/>
            <member role="member" user="siduma"/>
            <member role="member" user="jhaj"/>
            <member role="member" user="gbandini"/>
            <member role="member" user="fadams"/>
            <member role="member" user="eelamon"/>
            <member role="member" user="dmisawa"/>
         </members>
         <forums>
            <forum user="smaiti">
               <title>General Family Medicine Clinic</title>
               <content/>
               <topics>
                  <topic user="abauer">
                     <title>Creative Solution for Memory Loss</title>
                     <content><![CDATA[
    <p dir="ltr">
      <span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif; font-size: medium;">"Art should be taught to everyone," says Dr. Collin's, neurological consultant at the Digital Hospital. For patients suffering from memory loss, he believes "it's better than many medications." Dr. Collin's research on memory shows artistic skills create "cognitive reserves" in patients with dementia, meaning they can still access their talents and related memories even after their ability to perform simpler, everyday tasks is lost.</span>
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif; font-size: medium;">Renowned sculptor Mary Hecht is a case-in-point. Even with advanced dementia, she could quickly sketch accurate portraits from memory and speak of them eloquently - even though she couldn't draw the correct time on a clock or remember words she was asked to recall.</span>
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif; font-size: medium;">Citing this important discovery, occupational therapists at the Digital Hospitals Memory Clinic encourage patients' creativity to help maintain and restore their memory.</span>
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <span style="font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif; font-size: medium;">What can you do to help preserve your memory? Take up a visual art, like sculpting or drawing. Join a dance class that teaches choreography. Choose artsy activities and give your brain a workout!</span>
    </p>
  ]]></content>
                     <likes>
                        <like user="nolmos"/>
                     </likes>
                  </topic>
                  <topic user="abauer">
                     <title>Getting Help from Family and Friends</title>
                     <content><![CDATA[<h1 dir="ltr">
      Getting Help from Family and Friends
    </h1>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Dealing with health and medical issues can be stressful and confusing. It can be a good idea to ask friends and family for support. They can listen to what the health care providers tell you, ask questions, and help ensure that things go smoothly. And they can help you get the care you need.
    </p>
    <h2 dir="ltr">
      <img alt="" src="http://connections6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/getinghelpfromfamily.JPG" style="margin: 10px; float: right; width: 255px; height: 171px;" title="" />Who to ask
    </h2>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Think about the people in your life who can be there for you. Ask for help from people who:
    </p>
    <ul dir="ltr">
      <li>
        <p>
          Have good judgment
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          Can talk to medical professionals
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          Are organized and think clearly
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          Can be assertive, if needed
        </p>
      </li>
    </ul>
    <h2 dir="ltr">
      How they can help
    </h2>
    <p dir="ltr">
      When you visit a health care provider, friends and family can:
    </p>
    <ul dir="ltr">
      <li>
        <p>
          Drive you to and from your visit.
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          Make you feel comfortable and more confident.
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          Remind you what you planned to tell or ask.
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          Take notes.
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          Help you remember what&nbsp;your health care provider&nbsp;says.
        </p>
      </li>
    </ul>
    <p dir="ltr">
      When you are ill, friends and family can:
    </p>
    <ul dir="ltr">
      <li>
        <p>
          Talk to your health care team for you.
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          Help you learn about your illness.
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          Help you make medical decisions.
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          Help you keep track of tests and treatment.
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          Give you emotional support.
        </p>
      </li>
    </ul>]]></content>
                     <likes>
                        <like user="abauer"/>
                        <like user="fadams"/>
                        <like user="nolmos"/>
                        <like user="vhanley"/>
                     </likes>
                     <replies>
                        <reply user="fadams">
                           <title>Re: Getting Help from Family and Friends</title>
                           <content><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">
      Very helpful information
    </p>]]></content>
                        </reply>
                        <reply user="nolmos">
                           <title>Re: Getting Help from Family and Friends</title>
                           <content><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">
      I agree this was worth the read.
    </p>]]></content>
                        </reply>
                     </replies>
                  </topic>
                  <topic user="abauer">
                     <title>Talking to Your Health Care Provider</title>
                     <content><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">
      Telling your health care provider (HCP) about yourself will help improve your care. And ask questions when you don't understand something, or just want to know more. Don't be afraid to speak up! Good communication with your HCP helps you get the most out of your health care.
    </p>
    <h2 dir="ltr">
      <img alt="" src="http://connections6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/talkingtoyourhealth.JPG" style="margin: 10px; float: right; width: 285px; height: 191px;" title="" />Talk About Your Lifestyle
    </h2>
    <p dir="ltr">
      All sorts of things can affect your health. So your HCP needs to know about your daily life.
    </p>
    <h2 dir="ltr">
      Tell Your HCP
    </h2>
    <ul dir="ltr">
      <li>
        <p>
          Where you work and what you do
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          Whether you live alone or with others
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          About your eating and sleeping habits
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          Whether you get regular exercise
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          If you drink alcohol or smoke
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          If you are under a lot of stress
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          If you are dealing with a major life change such as marriage, divorce, or retirement
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          Your health and wellness goals
        </p>
      </li>
    </ul>
    <h2 dir="ltr">
      Share Your Symptoms&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;
    </h2>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Symptoms are a change from what's normal. They suggest illness or injury. If you notice a change in the way your body looks, works, or feels, tell your HCP.
    </p>
    <h2 dir="ltr">
      Tell Your HCP<i>&nbsp;</i>
    </h2>
    <ul dir="ltr">
      <li>
        <p>
          The type of symptom, such as pain, fever, nausea, or weakness
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          When your symptoms started
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          How often you have symptoms
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          Whether your symptoms wake you up at night
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          Whether you have symptoms at a certain time of day or while you are doing specific things
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          How bad your symptoms are
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          Whether your symptoms interfere with your daily activities and, if so, how
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          Whether other family members or people you spend time with have similar symptoms
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          Whether your symptoms are getting better or worse
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          Whether you have had these symptoms before
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          Whether you have other symptoms
        </p>
      </li>
    </ul>
    <h2 dir="ltr">
      Discuss Your Diagnosis
    </h2>
    <p dir="ltr">
      A diagnosis identifies the cause of an illness or the reason for symptoms. Be sure you understand your diagnosis. This will make it easier for you and your HCP to reach decisions about your treatment and care.
    </p>
    <h2 dir="ltr">
      Ask Your HCP<i>&nbsp;</i>
    </h2>
    <ul dir="ltr">
      <li>
        <p>
          The name of the condition
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          The cause of the condition
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          How long the condition will last
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          Whether there will be any long-term effects
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          What you can do to prevent the condition in the future
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          How you can learn more about the condition
        </p>
      </li>
    </ul>
    <h2 dir="ltr">
      Ask About Medical Tests
    </h2>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Medical tests include things such as blood tests and X-rays. If you have a medical problem, tests can give your doctor more information. Tests can also uncover hidden health problems.
    </p>
    <h2 dir="ltr">
      Ask Your HCP
    </h2>
    <ul dir="ltr">
      <li>
        <p>
          Why you need the test
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          What the test results will show
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          If there are any risks
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          How accurate the test results will be
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          How much the test will cost and if there is a less expensive option
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          How the test is done and how long it will take
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          What you need to do to get ready for the test
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          How you will feel after the test
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          If you will be able to drive yourself home
        </p>
      </li>
    </ul>
    <h2 dir="ltr">
      Think Over Your Treatment Options
    </h2>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Many medical conditions can be treated. Your HCP may recommend a certain treatment. But it's a decision you need to make together.
    </p>
    <h2 dir="ltr">
      Ask Your HCP
    </h2>
    <ul dir="ltr">
      <li>
        <p>
          About all your treatment options, including diet, exercise, medication, and surgery
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          How much treatment will cost
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          How soon you should start treatment
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          How long treatment will last
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          Whether there are risks
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          What will happen if the condition is not treated
        </p>
      </li>
    </ul>
    <h2 dir="ltr">
      Ask About Prevention
    </h2>
    <p dir="ltr">
      The goal of prevention is to keep from developing diseases or conditions. It's easier to prevent illness than it is to cure it. Talk to your HCP about what you can do to keep yourself healthy.
    </p>
    <h2 dir="ltr">
      Ask Your HCP
    </h2>
    <ul dir="ltr">
      <li>
        <p>
          How often you should come in for checkups
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          Whether you should get shots to prevent disease
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          How often you should get screening tests
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          Whether you should make any lifestyle changes
        </p>
      </li>
    </ul>]]></content>
                     <likes>
                        <like user="rferrar"/>
                        <like user="eelamon"/>
                     </likes>
                     <replies>
                        <reply user="pclemmons">
                           <title>Re: Talking to Your Health Care Provider</title>
                           <content><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">
      Very detailed instructions.
    </p>]]></content>
                        </reply>
                     </replies>
                  </topic>
                  <topic user="pdumont">
                     <title>Protecting elderly patients from adverse drug interactions</title>
                     <content><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">
      Providing safe, effective medication management services is a critical concern for <a href="http://www.carekinesis.com/" target="_blank">CareKinesis, Inc.</a>, a clinical pharmacy serving patients enrolled in the <a href="http://www.cruxialcio.com/researchers-enlist-ibm-cloud-quest-better-safer-elder-care-7476" target="_blank">Program of All-Inclusive Care</a> for the Elderly (PACE) managed care organization.&nbsp; "Adverse drug events are the fifth leading cause of death in the United States," <a href="http://www.carekinesis.com/" target="_blank">CareKinesis chief executive officer Dr. Calvin Knowlton</a> says. "And when a patient is elderly, with a slowing metabolism and a complex medication regimen, the risk of an ADE increases significantly."
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <iframe align="right" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" frameborder="0" height="315" scrolling="no" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2XhNKTWk7fc" width="560"></iframe>
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      &nbsp;
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Harnessing the power of cloud and <a href="http://www.coriell.com/misc/coriell-life-sciences-wins-2015-ibm-beacon-award" target="_blank">teaming with IBM Business Partner Coriell Life Sciences</a>, CareKinesis identifies potentially harmful drug interactions for its patients with genomic testing and data analytics.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      "CareKinesis sends a sampling of cells swabbed from inside a patient's cheek to a gene sequencing lab, which then provides us with the raw genetic information," Coriell Life Sciences chief executive officer Scott Megill says. "Our Genomic Data Ecosystem platform interprets and aligns that information with a vast library of research on frequently prescribed drugs."
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      The result? Detailed, data-driven reports for safer, more accurate clinical decision making. "Knowing which drugs are working and which may be putting patients at risk is incredible insight that physicians simply have not had available to them in the past," Megill says.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      &nbsp;
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      SoftLayer cloud technology powers the innovative Genomic Data Ecosystem solution. "A genome sequence is 3 billion points of data for one individual, so we're talking about a lot of information," Megill says. "We knew that SoftLayer could handle the massive amounts of data we're working with."
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      &nbsp;
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      With the powerful platform, CareKinesis is greatly reducing ADE risk for its elderly patients. "We identified gene variants resulting in recommendations for medication changes, discontinuations or dosage adjustments for 82 percent of our participating patients," Knowlton says. "These modifications mean far fewer unnecessary hospitalizations and emergency room visits."
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Coriell anticipates easily extending its services to drive similar results in medical communities worldwide. "The infrastructure SoftLayer has built and its global reach allow us to immediately do business in countries that would typically require us to build our own data centers inside their borders," says Megill. "With a SoftLayer cloud hosting platform, we're immediately global."
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <em>Learn more about the work CareKinesis is doing with IBM Cloud in <a href="https://connections6.ibmcollabcloud.com/files/form/anonymous/api/library/f0731d46-6615-4783-8983-99a2b0e2b025/document/12bc32b9-cb7f-4b5f-9abe-251c93620e55/media/CareKinesis%20case%20study.pdf" target="_blank" title="Download CareKinesis case study.pdf"><img aria-hidden="true" class="lconn-ftype16 lconn-ftype16-pdf" src="https://connections6.ibmcollabcloud.com/connections/resources/web/com.ibm.lconn.core.styles.oneui3/images/blank.gif?etag=20150304.195314" /><strong>CareKinesis case study.pdf</strong></a><span aria-hidden="true" class="lotusDivider" role="img">|</span><a href="https://connections6.ibmcollabcloud.com/communities/service/html/communityview?communityUuid=6a0c9ecc-75c8-46e8-94c1-d2894c5111b1#fullpageWidgetId=W5d91b2b5cb8b_451b_8dca_cdd4e145227a&amp;file=12bc32b9-cb7f-4b5f-9abe-251c93620e55" target="_blank" title="View details of CareKinesis case study.pdf">View Details</a>.</em>
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      &nbsp;
    </p>]]></content>
                     <likes>
                        <like user="rferrar"/>
                        <like user="abauer"/>
                        <like user="eelamon"/>
                     </likes>
                  </topic>
                  <topic user="pclemmons">
                     <title>DIABETIZER takes diabetic monitoring and tracking to the cloud</title>
                     <content><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">
      DIABETIZER founder and chief executive officer Robin Hrassnigg understands the challenges of managing diabetes on a personal level.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      "I'm a Type 1 diabetic," he says, "and it's not easy to handle in daily life."
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Hrassnigg is one of an estimated 387 million people worldwide suffering from diabetes mellitus, a group of chronic diseases affecting the body's ability to properly use insulin. Day-to-day management of the illness requires diligent monitoring and logging of blood sugar levels, food intake, medication dosages, exercise and other critical variables.<img alt="" src="https://images1.newscred.com/cD00NWE2Y2ExMWExMWRjMDNhOTA2OTM3MDliOGIwNzUwZiZnPWY0YWRiYjE4NzdjOTk4YTA2ZTg4YjliNTZmOTI3YzNj" style="margin: 10px; float: right;" />
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Diabetic patients who rely on handwritten records or a series of disconnected applications for tracking purposes run a high risk of error. And when doctors don't have accurate insight into the factors contributing to a diabetic's overall health, they can't provide optimal treatment.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      "For diabetics, the wrong treatment can lead to additional health complications like vision problems, heart disease and nerve damage," Hrassnigg says.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      The solution was clear to Hrassnigg: a cloud-driven platform designed to automatically gather and analyze data from devices and wearable technology. "With cloud, we knew we could be very fast and flexible in building and deploying our solution," Hrassnigg says. "And we wouldn't have to worry about buying hardware-as a start-up venture, it was helpful that we could avoid the investment in infrastructure."
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      DIABETIZER joined the IBM Global Entrepreneur Program for Cloud Startups, an initiative providing cloud credits and access to the complete IBM Cloud portfolio. With the IBM Bluemix development platform and SoftLayer hosting infrastructure, the business launched myDIABETIZER, an application that amasses and synchronizes patient data in a single centralized portal accessible from virtually anywhere in the world.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      "We designed the myDIABETIZER app to collect and combine blood sugar and nutritional data from glucose meters with activity data from wearable fitness services like RunKeeper, Fitbit, MapMy Fitness and Nutritionix," Hrassnigg says. "The platform creates a centralized personal risk index so that a user can check his or her health status at any given moment."
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      &nbsp;
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      The platform has tremendous quality-of-life benefits for diabetics struggling with the daily burdens of managing the illness.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      "We're thrilled to give diabetics around the world greater mobility and freedom to travel," Hrassnigg says. "And on a daily basis, no matter where they are, patients are relieved of the need to constantly log their vital data."
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      The myDIABETIZER app supports on-the-fly monitoring and decision-making that are also invaluable to a patient's standard of living.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      "If one of our users is at a restaurant and wants to order dessert after dinner, he or she can check blood sugar levels and the impact of the food already consumed during the meal via mobile device to make sure that it's a safe choice," Hrassnigg says.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      For caregivers, the myDIABETIZER platform delivers detailed, accurate patient data to uncover patterns and reveal the correlation between specific activities and blood sugar levels.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      "The importance of accuracy cannot be overstated," Hrassnigg says. "By capturing and delivering accurate data, our platform drives better clinical decisions and more effective treatment for diabetic patients."
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <iframe allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" frameborder="0" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kvllGartAvE" width="560"></iframe>
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      &nbsp;
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <em>Check out <a href="https://connections6.ibmcollabcloud.com/files/form/anonymous/api/library/f0731d46-6615-4783-8983-99a2b0e2b025/document/16b692f5-016a-461c-9499-99993e2c8189/media/diabetic%20case%20study.pdf" target="_blank" title="Download diabetic case study.pdf"><img aria-hidden="true" class="lconn-ftype16 lconn-ftype16-pdf" src="https://connections6.ibmcollabcloud.com/connections/resources/web/com.ibm.lconn.core.styles.oneui3/images/blank.gif?etag=20150304.195314" /><strong>diabetic case study.pdf</strong></a><span aria-hidden="true" class="lotusDivider" role="img">|</span><a href="https://connections6.ibmcollabcloud.com/communities/service/html/communityview?communityUuid=6a0c9ecc-75c8-46e8-94c1-d2894c5111b1#fullpageWidgetId=W5d91b2b5cb8b_451b_8dca_cdd4e145227a&amp;file=16b692f5-016a-461c-9499-99993e2c8189" target="_blank" title="View details of diabetic case study.pdf">View Details</a> to learn more about how DIABETIZER is using the cloud to help&nbsp;monitor and track diabetes.</em>
    </p>]]></content>
                     <likes>
                        <like user="simdray"/>
                     </likes>
                     <replies>
                        <reply user="simdray">
                           <title>Re: DIABETIZER takes diabetic monitoring and tracking to the cloud</title>
                           <content><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">
      Great article on diabetics.
    </p>]]></content>
                        </reply>
                     </replies>
                  </topic>
                  <topic user="simdray">
                     <title>Data analytics help doctors develop cancer treatment plans in a day</title>
                     <content><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">
      More than 14 million people worldwide were diagnosed with cancer in 2012, <a href="http://www.who.int/mediacentre/factsheets/fs297/en/">according to the World Health Organization</a>, and that number is expected to rise about 70 percent over the next 20 years. A sobering prediction magnified by the expense and time required to develop treatment plans.&nbsp; <a href="http://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/homepage.html">Intel</a> and the <a href="http://www.ohsu.edu/xd/health/services/cancer/">Knight Cancer Institute at Oregon Health &amp; Science University (OHSU)</a> hope to completely transform the way medical institutions treat cancer by leveraging big data analytics and open cloud technologies
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Twelve years ago, the <a href="http://www.genome.gov/10001772">Human Genome Project</a> sequenced and mapped the human genome. The project enabled a massive leap forward in precision medicine - taking into account individual differences in people's genes, environments and lifestyles. Instead of going through the horrors of chemotherapy, which kills healthy cells along with cancerous cells, genomics can help patients by allowing for precision treatment plans tailored specifically to their disease.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <span style="line-height: 1.5;">But so far, this type of precision medicine is available only to a select few, due partly to expense, but also to the amount of time involved. Today, it can take weeks or even months to sequence an individual's DNA, and then additional weeks or months to analyze it. Typically, about 1 TB of raw data comes off a sequencer, but it could be 2 TB or even 3 TB. That data has to be combined with imaging data and other clinical data.</span>
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      "I experienced this first hand as a cancer patient five years ago," says Eric Dishman, director, Proactive Health Research, Intel. "The sequencing part only took a day in my case, but it took four months of processing and then another four months to use these huge files. I got lucky enough to survive that eight months from sequencing to treatment."
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <strong>Cutting treatment time from 8 months to 24 hours</strong>
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Intel and OHSU want to make it possible to sequence an individual's DNA, analyze it and formulate a precision treatment plan within 24 hours. At the Intel Developer Forum on Wednesday, the two partners announced an open platform-as-a-service (PaaS) solution called the Collaborative Cancer Cloud with the aim of getting to that point by 2020.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      The Collaborative Cancer Cloud is precision medicine analytics platform that allows medical institutions to securely share patient genomic, imaging and clinical data. Dishman says it will enable large amounts of data from sites all around the world to be analyzed in a distributed way, while preserving the privacy and security of the patient data at each site.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      "The challenge now is that as more and more cancer genomes and more genomes for all diseases get sequenced, we're facing a huge amount of data that's getting generated," says Dr. Brian Druker, director of the Knight Cancer Institute at OHSU. "We need to be able to share this data in a way that allows us to decipher what it's trying to tell us in a timely fashion.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      "We need data shared securely in a way that accelerates our ability to do analytics and get treatments to patients," he adds. "We need a future where this becomes much more commonplace. Imagine where we'll be in 2020. Instead of two percent of patients getting sequenced, it will be 10 percent, 20 percent, maybe even 100 percent. All in one day."
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Intel and the Knight Cancer Institute will launch the Collaborative Cancer Cloud and expect two new institutions to come on board by 2016.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      "And from there, we can open up this federated, secure Collaborative Cancer Cloud network to dozens of other institutions - or let them create their own - to accelerate the science and the precision treatment options for clinicians and their patients," Dishman says. "They can also apply it to advance personalized research in other diseases that are known to have a genetic component, including Alzheimer's, diabetes, autism and more."
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <span style="line-height: 1.5;">Each partner will maintain control of its patients' data, Dishman explains. But the federation will allow the shareable cancer treatment knowledgebase to grow in availability. Essentially, rather than transporting massive volumes of data, the Collaborative Cancer Cloud will allow clinicians to run analytics on all of the data where it resides.</span>
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <strong>The power of data</strong>
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      "We want to help harness the power of that data in a way that benefits clinicians, researchers and patients with a better knowledgebase and preserves security and privacy," Dishman says. "By securely sharing clinical research data amongst many institutions while maintaining patient privacy, the entire research community can benefit from insights revealed in large data cohorts."
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      As a complement, Intel plans to deliver open source code contributions to ensure the broadest developer base possible is working on delivering interoperable solutions. Dishman says open sourcing the code will drive both interoperability across different clouds and allow analytics across a broader set of data.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      "That to me is the real power of academics working with Intel," Druker says. "The analytics clearly have to be improved and sped up. As cancer biologists, we know what we have to learn from the data. Intel computer scientists can help us optimize the code and get to more efficient analyses."
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <a href="https://plus.google.com/+ThorOlavsrud/posts">&nbsp;</a>
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      &nbsp;
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      This article was written by Thor Olavsrud from CIO and was legally licensed through the NewsCred publisher network.
    </p>]]></content>
                  </topic>
                  <topic user="rferrar">
                     <title>How Big Data analytics help hospitals stop a killer</title>
                     <content><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">
      Big Data. Predictive analytics. Real-time. Actionable insight. There's a buzzword smorgasbord around the use of data to derive value. It doesn't help that sometimes the benefits can be esoteric, or at least hard to visualize. But sometimes the benefits are crystal clear, as in the fight against sepsis, one of the leading killers in the U.S.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Sepsis is a serious medical condition that occurs when the body unleashes the full force of the immune system in response to an infection. The immune chemicals trigger widespread inflammation that can result in impaired blood flow and damage to (and failure) of the body's organs.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      According to the National Institute of General Medical Sciences, more than a million Americans get severe sepsis every year and between 28 percent and 50 percent of them die - more than the annual U.S. deaths from prostate cancer, breast cancer and AIDs combined. It is the leading cause of death in noncoronary intensive care units (ICUs) in U.S. hospitals and the 10th leading cause of death in the U.S. overall.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      How Sepsis spreads
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Sepsis frequently arises in hospitals because it always stems from another medical condition - an infection in the lungs, urinary tract, skin, appendicitis, or as the result of invasive medical procedures (e.g., the insertion of a vascular catheter that introduces bacteria into the bloodstream).
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <span style="line-height: 1.5;">The signs that a patient has system inflammatory response syndrome (SIRS), a precursor to sepsis, can be difficult to diagnose, even in a hospital setting, because they mimic other conditions. Common symptoms include fever, chills, rapid breathing and heart rate, rash, confusion and disorientation. Diagnosing sepsis often requires a blood test to look for an abnormal number of white blood cells, or an elevated lactate level, which correlates with the severity of the condition. Chest x-rays or CT scans can also be used to identify infections.</span>
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Unfortunately, these symptoms often occur after a patient has been discharged from the hospital. The condition arises unpredictably and can progress rapidly, which means a patient could have severe sepsis and be spiraling toward septic shock and multiple organ failure before seeking help.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      That intensifies the problem, because it can be very difficult to revive a patient that has gone into septic shock. The damage to organs can be permanent. It's vital to catch SIRS early, before it can progress.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Sepsis isn't just a killer, it's also a massive cost for the healthcare industry. The Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality found that sepsis was far and away the most expensive condition treated in U.S. hospitals in 2011 at more than $20 billion ($5 billion more than the next-leading expense, osteoarthritis), and the incidence of sepsis has increased since then.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <strong>Enter Big Data</strong>
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Here's where all those Big Data buzzwords come in. IT consulting and managed services provider Hitachi Consulting (a subsidiary of Hitachi) has joined forces with medical device maker Vital Connect and analytics specialist ClearStory Data to create a live clinical monitoring solution that can detect symptoms related to SIRS.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <span style="line-height: 1.5;">The prototype solution, showcased at the HIMSS15 Healthcare IT conference in April, consists of a disposable wireless Band-Aid-like biosensor (the FDA-certified HealthPatch), real-time processing of patient data using ClearStory Data's solution, and consumable analysis that allows medical professionals to take immediate action.</span>
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Vital Connect's HealthPatch, which is worn on the chest directly over the heart, is designed to monitor a patient's vital signs and track other information, including physical activity, posture, even falls. It connects wirelessly to a smartphone, when an app can show statistics such as steps taken, heart rate, breathing, skin temperature and more. It can be worn while a patient is awake, sleeping or even in the shower.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <img alt="" src="http://core0.staticworld.net//images/article/2015/07/clearstory-data-sepsis-alert-storyboard-100597109-large.idge.jpg" style="margin: 10px; float: right;" />
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      ClearStory Data provides near real-time measurements on the massive volumes of biosensor data analyzed by algorithms modeled after clinical practice standards. A patient storyboard (above) identifies and alerts clinicians to patients who might be at risk.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <span data-mce-mark="1" style="line-height: 1.5;">The smartphone app transmits the patient clinical data to a cloud-based repository, where it is mashed up with existing patient data from other data sources (NoSQL and SQL-based data sources, premium data sources, etc.). Caregivers can use ClearStory Data to analyze and correlate the data against systemic patterns to detect the potential of SIRS.</span>
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      "These devices throw off data on heart rate, temperature, energy consumption, blood pressure, etc.," says Sharmila Mulligan, CEO and founder of ClearStory Data. "Even body posture. Your posture changes when you have sepsis; you start slowing down in how you walk. If the patient is actually showing that a couple of these attributes are starting to hit certain numbers, they are on their way to having a high-risk situation. Caregivers need to see this data in real-time."
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      ClearStory Data, powered by Apache Spark, provides fast-cycle, near real-time measurements on the massive volumes of biosensor data analyzed by algorithms modeled after clinical practice standards used in conventional human clinical monitoring disciplines. A patient "storyboard" identifies and alerts clinicians to patients who might be at risk based upon the biosensor measures. Serum level testing can then be used to confirm the presence of SIRS and/or sepsis.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <strong>Saving lives and cutting costs</strong>
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      U.S. states are beginning to take action in an effort to save lives and bring down the cost of healthcare. New York took the lead in 2013, when Gov. Andrew Cuomo introduced a sweeping set of regulations that required hospitals to adopt evidence-based practices to bring down sepsis mortality rates.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      The measures were prompted in part by the 2012 death of 12-year-old Rory Staunton, a sixth-grader from Queens, who died of severe septic shock following a cut received while playing basketball in gym class. Staunton was treated in the NYU Langone Medical Center emergency room then sent home. Vital signs taken at the hospital indicated several of the symptoms that could be used to diagnose sepsis, but caregivers failed to put the picture together. He died in an intensive care unit three days later.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Sixteen other states have followed New York and adopted similar measures.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      "Every country has this problem," Mulligan says. "They're doing the same thing."
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      For instance, she notes that Singapore has undertaken a five-year project to digitize the whole city. As part of the project, every patient who leaves a noncoronary ICU will get a HealthPatch to monitor their condition.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      "This ground-breaking solution enables hospital and clinic caregivers to make fast, real-time data-driven decisions that have an immediate impact on patient care and diagnosis, while reducing healthcare expenditures," Mulligan says. "The solution exemplifies the speed, scale and power of next-generation analysis to serve up critical information in real-time and confirms that unprecedented innovation in healthcare is well within reach."
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      &nbsp;
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      This article was written by Thor Olavsrud from CIO and was legally licensed through the NewsCred publisher network.
    </p>]]></content>
                  </topic>
                  <topic user="pclemmons">
                     <title>IBM intros Watson Health Cloud for Life Sciences Compliance</title>
                     <content><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">
      <img alt="" height="129" src="http://www.thoughtsoncloud.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/wpid-thumbnail-75d11a2ecd8d04be1511d791552d6c06-300x150.jpeg" style="margin: 10px; float: left;" width="258" />For years, regulatory issues have made it difficult for the life sciences industry to take advantage of cloud computing's myriad benefits. That's likely to change with the introduction of IBM Watson Health Cloud for Life Sciences Compliance.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      IBM's latest offering provides a comprehensive cloud infrastructure solution to help life science clients take advantage of cloud computing. They can do this while maintaining their compliance program, providing validated and qualified cloud infrastructure, tools, and expertise.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Regulations governing the testing and manufacturing of drugs or medical devices are intended to assure that these products are safe and effective. &nbsp;Today, computerized systems are an essential and integral part of drug and medical device development and manufacture.&nbsp; To assure the integrity of data collected by life science companies and the quality of products, computerized systems must be tested to assure that they function reliably.&nbsp; Such testing includes:
    </p>
    <ul dir="ltr">
      <li>
        &nbsp;Qualification of the IT infrastructure on which software applications are run
      </li>
      <li>
        &nbsp;Validation of software applications that perform regulated activities
      </li>
    </ul>
    <p dir="ltr">
      The key challenge around these requirements is having the skills, resources, capital, and time to deploy a qualified infrastructure and validated applications.&nbsp; This process can often take months, which can delay product releases and increase costs.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Anything a pharmaceutical or medical device company does that relies on a software application needs to be built on qualified infrastructure. IBM Watson Health Cloud for Life Sciences Compliance managed infrastructure as a service (IaaS) provides the platform for supporting all of those functions.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <iframe allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" frameborder="0" height="315" scrolling="no" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/g_ktXeecbnU" width="560"></iframe>
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      &nbsp;
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      "The service lives in the cloud on SoftLayer's bare metal infrastructure," says Vinod Chavan, IBM Cloud Global Technical Solutions Executive. "This will give our clients the flexibility, scalability and control they need to bring innovation to market even faster."
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      IBM Watson Health Cloud for Life Sciences Compliance is managed under a life science industry quality management system.&nbsp; This system includes trained personnel operating under the guidance of IBM's Life Sciences Regulatory Center of Excellence, an incident, problem, and change management system, a document management system and a learning management system. These applications have been validated, which means they've gone through the rigorous testing and are operated under strict controls. &nbsp;This includes the cloud operation and management software, a major differentiator from other cloud service providers' "black box" approach to cloud management software.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      "Every client will get a private cloud on the dedicated bare metal servers with VPN connectivity to on-premises environments, enterprise grade performance and state of the art security capabilities," Chavan says. "They will be able to add, change, retire virtual machines, networks and storage based on the business requirements."
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      The new offering will allow clients to be more nimble by taking advantage of cloud computing's on-demand flexibility and decreasing the time and expense required to provision and qualify infrastructure; ultimately accelerating time to market in developing new drugs and medical devices.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      We foresee a wide range of applications that can be built on this IaaS, like customizable control systems, clinical trial management and analytics systems, and patient monitoring systems.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      As with any industry, life sciences customers are interested in reducing costs. These companies can now take advantage of cloud's pay-as-you go model, and they're not beholden to hefty initial investments. We've heard from numerous life sciences customers that they want to use cloud as a utility. They want all of the advantages that cloud can offer-scalability, elasticity and on-demand service.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Because we've built it in a way that will support their compliance program, IBM Watson Health Cloud for Life Sciences Compliance makes cloud a reality for a vital field. The net result is a win-win:&nbsp; Patients can benefit from critical medical products faster. Pharmaceutical and medical device companies can reap profits sooner by getting their products to customers faster without compromising their compliance program.<strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong>
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <strong>&nbsp;</strong><em>James McCormack, Ph.D., is IBM's Vice President of Life Sciences Compliance</em>
    </p>]]></content>
                  </topic>
                  <topic user="gbandini">
                     <title>I need to cancel or reschedule a new patient appointment; what should I do?</title>
                     <content><![CDATA[
  ]]></content>
                     <question>true</question>
                     <answered>true</answered>
                     <likes>
                        <like user="nolmos"/>
                        <like user="smaiti"/>
                     </likes>
                     <replies>
                        <reply user="jhaj">
                           <title>Re: I need to cancel or reschedule a new patient appointment; what should I do?</title>
                           <content><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">
      Contact the new patient intake service at (555) 555-7449. We ask that you try to provide at least 24 hours' notice before cancelling or changing your appointment.
    </p>]]></content>
                           <answer>true</answer>
                        </reply>
                     </replies>
                  </topic>
                  <topic user="nolmos">
                     <title>I want to be a patient at a specific health centre  do I have a choice about where Ill be a patient?</title>
                     <content><![CDATA[
  ]]></content>
                     <question>true</question>
                  </topic>
                  <topic user="vhanley">
                     <title>Who is eligible for in-home care?</title>
                     <content><![CDATA[
  ]]></content>
                     <question>true</question>
                     <answered>true</answered>
                     <likes>
                        <like user="siduma"/>
                     </likes>
                     <replies>
                        <reply user="samcurman">
                           <title>Re: Who is eligible for in-home care?</title>
                           <content><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">
      <strong>To be eligible for in-home care, you must be:</strong>
    </p>
    <ul dir="ltr">
      <li>
        Aged 65 or older
      </li>
      <li>
        Unable to attend clinic because of a disability
      </li>
      <li>
        Not living in a retirement or nursing home facility
      </li>
      <li>
        Not receiving Palliative Care services
      </li>
      <li>
        Living within the program boundaries
      </li>
    </ul>
    <p dir="ltr">
      The in-home visit team includes
    </p>
    <ul dir="ltr">
      <li>
        Family physicians
      </li>
      <li>
        Nurse practitioners
      </li>
      <li>
        Pharmacists
      </li>
      <li>
        Community Care Access Centers (CCAC) care coordinator
      </li>
      <li>
        Specialty care providers
      </li>
    </ul>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <strong>To get a referral to the home visiting service:</strong>
    </p>
    <ul dir="ltr">
      <li>
        Speak with your family doctor or community care access center coordinator to be referred to the program
      </li>
      <li>
        We are currently a small project caring for 30 patients at a time.
      </li>
    </ul>]]></content>
                           <answer>true</answer>
                           <likes>
                              <like user="fadams"/>
                           </likes>
                           <reply user="vhanley">
                              <title>Re: Who is eligible for in-home care?</title>
                              <content><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">
      This is exactly what I needed.&nbsp; Thanks
    </p>]]></content>
                              <likes>
                                 <like user="abauer"/>
                              </likes>
                           </reply>
                        </reply>
                     </replies>
                  </topic>
               </topics>
            </forum>
         </forums>
         <bookmarks/>
         <files>
            <file user="pclemmons">
               <label>diabetic case study.pdf</label>
               <type>application/pdf</type>
               <summary/>
               <visibility>private</visibility>
               <tags>diabetic,diabetizer</tags>
            </file>
            <file user="pdumont">
               <label>CareKinesis case study.pdf</label>
               <type>application/pdf</type>
               <summary/>
               <visibility>private</visibility>
               <tags>carekinesis</tags>
            </file>
         </files>
         <blogs>
            <communityblog user="smaiti">
               <title>Fish and polychlorinated biphenyls (PCBs)</title>
               <handle>7e4a0360-0e68-4cf9-9ac1-b698ae9b770a</handle>
               <summary/>
               <posts>
                  <post user="smaiti">
                     <title>Popularity of soda slips</title>
                     <content><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr"><strong>Good news! </strong>A Gallup poll reports that Americans are actively trying to drink less soda and cut back on sugar, while also striving to include more fruits and vegetables in their diets. These results suggest that Americans are getting the message about the importance of a healthy balanced diet.</p>



<p dir="ltr">Sixty-one percent of people surveyed said they&#39;re trying to exclude both regular and diet soda from their diet. This number is up from 41 percent in 2002. The main reason for avoiding regular soda is to cut down on sugar and calories. Avoidance of diet sodas appears to be motivated by concerns about artificial sweeteners.<a href="http://connections6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/can%202.png" target="_blank"><img alt="image" src="http://connections6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/can%202.png" style=" width:200px;  display:block; margin: 1em 0pt 0pt 1em; float: right;"></img></a></p>



<p dir="ltr">Do you have similar goals? Here are some tips to help you cut back on soda and sugar and eat more fruits and vegetables:</p>



<p dir="ltr">Drink water. If you want bubbles, try seltzer or mineral water. To make water more appealing, flavor it with fruits, vegetables or herbs such as mint.<br>

Check ingredient labels for added sugars and artificial sweeteners. Choose products with the least amount of added sugar and sweeteners.<br>

Sweeten homemade smoothies, cereals, muffins or salad dressing with fruit instead of table sugar.<br>

Make half of meals fruits and vegetables &mdash; as the main dish or included in casseroles, sauces or toppings.<br>

Visit your local market and see what produce is in season. Plan meals around your purchases.<br>

Keep frozen and canned fruits and vegetables on hand as an easy way to add balance to any meal.</p>]]></content>
                     <tags>diets,health</tags>
                     <likes>
                        <like user="tamado"/>
                        <like user="jhaj"/>
                     </likes>
                     <comments>
                        <comment user="jhaj">
                           <content><![CDATA[This is great news!!]]></content>
                        </comment>
                     </comments>
                  </post>
                  <post user="tamado">
                     <title>Fish and polychlorinated biphenyls (PCBs)</title>
                     <content><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">Our recent blog post on eating fish during pregnancy prompted one reader to ask why we didn&#39;t mention that salmon is high in dangerous PCBs. So what are PCBs and what risk do they pose?</p>



<p dir="ltr">Polychlorinated biphenyls (PCBs) are industrial chemicals that were manufactured from 1929 until 1979 when they were banned. PCBs have been shown to cause adverse health effects, including potential cancers, and negative effects on the immune, nervous and endocrine systems.</p>



<p dir="ltr">PCB remnants still cycle between air, water and soil, and traces are found all over the world. PCBs settle into water and sediment, where they are taken up by small organisms, fish and animals (including humans) that eat fish. PCBs accumulate in fat and in organs such as liver.</p>



<p dir="ltr">PCBs can pose serious health risks to people who frequently eat contaminated fish. PCBs can be transferred from a mother to her unborn baby, increasing the risk of preterm delivery and low birth weight. PCBs may also be transferred from mother to baby through breast milk, and exposure has been associated with learning defects.<a href="http://connections6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/fish.JPG" target="_blank"><img alt="image" src="http://connections6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/fish.JPG" style=" width:200px;  display:block; margin: 1em 0pt 0pt 1em; float: right;"></img></a></p>



<p dir="ltr">Fish are the major dietary sources of PCBs, especially fish caught in contaminated lakes or rivers. However, small amounts are also found in meat, dairy products and drinking water.</p>



<p dir="ltr">The Food and Drug Administration (FDA) sets PCB residue limits for foods, while the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) sets limits for lakes, streams and drinking water. In 2004 these agencies came out with guidelines for fish consumption during pregnancy but PCBs weren&#39;t mentioned. Nor were they mentioned in last year&#39;s draft update of the guidelines. The final guidelines are expected to be released later this year.</p>



<p dir="ltr">However, two other groups, Physicians for Social Responsibility (PSR) and the Association of Reproductive Health Professionals (ARHP), released fish consumption guidelines that do address PCBs.</p>



<p dir="ltr">The PSR/ARHP guidelines specifically mention the need for caution with fish, such as salmon, that can contain high levels of PCBs. With respect to salmon, the guidelines say:</p>



<p dir="ltr">Canned Pacific salmon can be eaten twice a week<br>

Fresh or frozen wild Pacific salmon can be eaten up to twice a month<br>

Fresh or frozen farmed Atlantic salmon can be eaten once every 2 months</p>



<p dir="ltr">The guidelines also recommend ways to reduce PCB risks in the preparation of salmon and other fatty fish:</p>



<p dir="ltr">Trim fatty areas (belly, top back and dark meat along the side)<br>

Remove or puncture skin before cooking to allow fat to drain off<br>

Broil, grill, roast or steam fish on a rack to allow fat to drain off<br>

Do not fry large fatty fish such as salmon and bluefish</p>



<p dir="ltr">Both sets of guidelines agree that:</p>



<p dir="ltr">The benefits of eating fish outweigh the risks.<br>

Eating a variety of fish is a good way to minimize risks from contaminants.<br>

Because of high levels mercury (another common pollutant), king mackerel, shark, swordfish and tilefish should be avoided.</p>



<p dir="ltr">The bottom line: Eat a variety of fish twice a week and keep the portion size at 6 ounces (170 grams). When you eat fatty fish like salmon, make sure they&#39;re prepared using the above guidelines. When you catch your own fish, follow local and state fish advisories for restrictions.</p>]]></content>
                  </post>
               </posts>
            </communityblog>
         </blogs>
         <wikis>
            <wiki user="smaiti">
               <title>Family Medical Community</title>
               <summary><![CDATA[The General Internal Medicine (GIM) Clinic is a resident-based outpatient practice where patients with complicated medical issues or diagnostic dilemmas are reviewed and assessed over 3-4 visits and then return for ongoing care with their primary care giver. Findoutmore.]]></summary>
               <label>W450ce4b00d2a_40b6_b59f_b8435c5bbc0e</label>
               <visibility>PUBLIC_TO_VIEWERS</visibility>
               <pages>
                  <page user="smaiti">
                     <title>Family Medicine Clinic</title>
                     <label>Family Medicine Clinic</label>
                     <content><![CDATA[<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!DOCTYPE html [<!ENTITY amp "&#38;#38;"><!ENTITY lt "&#60;#60;"><!ENTITY gt "&#62;#62;"><!ENTITY nbsp "&#160;"><!ENTITY apos "&#39;"><!ENTITY quot "&#34;">]><div><h2 dir="ltr" style="color: rgb(41, 41, 41); font-family: &apos;Helvetica Neue&apos;, Helvetica, Roboto, Arial; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; letter-spacing: normal; text-align: start; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: 1; word-spacing: 0px; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px;">Family Medicine</h2><p class="p1" dir="ltr">Family Medicine is the foundation of our practice, which allows us to form lasting, caring relationships with you and your family. For us, a better way to be treated means taking the time to listen, manage your health history, and provide options to help you make the right health care choices throughout all stages of life.</p><p class="p1" dir="ltr">Our family medicine physicians specialize in preventive care as well as diagnosis and management of acute and chronic illness. Services include but are not limited to the following:</p><ul dir="ltr">	<li class="p1">Pre-natal care, labor and delivery</li>	<li class="p1">Newborn, adolescent and adult wellness exams</li>	<li class="p1">Treatment of acute injuries and conditions</li>	<li class="p1">Diagnosis and disease management</li>	<li class="p1">Health and wellness counseling</li></ul><div dir="ltr"><ul dir="ltr" style="padding: 4em 0; width:100%; margin: 0 auto; font-family: roboto, helvetica, Arial;">	<li style="display: inline-block; width: 70%; vertical-align: top; overflow: hidden; background-color: rgba(50, 92,128, 0.8); padding: 15px; box-sizing: border-box;">	<h2 style="margin: 0; color: #fff !important;"><span style="font-weight: 600; font-size: 1.7em;">The Staff</span></h2>	&nbsp;	<ul style="width: 100%; font-family: roboto, helvetica, Arial;">		<li style="display: inline-block; width: 20%">		<h4 style="color: #ffffff !important;">Family Doctor</h4>		<div class="staffLeft" role="presentation" style="float: none !important;"><span class="staffComm"><a class="fn url" href="/profiles/html/profileView.do?key=51a9cce2-e240-4860-9092-884652d51d19" title=""><img alt="Dr Paul Clemmons" class="staffPeople32" height="85" src="/profiles/photo.do?key=51a9cce2-e240-4860-9092-884652d51d19" title="Dr Paul Clemmons" width="85" /></a><span class="x-lconn-userid" style="display: none;">51a9cce2-e240-4860-9092-884652d51d19</span><span class="x-lconn-displayname" style="display: none;">Dr Paul Clemmons</span></span></div>		</li>		<li style="display: inline-block; width: 20%">		<h4 style="color: #ffffff !important;">Cancer Doctor</h4>		<div class="staffLeft" role="presentation" style="float: none !important;"><span class="staffComm"><a class="fn url" href="/profiles/html/profileView.do?key=f7a7eaca-408f-4597-b996-4a80f157d519" title=""><img alt="Dr Rita Ferrar" class="staffPeople32" height="85" src="/profiles/photo.do?key=f7a7eaca-408f-4597-b996-4a80f157d519" title="Dr Rita Ferrar" width="85" /></a><span class="x-lconn-userid" style="display: none;">f7a7eaca-408f-4597-b996-4a80f157d519</span><span class="x-lconn-displayname" style="display: none;">Dr Rita Ferrar</span></span></div>		</li>		<li style="display: inline-block; width: 20%">		<h4 style="color: #ffffff !important;">Diabetes Doctor</h4>		<div class="staffLeft" role="presentation" style="float: none !important;"><span class="staffComm"><a class="fn url" href="/profiles/html/profileView.do?key=28cda719-fab8-4b9b-ae95-0ea3929a69a5" title=""><img alt="Dr Simone Dray" class="staffPeople32" height="85" src="/profiles/photo.do?key=28cda719-fab8-4b9b-ae95-0ea3929a69a5" title="Dr Simone Dray" width="85" /></a><span class="x-lconn-userid" style="display: none;">28cda719-fab8-4b9b-ae95-0ea3929a69a5</span><span class="x-lconn-displayname" style="display: none;">Dr Simone Dray</span></span></div>		</li>		<li style="display: inline-block; width: 20%">		<h4 style="color: #ffffff !important;">Cardiac Doctor</h4>		<div class="staffLeft" role="presentation" style="float: none !important;"><span class="staffComm"><a class="fn url" href="/profiles/html/profileView.do?key=4e080698-0993-4a5f-8d37-73c197e27b80" title=""><img alt="Dr Pierre Dumont" class="staffPeople32" height="85" src="/profiles/photo.do?key=4e080698-0993-4a5f-8d37-73c197e27b80" title="Dr Pierre Dumont" width="85" /></a><span class="x-lconn-userid" style="display: none;">4e080698-0993-4a5f-8d37-73c197e27b80</span><span class="x-lconn-displayname" style="display: none;">Dr Pierre Dumont</span></span></div>		</li>	</ul>	<p style="margin: 0; font-size: 1.2em; color: #fff">&nbsp;</p>	</li></ul></div><div dir="ltr" style="height: 10px; width: 95%;">&nbsp;</div><p dir="ltr" style="margin: 5px 0px 0px; color: rgb(41, 41, 41); font-family: &apos;Helvetica Neue&apos;, Helvetica, Roboto, Arial; font-size: 12px; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; letter-spacing: normal; line-height: 18px; text-align: start; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: 1; word-spacing: 0px; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px;"><span style="font-size: 24px;"><strong style="font-weight: bold;">Referral process</strong></span></p><p dir="ltr" style="margin: 5px 0px 0px; color: rgb(41, 41, 41); font-family: &apos;Helvetica Neue&apos;, Helvetica, Roboto, Arial; font-size: 12px; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; letter-spacing: normal; line-height: 18px; text-align: start; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: 1; word-spacing: 0px; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px;"><strong style="font-weight: bold;"><span style="font-size: 16px;">To refer you patient to the&nbsp; Clinic, please use this <a href="http://playground.ibmcollabcloud.com/forms/secure/org/app/eb834d95-f9da-4cec-8f9d-891ce538c1e9/launch/index.html?form=F_LibraryRegistration" style="text-decoration: none; color: rgb(65, 120, 190);" target="_blank">Referral&nbsp;Form</a></span></strong></p><p dir="ltr" style="margin: 5px 0px 0px; color: rgb(41, 41, 41); font-family: &apos;Helvetica Neue&apos;, Helvetica, Roboto, Arial; font-size: 12px; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; letter-spacing: normal; line-height: 18px; text-align: start; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: 1; word-spacing: 0px; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px;">The Family Medicine Clinic.&nbsp; New referrals of all types are welcome.</p><p dir="ltr" style="margin: 5px 0px 0px; color: rgb(41, 41, 41); font-family: &apos;Helvetica Neue&apos;, Helvetica, Roboto, Arial; font-size: 12px; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; letter-spacing: normal; line-height: 18px; text-align: start; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: 1; word-spacing: 0px; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px;">When a patient is referred to a specific staff physician, every effort is made to honor that request.</p><p dir="ltr" style="margin: 5px 0px 0px; color: rgb(41, 41, 41); font-family: &apos;Helvetica Neue&apos;, Helvetica, Roboto, Arial; font-size: 12px; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; letter-spacing: normal; line-height: 18px; text-align: start; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: 1; word-spacing: 0px; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px;">Referrals can be sent to the Clinic via fax 555-864-5714.</p><p dir="ltr" style="margin: 5px 0px 0px; color: rgb(41, 41, 41); font-family: &apos;Helvetica Neue&apos;, Helvetica, Roboto, Arial; font-size: 12px; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; letter-spacing: normal; line-height: 18px; text-align: start; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: 1; word-spacing: 0px; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px;"><a href="http://playground.ibmcollabcloud.com/forms/secure/org/app/eb834d95-f9da-4cec-8f9d-891ce538c1e9/launch/index.html?form=F_LibraryRegistration" style="text-decoration: none; color: rgb(65, 120, 190);" target="_blank">Download&nbsp;referral&nbsp;form&nbsp;here</a></p><ol dir="ltr" style="padding: 0px 40px; color: rgb(41, 41, 41); font-family: &apos;Helvetica Neue&apos;, Helvetica, Roboto, Arial; font-size: 12px; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; letter-spacing: normal; line-height: text-align: start; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: 1; word-spacing: 0px; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px;">	<li>Fax referral to 555-864-5714</li>	<li>Once the referral is triaged, an appointment will be faxed to the referring physician. Please contact the patient with the appointment details and have them call to confirm their appointment.</li>	<li>Be sure to send us any pertinent test results and/or consult notes.</li></ol></div>]]></content>
                     <tags>cancer,diabetes,family,gfm,healthcare,referral</tags>
                  </page>
                  <page user="abauer">
                     <title>Referral Form</title>
                     <label>Referral Form</label>
                     <content><![CDATA[<div><p dir="ltr"><iframe frameborder="0" height="2000" scrolling="yes" src="http://digital.ibmcollabcloud.com/forms/secure/org/app/eb834d95-f9da-4cec-8f9d-891ce538c1e9/launch/index.html?form=F_LibraryRegistration" width="1000" /></p></div>]]></content>
                  </page>
                  <page user="abauer">
                     <title>Oncology Cancer care</title>
                     <label>Oncology Cancer care</label>
                     <content><![CDATA[<div><h4 dir="ltr">Medical Daycare Unit</h4><p dir="ltr"><img  style="margin: 10px; float: left; width: 119px; height: 180px;" lconnwikiparamattachmentname="doctor clip board.jpg" src="http://connections6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/doctorclipboard.jpg" lconnwikiparamwikipage="Oncology Cancer care" lconnwikimacro="image" title="" alt=""/>In the medical daycare unit, we provide outpatient cancer care to approximately 600 patients per month. Patients seen in this clinic are treated for a range of cancers, including breast, colon, bowel and lung cancer. We also treat disorders of the blood. Care is provided by an interdisciplinary team comprised of doctors, nurses, a social worker and a dietitian, all of whom have expertise in providing care to cancer patients.</p><p dir="ltr">You can reach the unit by phone between 8 a.m. and 4:30 p.m.</p><h4 dir="ltr"><br />Inpatient Oncology Unit</h4><p dir="ltr">The inpatient oncology unit is located on the same floor as the medical daycare unit. Care is provided by a multidisciplinary team that includes nurses, doctors, a social worker, a dietitian, a physiotherapist and a chaplain.</p><p dir="ltr"></p><h4 dir="ltr">Contact Us</h4><p dir="ltr">Digital Hospital<br />10 IBM Way<br />New York<br /></p><p dir="ltr">Phone: 555-864-5222<br />Fax: 55-864-5273</p></div>]]></content>
                  </page>
                  <page user="pdumont">
                     <title>Pediatric Ambulatory Clinic</title>
                     <label>Pediatric Ambulatory Clinic</label>
                     <content><![CDATA[<div><p dir="ltr">We offer a wide array of specialty clinics to meet the needs of children and youth. We offer clinics in a number of fields:</p><ul dir="ltr">	<li>antenatal consultation</li>	<li>developmental assessment</li>	<li>dietetic/nutritional support</li>	<li>fetal alcohol spectrum disorder diagnostic</li>	<li>general pediatric consultation</li>	<li>inner city youth</li>	<li>neonatal follow-up</li></ul><p dir="ltr">Our dynamic team of healthcare professionals works to meet the special needs of children and youth. The professionals involved in your childs care include</p><ul dir="ltr">	<li>adolescent medicine specialists</li>	<li>clinical nurse specialists and nurse practitioners</li>	<li>dieticians</li>	<li>developmental pediatricians</li>	<li>lactation consultants</li>	<li>neurodevelopmental testing nurses</li>	<li>pediatricians and neonatalogists</li>	<li>pediatric nurses</li></ul><p dir="ltr"><img height="183" src="http://connections6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/kid.JPG" width="275" /></p></div>]]></content>
                     <tags>care,children,clinic,pediatric</tags>
                  </page>
                  <page user="pdumont">
                     <title>Maternity care</title>
                     <label>Maternity care</label>
                     <content><![CDATA[<div><p dir="ltr">Family Health Team can provide care to you throughout your pregnancy. Your health care provider will take care of you with the team of family medicine obstetrics providers who will attend your babys delivery. This team based approach to prenatal care allows for a smooth transition to parenthood.<br /><br />It is a good idea to contact your primary care providers office as soon as you are aware of your pregnancy. Your initial visit should be within your first 10 weeks of pregnancy. Prenatal visits are every four weeks during the early part of pregnancy, and they become more frequent as you get closer to your due date. Partners are welcome to join you for your appointments.<br /><br /><strong>What services does the family medicine obstetrics team provide?</strong><img src="http://connections6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/doctorandbaby.png" style="width: 221px; height: 146px; margin: 10px; float: right;" /></p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Care initially from your own health care provider</strong></p><ul dir="ltr">	<li>We encourage you to continue seeking care from your usual primary care provider for as long as the two of you feel comfortable.</li></ul><p dir="ltr"><strong>Care at 28 weeks</strong></p><ul dir="ltr">	<li>After 28 weeks you will be introduced to the family medicine obstetrics provider at your clinic. This will be the doctor you see in the last three months of your pregnancy.</li>	<li>Meet the doctor night	<ul>		<li>You have the chance to meet all the family medicine obstetrics providers on the first Monday in September, December, February and June at 7 p.m.</li>		<li>No appointment is required but ask your doctor or nurse for confirmation of the date and location.</li>	</ul>	</li></ul><p dir="ltr"><strong>Prenatal classes</strong></p><ul dir="ltr">	<li>We recommend enrolling in the Hospital Academic Family Health Teams prenatal classes (ask your doctor or nurse for class information)</li></ul><p dir="ltr"><strong>What happens when my baby is born?</strong></p><p dir="ltr">We recommend that within one to two days of leaving the hospital, your baby should be seen by your health care provider.</p></div>]]></content>
                     <tags>doctor,maternity,obstetrics,pregnancy</tags>
                  </page>
                  <page user="jhaj">
                     <title>Nutritional services</title>
                     <label>Nutritional services</label>
                     <content><![CDATA[<div><p dir="ltr"><img src="http://connections6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/food.JPG" style="margin: 10px; float: right; width: 288px; height: 189px;" />Do you have questions about food and nutrition? Are you trying to make changes in how you eat?</p><p dir="ltr">Our family health team registered dietitians can answer your questions and help you make changes in what and how you and your family eat. We will work with you and your health care team to help you meet your health goals through improved nutrition.<br /><br /><strong>What services does the registered dietitian provide?</strong></p><ul dir="ltr">	<li>Nutrition assessments</li>	<li>Meetings to review your eating patterns</li>	<li>Counselling to help you make changes to your eating habits</li>	<li>Recommending group classes</li></ul><p dir="ltr"><strong>How do I make an appointment with the registered dietitian?</strong></p><ul dir="ltr">	<li>Referrals can be made through your primary health care provider or through a member of the health-care team.</li></ul></div>]]></content>
                     <tags>family,food,health,nutrition</tags>
                  </page>
                  <page user="abauer">
                     <title>Watson Heathcare Question and Answer</title>
                     <label>Watson Heathcare Question and Answer</label>
                     <content><![CDATA[<div><p dir="ltr"><iframe height="1750" src="http://watson-qa-demo.mybluemix.net" width="100%" /></p></div>]]></content>
                  </page>
               </pages>
            </wiki>
         </wikis>
         <subcommunities nav="false"/>
      </community>
   </communities>
</icda>
