<icda>
   <communities>
      <community user="ablanks">
         <title>Home Community</title>
         <content><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">Find information here about Home Insurance.&nbsp; Ask Insurance Questions and get answers from real insurance industry professionals and your community.</p>]]></content>
         <type>public</type>
         <isExternal>false</isExternal>
         <logo>bb7e4f5c-09a6-4b72-a632-8e66f73a2404.png</logo>
         <tags>home,homeowners,insurance,property</tags>
         <members>
            <member role="owner" user="rgestner"/>
            <member role="owner" user="dmishkey"/>
            <member role="owner" user="ablanks"/>
            <member role="member" user="nolmos"/>
            <member role="member" user="siduma"/>
            <member role="member" user="fadams"/>
            <member role="member" user="eelamon"/>
            <member role="member" user="bjordan"/>
         </members>
         <forums>
            <forum user="ablanks">
               <title>Home Community</title>
               <content/>
               <topics>
                  <topic user="nolmos">
                     <title>How are home insurance premiums set?</title>
                     <content><![CDATA[
    <p dir="ltr">
      What are the factors that affect my home insurance premiums?<br />
       &nbsp;
    </p>
  ]]></content>
                     <question>true</question>
                     <answered>true</answered>
                     <likes>
                        <like user="ablanks"/>
                        <like user="nolmos"/>
                        <like user="siduma"/>
                     </likes>
                     <replies>
                        <reply user="ablanks">
                           <title>Re: How are home insurance premiums set?</title>
                           <content><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">
      The cost of your insurance policy depends not only on the coverage you select, but also on a number of other factors. &nbsp;<br />
       &nbsp;<br />
       <span style="font-size:14px;"><strong>Cost Factors You Can't Control</strong></span>
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Some factors, such as the location of your home, its age, the materials with which it is made, and your age, are largely or entirely beyond your control. &nbsp;
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <strong><em>Where You Live</em> &nbsp;</strong>
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Insurance companies divide the areas in which they write policies into territories (usually using county and city boundaries as territory lines). Companies use these territorial boundaries as one way to determine their premiums. As you can see from our cost comparison tables, we found that prices varied substantially from territory to territory for the areas we looked at. &nbsp;
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Differences in average rates among territories are influenced by the losses companies experience in each territory. Loss experience, in turn, is influenced by such factors as the quality of police and fire departments, the incidence of crime, and the general level of maintenance of the housing stock. &nbsp;
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Within territories, companies set rates according to fire protection classifications. The fire protection classification for your home's location depends on how close you are to a fire station and how close to a fire hydrant, and on the quality of the fire department and the water supply for firefighting. Rates are usually much better for homes in "protected" areas, which are areas within five miles of a fire station and within 500 or 1,000 feet of a fire hydrant. Costs for homeowners insurance in unprotected areas are typically 40 to 60 percent higher than costs in protected areas. &nbsp;
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Another way in which location affects premiums is the impact of construction costs, but there's not much variation in construction costs within different parts of the Washington area. &nbsp;
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <em><strong>Building Materials &nbsp;</strong></em>
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      The material with which your house is constructed will also have an effect on your premium. Companies will rate your house as frame, masonry, or "superior" construction. The lowest premiums go to houses in the "superior" construction category. This category is for houses in which all floors, the roof, and all exterior walls are constructed from noncombustible materials like concrete, metal, or gypsum. The masonry construction category includes houses with exterior walls made of a noncombustible material like brick, stone, or adobe but that have floors or roofs made of combustible materials. The most expensive rating is for houses of wood frame construction, including houses with wood, vinyl, or aluminum siding. &nbsp;
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      If your house is a combination of frame and masonry, it will generally be rated as frame if the exterior walls are over 20 percent frame. The same is true of homes with brick veneer exterior walls. Some companies, however, will allow a house that is as much as 33 percent frame to be classified as masonry. &nbsp;
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      "Superior" construction will save you about 15 percent on your overall premium compared to masonry. At a location with good fire protection, frame construction will cost you on average 10 percent more than masonry construction. At a location with poor fire protection, construction materials matter more because the risk that a frame house will totally burn is greater. In such a location, you can expect your total premium to be about 20 percent higher for a frame house than for a masonry house. &nbsp;
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      While frame construction is a disadvantage in the event of fire, it is an advantage in an earthquake. If you decide to purchase earthquake coverage, your overall homeowners premium is likely to be higher for a masonry house than for a frame house. &nbsp;
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <em><strong>How Old or Historic Your House Is &nbsp;</strong></em>
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      If your house is less than 10 years old, most companies will give you a premium discount, and some companies give you a discount if your home is less than 25 years old. This discount can be as high as 50 percent for a brand-new house but will be only about half as much for a five-year-old house and is likely to be five percent or less for older homes. &nbsp;
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      If your house was built before 1900, you may not be able to qualify for an HO-3 policy. Instead, you may be offered an HO-8 policy, which will not cover damage caused by accidents such as bursting pipes or electrical shortages, more likely to occur in an older home. &nbsp;
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      If your home is located in an historic district, you can expect to pay much higher premiums, since historic districts usually require that if your home's exterior is damaged, you will have to have it repaired so that it replicates its original features and appearance. Also, if you own a home in an historic district, you'll likely be limited in your choice of insurers, since many insurers won't write policies in these neighborhoods. Some insurers-such as, Chubb and Fireman's Fund-specialize in insuring old or historic homes. &nbsp;
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <em><strong>Features of Your Home &nbsp;</strong></em>
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Insurers will likely charge you a higher premium if your home has features that include- &nbsp;<br />
       • One or more fireplaces or wood-burning stoves; &nbsp;<br />
       • A pool, tennis court, trampoline, or outdoor hot tub; &nbsp;<br />
       • A basement that is fully or partially finished; &nbsp;<br />
       • An electrical system that has not been updated with a circuit breaker; &nbsp;<br />
       • A roof made with wood shingles; &nbsp;<br />
       • A roof that is over 20 years old; or &nbsp;<br />
       • A furnace that is more than 20 years old. &nbsp;
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <strong><em>If You Have a Dog &nbsp;</em></strong>
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Although your homeowners insurance won't insure your home for damage to your property caused by animals, the liability portion of your policy may cover claims by others if your dog bites someone. For this reason, most insurers charge higher premiums to those who own a Rottweiler, Pit Bull, or another breed of dog that has a propensity to attack strangers, and most insurers will charge higher premiums to those who own a dog that has ever bitten a stranger. Some insurers have begun specifically to exclude from their liability coverage damages caused by dog bites. (If your dog has ever bitten a stranger, you may also have trouble shopping around for insurance, since many companies refuse to write new policies for homeowners whose dogs have a history of biting.) &nbsp;
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <em><strong>Your Age &nbsp;</strong></em>
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Some companies give discounts to seniors. Some set the age cutoff at 55, others at 50. Most cut the premium for qualifying homeowners by five to 10 percent. &nbsp;<br />
       &nbsp;<br />
       <span style="font-size:14px;"><strong>Cost Factors You Can Control</strong></span>
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Although there's much you can't control with regard to how your homeowners premium is determined, you do have control over many choices and factors. Most important is how much insurance you choose to purchase-whether to get replacement cost coverage on personal property or to raise coverage beyond the standard limits, for instance. We've discussed these options above. But you also have control over several other factors that determine how your insurance premium is set. &nbsp;
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      You'll need to ask insurance agents you're working with what discounts are offered, then decide whether any cost or inconvenience of qualifying is justified by premium savings. Discounts might not be mentioned if you don't ask. &nbsp;
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <em><strong>Claims History</strong></em> &nbsp;
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Making too many claims can drastically increase your premiums, so you'll want to try to limit the number of claims you make. The most costly effect of making too many claims is that your insurer may refuse to renew your policy. This has become an increasingly common problem for many consumers, as many insurers have begun to refuse to renew policies that have had as few as two claims during a two-year period, or even a five-year period. If your insurer decides not to renew your homeowners policy, you'll likely pay a steep price as a result. You may have trouble finding another reasonably priced insurer that will agree to write you a new policy, and even if you find another insurer, you'll be considered a high-risk customer and will have to pay high premiums. As a worst-case scenario, if you can't find an insurer to cover you, you'll be forced to get coverage with your state's FAIR plan, which can be expected to charge premiums that are higher than even the most expensive private insurers. &nbsp;
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Even if your claims history doesn't cause your insurer to drop your policy, making claims will probably have an effect on the premium you pay. Some insurers offer steep discounts for customers who have not made any claims on a policy during a two-to-five-year period. Other insurers simply increase rates for policyholders who make claims. &nbsp;
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <em><strong>Your Deductible &nbsp;</strong></em>
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      All homeowners insurance policies come with deductibles that apply to claims for damage to your property. Your loss must exceed the deductible amount before the insurance company's coverage takes over. Most companies apply a standard deductible of either $500 or $1,000. All companies, however, will allow you to raise your deductible above the basic level. &nbsp;
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      By taking as high a deductible as you can, you will cut your premiums substantially. This figure shows the typical savings. Moving from a $500 deductible to a $1,000 deductible will lower your insurance premium by an average of about 12 percent. A deductible of $2,000 will save you on average about 21 percent compared to a $500 deductible. &nbsp;
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      By taking a high deductible, you'll also reduce the likelihood of filing small claims that may result in future premium hikes. &nbsp;
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Keep in mind that the purpose of insurance is to protect you from losses that you can't afford to cover yourself. If you buy insurance for small losses, you pay insurance company overhead-sales, administrative, and claims handling costs-to deal with losses you could take care of out of your own pocket. On average, only 60 cents of every dollar policyholders spend on homeowners insurance is returned in claims payments. The rest goes to company overhead-a waste of money from your standpoint. You need to ask yourself how big a loss you can incur without an unacceptable level of disruption to your life and then set your insurance deductible levels accordingly. &nbsp;
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <em><strong>Protective Devices &nbsp;</strong></em>
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      You can get substantial discounts for installing devices to protect your home from burglary and fire. Deadbolt locks, in-home-sounding fire and burglar alarms, fire extinguishers, or a combination of these devices will generally save you one to three percent. Bigger discounts-typically an additional five to 10 percent-are available for homes that have alarms that report to a central-station monitoring service. For more information on home-security systems,&nbsp; including ratings of alarm installers, see our article Securing Your Home. The biggest discounts usually go to homes with full sprinkler systems. &nbsp;
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <em><strong>Dual-Policy Discounts &nbsp;</strong></em>
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Another type of discount is for dual policyholders. If you purchase auto and homeowners insurance from the same company, some companies will give you a discount off your homeowners premium, others will cut your auto premium, and some will cut both. Click here to go to see our ratings of auto insurance companies for price and quality. &nbsp;
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <em><strong>Credit History &nbsp;</strong></em>
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      In the District and Virginia, most insurers use credit scores to help determine premiums. (Maryland law now prohibits homeowners insurance writers from using credit information in setting rates.) In the District and Virginia, if you have a low credit score, have ever declared bankruptcy, or have been through foreclosure, some insurance companies may offer you only a higher priced policy intended for high-risk policyholders. The logic is that if you handle your finances carefully, you are more likely to be careful with the investment in your home. Many consumer groups and others oppose the use of credit scores in this way, arguing that the scores are not a direct measure of insurance risk and that using the scores in insurance pricing hurts low-income consumers, whose scores tend to be lower on average. &nbsp;
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      &nbsp;
    </p>]]></content>
                           <answer>true</answer>
                           <reply user="nolmos">
                              <title>Re: How are home insurance premiums set?</title>
                              <content><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">
      Thanks for the detailed answer
    </p>]]></content>
                           </reply>
                        </reply>
                     </replies>
                  </topic>
                  <topic user="bjordan">
                     <title>What should I do after my home is damaged?</title>
                     <content><![CDATA[
    <p dir="ltr">
      My home was damaged in the storm last week.&nbsp; What should I do?
    </p>
  ]]></content>
                     <question>true</question>
                     <likes>
                        <like user="ablanks"/>
                        <like user="eelamon"/>
                     </likes>
                     <replies>
                        <reply user="ablanks">
                           <title>Re: What should I do after my home is damaged?</title>
                           <content><![CDATA[<p class="gray_header" dir="ltr">
      What You Should Do After Damage to Your Home&nbsp;
    </p>
    <p class="gray_text" dir="ltr">
      <strong><i>How to Report a Claim&nbsp;</i></strong>
    </p>
    <p class="gray_text" dir="ltr">
      Your insurance agent is the first link between you and your company. If your agent is unavailable or if your insurance company does not have representatives on the scene available to help you, call the company directly and ask for the claims department. The company's phone number should be listed in your policy.&nbsp;
    </p>
    <p class="gray_text" dir="ltr">
      It is important that you fully understand your rights and responsibilities. If your insurance policy has been lost or destroyed in the disaster or if you are confused about the policy benefits or exclusions, your agent or company will be able to tell you exactly what coverage you have purchased and give you a copy of the policy provisions.&nbsp;
    </p>
    <p class="gray_text" dir="ltr">
      <strong><i>Make Sure Your Insurer Promptly Responds to Your Claim&nbsp;</i></strong>
    </p>
    <p class="gray_text" dir="ltr">
      After you report your loss, the insurance company will assign a company representative to check the damage to your property and determine how much will be paid for your loss. If it is necessary to vacate your home, be sure to report the address and phone number where you can be reached.&nbsp;
    </p>
    <p class="gray_text" dir="ltr">
      The District, Maryland, and Virginia have regulations that govern claims handling practices. For example, insurance companies are required to acknowledge the receipt of your claim within 10 working days. They are also required to provide you with the appropriate forms to file a claim. If your company has not responded to you within the required period of time or if you have experienced any other unreasonable delays in the handling of your claim, contact your insurance department for assistance (see the box above for contact information).&nbsp;
    </p>
    <p class="gray_text" dir="ltr">
      <strong><i>Information You Will Need to Provide&nbsp;</i></strong>
    </p>
    <p class="gray_text" dir="ltr">
      Your homeowners policy requires you to complete a claim report that lists all items destroyed, damaged, or missing. If you don't have or can't locate a complete household inventory, try to picture the contents of every room in your home and then list and describe all the items that were damaged or destroyed. As accurately as possible, try to remember when or where you bought each item, how much you paid for it, and how much it will cost to replace it. It is also helpful to include the brand name and model number if you know them.&nbsp;
    </p>
    <p class="gray_text" dir="ltr">
      <strong><i>Make Temporary Repairs to Prevent Further Damage&nbsp;</i></strong>
    </p>
    <p class="gray_text" dir="ltr">
      To protect your property from further damage, you should make all necessary temporary repairs, such as boarding up windows and patching holes in walls or roofs, as soon as possible, even if you have not yet seen the company representative. You can also move your personal property to a protected area and begin cleaning and drying items damaged by water. However, you should not dispose of any items that you believe may be a complete loss until the company representative has examined them.&nbsp;
    </p>
    <p class="gray_text" dir="ltr">
      Take photographs to show the way things look before you begin cleaning and repairing and be sure to keep receipts for all of your clean-up expenses.&nbsp;
    </p>
    <p class="gray_text" dir="ltr">
      Most homeowners policies cover reasonable costs of emergency clean-up and temporary repairs. You should ask your company representative whether the company will compensate you for work you do yourself. Be sure to keep receipts.&nbsp;
    </p>
    <p class="gray_text" dir="ltr">
      <strong><i>When Dealing with Contractors, Try to Withhold as Much Payment as Possible Until Work Is Completed&nbsp;</i></strong>
    </p>
    <p class="gray_text" dir="ltr">
      If the repair work is extensive, the contractor may ask for periodic partial payments as the work progresses, but no reputable contractor should request full payment in advance. The contract should specify that payments will be made as the work is completed. If you have a mortgage on your home, the lending institution may also have specific requirements as to how the insurance funds are disbursed.&nbsp;
    </p>
    <p class="gray_text" dir="ltr" style="font-style: italic">
      What to Do If the Cost of Repairs Is Higher than What the Insurer Will Pay&nbsp;
    </p>
    <p class="gray_text" dir="ltr">
      If there is a discrepancy between what your insurance company offers you and the actual cost of repairs, or if the contractor finds hidden damage after the insurance company has set a cost figure, you should first contact the company representative and try to resolve the difference. If you are still unable to resolve your differences, contact your state's insurance department.&nbsp;
    </p>
    <p class="gray_text" dir="ltr">
      <strong><i>Where to Live During Repairs&nbsp;</i></strong>
    </p>
    <p class="gray_text" dir="ltr">
      Standard homeowners policies include coverage for costs you incur that are in excess of your normal living expenses. For example, if you normally spend $3,000 per month for mortgage/rent, utilities, food, and transportation, and these living expenses increase to $4,000 per month because of the disaster, the insurance company will reimburse you $1,000. Be sure to save receipts.&nbsp;
    </p>
    <p class="gray_text" dir="ltr">
      You should also ask your company representative if there are any restrictions on where and how long you can stay and how much you are allowed for hotel rooms. If you stay with a relative or friend, the company may reimburse your host for lodging only if you can show proof of actual payment. Extra expenses, such as higher utility bills incurred by the host, would definitely be considered.&nbsp;
    </p>]]></content>
                        </reply>
                     </replies>
                  </topic>
                  <topic user="siduma">
                     <title>How do I find a company that provides good claims handleing services?</title>
                     <content><![CDATA[
    <p dir="ltr">
      What should I be looking for in a company to see if they have a good claims handling service?&nbsp;&nbsp; My last company was a nightmare to work with.
    </p>
  ]]></content>
                     <question>true</question>
                     <answered>true</answered>
                     <likes>
                        <like user="siduma"/>
                        <like user="ablanks"/>
                     </likes>
                     <replies>
                        <reply user="dmishkey">
                           <title>Re: How do I find a company that provides good claims handleing services?</title>
                           <content><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">
      <br />
       <strong>One way to spot serious problems is to look at records of complaints filed with states' departments of insurance. &nbsp;</strong>
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      On this table, we have reported counts of homeowners insurance complaints for the District, Maryland, and Virginia using the most recent time periods for which data were available. The companies listed on the table are those that wrote the most policies in each state during the time period shown. For each company, the table also reports "complaint rates," which are intended to take into account the fact that some companies do much more business than others and therefore are more exposed to incurring complaints. The complaint rates are calculated as the companies' numbers of complaints per $10 million in direct homeowners premiums written. &nbsp;
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Comparing the complaint rate information with the pricing information, you will see that in all parts of the Washington area homeowners have companies available to them that have relatively low premiums and also relatively low complaint rates. For example, Brethren Mutual quoted consistently low rates for all the Northern Virginia profiles shown on our cost comparison tables, and didn't have any complaints filed against it in Virginia for the three-year period we looked at. Similarly, Erie's premium for the sample frame house in Fairfax County was $595, compared to the $821 rate of MetLife; yet Erie's Virginia complaint rate was lower than MetLife's. And Travelers' rates for the sample profiles shown on our cost comparison tables were usually among the lowest of all the companies, yet Travelers' complaint rate was better than many of its higher cost competitors. In short, you can save money and also get good service. &nbsp;
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <strong>Feedback from Policyholders and Contractors &nbsp;</strong>
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Another way to measure the quality of service from homeowners insurance companies is to look at results of surveys of customers who have made claims. We have collected some feedback from surveying CHECKBOOK subscribers. This table shows the percentage of respondents who said they would recommend each of 13 companies. Consumer Reports has published ratings of homeowners insurance companies based on a survey of its subscribers and, in general, the companies that scored high on our survey-USAA, Amica Mutual, Chubb, and State Farm-got relatively high ratings on the Consumer Reports survey while those that got relatively low ratings on our survey-Travelers, Farmers, and Allstate-got relatively low scores on the Consumer Reports survey. &nbsp;
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Another way to get insight on company service is to collect feedback from contractors who work with homeowners making repairs for which the homeowners are making claims. After all, contractors who do such repair work get a chance to hear enough claims-handling nightmare stories from customers to form fairly informed opinions. We surveyed roofers and asked them to rate insurance companies with which they had experience "poor," "fair," "good," "very good," or "excellent" for "treating their customers fairly when paying claims." Some roofers told us they were unable to provide judgments, since they didn't do much repair work and therefore had little or no experience working with customers who needed work done under insurance claims. But many roofers did have opinions based on their experiences. This table shows the percentage of roofers who rated various companies at least "very good." Not surprisingly, there is some correlation between companies' scores with roofers and their scores with surveyed homeowners. &nbsp;
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <strong>Other Considerations &nbsp;</strong>
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Another concern in choosing a company is the risk of having your coverage arbitrarily terminated-perhaps because you've made a few claims. Unfortunately, we have no data to compare companies on their termination practices. &nbsp;
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Although there do appear to be service differences among companies, it seems you can safely focus your shopping on price differences. Even the companies with the highest complaint rates, for example, were the subjects of complaints in a year from only a small percentage of their policyholders. &nbsp;
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      &nbsp;
    </p>]]></content>
                           <answer>true</answer>
                        </reply>
                     </replies>
                  </topic>
               </topics>
            </forum>
         </forums>
         <bookmarks/>
         <files/>
         <blogs>
            <communityblog user="ablanks">
               <title>Tips on finding a good agent</title>
               <handle>bb7e4f5c-09a6-4b72-a632-8e66f73a2404</handle>
               <summary/>
               <posts>
                  <post user="ablanks">
                     <title>Do You Trust Your Insurance Company?</title>
                     <content><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr"><span class="home-page" id="main-content">Insurance might not be the oldest profession. But, the idea does go back to ancient times. Some say that the concept of sharing risk began 5000 years ago when Chinese merchants started mixing their cargoes together to distribute each merchant&rsquo;s goods across multiple ships. Of course, the downside was, if a ship went down, it took a portion of each merchant&rsquo;s goods with it. The upside? Every merchant was &ldquo;insured&rdquo; against being wiped out completely. This &ldquo;colleague insurance&rdquo;, invented in 3000 BC, developed because merchants trusted each other to keep everyone&rsquo;s best interests at heart. <a href="http://connections6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/Ancient-Chinese-ship-red-sails-300x118.gif" target="_blank"><img alt="image" src="http://connections6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/Ancient-Chinese-ship-red-sails-300x118.gif" style="  display:block; margin: 1em 0pt 0pt 1em; float: right;"></img></a><br>

As in ancient times, trust and insurance should be inextricably intertwined. So, why don&rsquo;t most consumers today feel that way? At IBM, our most recent survey shows that only 43% of customers trust the insurance industry. In fact, lack of consumer trust in insurance providers has remained above 50% since 2007 (when we first started taking surveys).<br>

The problem with this is &mdash; it is impossible to develop meaningful customer engagement without trust. Today&rsquo;s consumers expect insurers to engage them in their context via personalization, responsiveness and seamless experiences across all touch points. In order for insurance providers to do this, they need data &mdash; lots of revealing, personal data about consumers&rsquo; situations, wants, needs, and behaviors. In the future, providers may find it harder to obtain the data they need for engagement without trust.<br>

Without meaningful customer engagement, forget about customer retention! Our data shows that dissatisfied insurance customers are six times more likely to switch insurers. In fact, 41% of policyholders say they have switched their insurer when their needs changed and their provider couldn&rsquo;t keep up. This is bad news for insurers who have to spend more time and money acquiring new customers only to lose them when they can&rsquo;t meet their new customers&rsquo; engagement needs.</span></p>



<p dir="ltr"><span class="home-page" id="main-content">So, what steps can insurers take to ensure they gain the trust of their customers, obtain access to personal data and develop meaningful customer engagement? Insurance providers need to:</span></p>



<ul dir="ltr">

	<li><span class="home-page" id="main-content">Leverage <a href="http://www.ibm.com/commerce/us-en/customeranalytics?lnk=WH_customeranalytics">customer analytics</a> to build evolving 360&deg; views of policyholders to proactively anticipate needs policyholders didn&rsquo;t even know they had</span></li>

	<li><span class="home-page" id="main-content">Engage policyholders at the right times/places with the use of a customer <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=b1ePsNWy4oE">journey designer</a></span></li>

	<li><span class="home-page" id="main-content">Capitalize on <a href="http://www.ibm.com/commerce/us-en/">customer engagement</a> to deliver more intimate policyholder interactions that improve with time</span></li>

</ul>



<p dir="ltr"><span class="home-page" id="main-content">Remember the ancient Chinese merchant mariners who used their social network to syndicate their risk? What can modern insurance companies learn from their example? The answer brings us back to trust. As consumers continue to become more empowered about the data collected about them, they may allow access only in return for valuable engagement.</span></p>



<p dir="ltr"><span class="home-page" id="main-content">So, how can an insurer establish trust with its policyholders? Let&rsquo;s look at a modern day example &ndash; Friendsurance.</span></p>



<p dir="ltr"><span class="home-page" id="main-content">Friendsurance leverages social networks to sell &ldquo;deductible&rdquo; insurance. When a Friendsurance policyholder makes a claim small enough to have been paid out of his deductible, the payment is made instead by his group of friends who have signed up for Friendsurance&rsquo;s deductible insurance together. (&ldquo;Friend&rdquo; groups can also form ad hoc on Friendsurance&rsquo;s web site.) If a group&rsquo;s small claims don&rsquo;t exhaust the premiums paid in a given year, each friend gets back his share of the remaining funds!</span></p>



<p dir="ltr"><span class="home-page" id="main-content">The results? Friendsurance&rsquo;s model can produce enhanced policyholder profitability due to:</span></p>



<ul dir="ltr">

	<li><span class="home-page" id="main-content">Reduced claim costs &mdash; friends hesitate to ask their friends to pay for unimportant damages</span></li>

	<li><span class="home-page" id="main-content">Decreased marketing costs &mdash; friends recruit their own social networks to join their Friendsurance groups</span></li>

	<li><span class="home-page" id="main-content">Lessened fraud risk &mdash; friends are less likely to scam each other</span></li>

	<li><span class="home-page" id="main-content">Improved retention rates and increased loyalty &mdash; friends don&rsquo;t want to leave their friends in the lurch by leaving the group</span></li>

	<li><span class="home-page" id="main-content">Higher policyholder satisfaction due to cash rebates as a reward for low claims</span></li>

</ul>



<p dir="ltr"><span class="home-page" id="main-content">As Friendsurance demonstrates, insurance provider profitability can be enhanced by delivering rewarding customer engagement built on trust.<br>

So, if your insurer is looking to improve customer engagement and retention, just ask yourself &mdash; How is your insurer building trust?</span></p>]]></content>
                     <tags>property,trust,insurance</tags>
                     <likes>
                        <like user="ablanks"/>
                        <like user="eelamon"/>
                        <like user="siduma"/>
                     </likes>
                  </post>
                  <post user="dmishkey">
                     <title>5 Best Home Renovations for Under $5,000</title>
                     <content><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">Regardless if you own or rent, your home is at the center of your universe. It&rsquo;s where you eat, sleep, socialize and store all the things that matter most.<a href="http://connections6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/moneybpigv2.jpg" target="_blank"><img alt="image" height="208" src="http://connections6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/moneybpigv2.jpg" style="display: block; margin: 1em 0pt 0pt 1em; float: right;" width="311"></img></a></p>



<p dir="ltr">So why does it look like such a mess? I&rsquo;m guessing two reasons: time and money, or the lack thereof. In other words, your busy life keeps you from taking the time to be organized and implementing the latest interior design trends, and the plethora of other demands on your wallet prevent you from hiring someone to do the job for you.</p>



<p dir="ltr">Fret not, because we&rsquo;ve compiled a list of five efficient ways to spruce up your home without breaking the bank.</p>



<p dir="ltr"><span style="font-size:14px;"><strong>1. Paint it out</strong></span></p>



<p dir="ltr">It&rsquo;s easy to take the small things for granted. Applying a fresh coat of paint is one of the simplest and cheapest ways to take an old room from drab to fab&hellip; provided that your new coat&rsquo;s color is indeed fab. If you&rsquo;re not blessed with an eye for color coordination, snap some pictures of the rooms you want to repaint, take them to a local home improvement store and ask for some help. There&rsquo;s no shame in admitting you don&rsquo;t want your dining room to have the color palette of a Warhol painting and need assistance to avoid that fate.</p>



<p dir="ltr"><strong><span style="font-size:14px;">2. Get some light</span></strong></p>



<p dir="ltr">Dimness is great for romantic dinners&hellip; but not so much for cooking, doing laundry, taking showers and all the other things you do at home most days. Practical matters aside, low light also makes everything look kind of dingy. So brighten up your life! It&rsquo;ll change everything, and with a $5,000 budget, a half-day&rsquo;s worth of time and a trip to an affordable retailer, you&rsquo;ll be able to outfit your entire home, no sweat.</p>



<p dir="ltr">Important: Remember to treat lights like furniture. They should be functional and fashionable. The monstrosities you had in your college dorm won&rsquo;t work anymore.</p>



<p dir="ltr"><span style="font-size:14px;"><strong>3. Caulk and tile</strong></span></p>



<p dir="ltr">Bathroom renovation can seem awfully unappealing, especially if you only have one. The prospect of navigating around a demolition zone every time you want to brush your teeth or take a shower isn&rsquo;t something anyone wants to think about, but with a little planning, your worst washroom fears can be easily avoided.</p>



<p dir="ltr">Start by re-caulking around sinks, showers, toilets and tubs to get rid of unsightly grime. Then pick out some affordable new tiles for the floor, and you&rsquo;ll be in business. Sure, new sinks and toilets are great &mdash; and probably within range for a $5,000 budget (provided you didn&rsquo;t go with marble flooring) &mdash; but caulk and tile is probably all you&rsquo;ll need to make an impact. Unless you&rsquo;ve got plenty of experience, though, hire a professional to do the job. It may be relatively cheap, but it sure ain&rsquo;t easy.</p>



<p dir="ltr"><span style="font-size:14px;"><strong>4. Clean up your act</strong></span></p>



<p dir="ltr">Simple and free. The perfect combo. Yes, all you&rsquo;ll need to do to clean up your house is&hellip;clean up your house. Set aside a weekend and collect all the useless items cluttering up your abode. (You probably don&rsquo;t need any electronic device made before 2000, and that cargo-pocket phase you went through? Mistake.) Throw out the junk, sell anything that might yield more than $5 at a yard sale or on Craigslist, and revel in the newfound order you&rsquo;ve created.</p>



<p dir="ltr"><span style="font-size:14px;"><strong>5. Knobs, pulls, and counters</strong></span></p>



<p dir="ltr">Kitchen renovations and panic attacks usually go hand in hand, but it doesn&rsquo;t have to be that way. The most expensive part of doing your kitchen over is replacing astronomically priced appliances &mdash; a superfluous expense as long as they&rsquo;re clean and functional. New cabinet knobs, drawer pulls and counter tops can all be installed on a very reasonable budget, and will rejuvenate even the stalest of kitchens, panic-free.</p>



<p dir="ltr">What DIY projects are you ready to tackle?</p>]]></content>
                     <likes>
                        <like user="dmishkey"/>
                     </likes>
                  </post>
                  <post user="ablanks">
                     <title>Tips on finding a good agent</title>
                     <content><![CDATA[<p class="gray_sub_header" dir="ltr"><strong>Finding a Good Agent&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p class="gray_text" dir="ltr">Since most insurance companies sell policies only through insurance agents, your first step toward getting good service is to find an insurance agent you can trust. You&rsquo;ll want a responsive, knowledgeable agent who can provide sound advice and accurate price quotes. Unfortunately, when contacting area agents to obtain insurance premium quotes, we found, just as we have when we have done such shopping in the past, that many agents weren&rsquo;t up to the challenge of calculating accurate prices, and some offered alarmingly bad information and advice. The following were the most common problems we encountered&mdash;&nbsp;</p>



<ul class="gray_text" dir="ltr">

	<li>Agents rarely agreed on the amount of coverage that was needed to insure our sample homes. In some cases, the amount of dwelling coverage we were advised to purchase on a sample home varied by more than $100,000 from agent to agent for the same company. Often the agents were advising us to take on much more coverage&mdash;at more cost to us&mdash;than was needed.&nbsp;<a href="http://connections6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/homeagentv2.jpg" target="_blank"><img alt="image" height="234" src="http://connections6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/homeagentv2.jpg" style="display: block; margin: 1em 0pt 0pt 1em; float: right;" width="232"></img></a></li>

	<li>For the same home and coverage, we repeatedly encountered insurance agents who quoted completely different premiums than other agents for a policy written by the same insurance company. In some cases, agents quoted prices that were more than double the correct premium.&nbsp;</li>

	<li>Some agents didn&rsquo;t bother asking our shoppers enough questions about our sample home and homeowner to enable them to quote accurate prices. For example, a few agents never bothered to ask whether the home was of frame or masonry construction, and many agents never bothered to ask about features of the home that would have affected premiums, such as the presence of burglar alarms.&nbsp;</li>

	<li>Some agents didn&rsquo;t properly include discounts for which our shoppers would be eligible, based on information the shopper provided.&nbsp;</li>

	<li>Many agents tried to sell us unwanted options and add-ons, such as sewer backup coverage and coverage for identity fraud. Often, these options were simply tacked on to the agents&rsquo; price quotes without any discussion or any mention of the fact that these coverages weren&rsquo;t required and would increase the premiums.&nbsp;</li>

	<li>When we questioned the addition of unwanted options, some agents tried to justify their selling practices by falsely telling us that the extra coverages were required by the insurance company or mandated by state law.&nbsp;</li>

	<li>Many agents tried to sell us more insurance than requested by quoting prices based on optional, higher coverage limits. When we asked them to re-quote prices using the originally requested, lower coverage amounts, some agents falsely told us that they would be unable to do so since such limits were the minimum coverages offered by the company. For example, a common practice was to include $500,000 in liability coverage; when we contacted these agents and asked them to adjust their quotes to include our specified $300,000 for liability coverage, some told our shoppers that it would be impossible to do so because all of the company&rsquo;s HO-3 policies come with $500,000 in liability coverage&mdash;even for companies that have standard minimum limits of $100,000 for liability coverage.&nbsp;</li>

</ul>



<p class="gray_text" dir="ltr">Encountering purveyors of bad advice is not a new phenomenon for us when collecting information from local service companies. But our experiences in dealing with insurance agents are particularly disturbing because the &ldquo;up-selling&rdquo; and downright dishonesty we encountered were so commonplace, and because the problem has persisted over the many years we have done similar shopping.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="gray_text" dir="ltr">To make sure you&rsquo;re being given accurate information and prices, our advice is to shop several agents. When obtaining quotes for premiums, push hard to get reliable information. A good first step is to decide for yourself the exact types of coverage and amounts you want to buy, then make sure that any agent you deal with bases your premiums on those specifications. Look over price quotes and policies you receive very carefully. If an agent includes coverage that you did not request or that you believe is unnecessary, ask him or her to explain why it was included. If the answer is unsatisfying, take your business elsewhere.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="gray_text" dir="ltr">Since agents frequently fail to mention the most attractive available policy terms and sometimes quote inaccurate rates for the policies that are offered, always ask whether there are other policies and terms that will result in better rates.&nbsp;</p>]]></content>
                     <tags>insurance,trust,home,agent,finding</tags>
                     <likes>
                        <like user="ablanks"/>
                        <like user="eelamon"/>
                     </likes>
                  </post>
               </posts>
            </communityblog>
         </blogs>
         <wikis>
            <wiki user="ablanks">
               <title>Home Community</title>
               <summary><![CDATA[Find information here about Home Insurance.  Ask Insurance Questions and get answers from real insurance industry professionals and your community.]]></summary>
               <label>W8f708826a69e_4f97_bac1_645e8ac8145d</label>
               <visibility>PUBLIC_TO_VIEWERS</visibility>
               <pages>
                  <page user="ablanks">
                     <title>Welcome to the Home Community</title>
                     <label>Welcome to the Home Community</label>
                     <content><![CDATA[<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!DOCTYPE html [<!ENTITY amp "&#38;#38;"><!ENTITY lt "&#60;#60;"><!ENTITY gt "&#62;#62;"><!ENTITY nbsp "&#160;"><!ENTITY apos "&#39;"><!ENTITY quot "&#34;">]><div><div dir="ltr"><p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size:26px;"><strong>This is the place to discuss all things about homes</strong></span></p><table align="center" border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" dir="ltr" height="993" style="font-family: helvetica neue,helvetica,arial,sans-serif;" width="888">	<tbody>		<tr>			<td align="left" style="margin: 0px; padding: 5px; width: 28%;" valign="top">			<table border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" height="394" style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px; border: 1px solid rgb(175, 175, 175); box-shadow: 2px 2px 1px 1px rgb(225, 225, 225);" width="417">				<tbody>					<tr>						<td height="25" style="padding: 10px 15px 0px; width: 357px; text-align: center; color: rgb(4, 80, 115) !important; font-size: 15px;">If you have questions we have the answers.</td>					</tr>					<tr>						<td style="padding: 10px 15px 0px; width: 357px; text-align: center;"><img height="220" src="http://connections6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/question3.jpg" width="235" /></td>					</tr>					<tr>						<td height="40" style="padding: 10px 15px 0px; width: 357px; text-align: center; color: rgb(4, 80, 115) !important; line-height: 30px; font-size: 28px; font-weight: 200;" valign="middle"><a href="http://connections6.ibmcollabcloud.com/communities/service/html/communityoverview?communityUuid=bb7e4f5c-09a6-4b72-a632-8e66f73a2404#fullpageWidgetId=W59392f110a27_4399_991a_bf87f4e91cd6">The&nbsp;Home&nbsp;Forums</a></td>					</tr>					<tr>						<td style="padding: 10px 15px; width: 357px; text-align: center; color: rgb(54, 58, 62) !important; line-height: 24px; font-size: 20px; font-weight: 100;">Please ask your question here</td>					</tr>				</tbody>			</table>			</td>			<td align="left" style="margin: 0px; padding: 5px; width: 28%; vertical-align: top;" valign="top">			<table border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px; border: 1px solid rgb(175, 175, 175); box-shadow: 2px 2px 1px 1px rgb(225,225,225);" width="100%">				<tbody>					<tr>						<td height="25" style="padding: 10px 15px 0px; text-align: center; color: rgb(4, 80, 115) !important; font-size: 15px;">Share your ideas on homes here</td>					</tr>					<tr>						<td style="padding: 10px 15px 0px; text-align: center; vertical-align: middle;"><img height="217" src="http://connections6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/insidehousev2.jpg" width="325" /></td>					</tr>					<tr>						<td height="40" style="padding: 10px 15px 0px; text-align: center; color: rgb(4, 80, 115) !important; line-height: 30px; font-size: 28px; font-weight: 200;" valign="middle"><a href="http://connections6.ibmcollabcloud.com/blogs/bb7e4f5c-09a6-4b72-a632-8e66f73a2404?lang=en_us">The&nbsp;Home&nbsp;Blogs</a></td>					</tr>					<tr>						<td style="padding: 10px 15px; text-align: center; color: rgb(54, 58, 62) !important; line-height: 24px; font-size: 20px; font-weight: 100;">Fun place to share stories about homes, insurance, and safety.</td>					</tr>				</tbody>			</table>			</td>		</tr>		<tr>			<td align="left" style="margin: 0px; padding: 5px; width: 28%; vertical-align: top;" valign="top">			<table border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" height="485" style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px; border: 1px solid rgb(175, 175, 175); box-shadow: 2px 2px 1px 1px rgb(225, 225, 225);" width="412">				<tbody>					<tr>						<td height="25" style="padding: 10px 15px 0px; color: rgb(4, 80, 115) !important; font-size: 15px;">						<p style="text-align: center;">Home insurance policy types</p>						</td>					</tr>					<tr>						<td style="padding: 10px 15px 0px;"><img height="242" src="http://connections6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/home1v2.jpg" width="364" /></td>					</tr>					<tr>						<td height="40" style="padding: 10px 15px 0px; text-align: center; color: rgb(4, 80, 115) !important; line-height: 30px; font-size: 28px; font-weight: 200;" valign="middle"><a  lconnwikiparamwikipage="Home insurance policy types" lconnwikimacro="wikilink" href="/wikis/home/wiki/W8f708826a69e_4f97_bac1_645e8ac8145d/page/Home%20insurance%20policy%20types">Click here to find out more</a></td>					</tr>					<tr>						<td style="padding: 10px 15px; text-align: center; color: rgb(54, 58, 62) !important; line-height: 24px; font-size: 20px; font-weight: 100;">Did you know that insurers offer four types of policies for single-family homes.</td>					</tr>				</tbody>			</table>			</td>			<td align="left" style="margin: 0px; padding: 5px; width: 28%; vertical-align: top;" valign="top">			<table border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" height="483" style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px; border: 1px solid rgb(175, 175, 175); box-shadow: 2px 2px 1px 1px rgb(225, 225, 225);" width="446">				<tbody>					<tr>						<td height="25" style="padding: 10px 15px 0px; color: rgb(4, 80, 115) !important; font-size: 15px;">						<p style="text-align: center;">Insurance for Renters and Condominium Owners</p>						</td>					</tr>					<tr>						<td style="padding: 10px 15px 0px; text-align: center;"><img height="232" src="http://connections6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/apartment.JPG" width="413" /></td>					</tr>					<tr>						<td height="40" style="padding: 10px 15px 0px; text-align: center; color: rgb(4, 80, 115) !important; line-height: 30px; font-size: 28px; font-weight: 200;" valign="middle"><a  lconnwikiparamwikipage="Insurance for Renters and Condominium Owners" lconnwikimacro="wikilink" href="/wikis/home/wiki/W8f708826a69e_4f97_bac1_645e8ac8145d/page/Insurance%20for%20Renters%20and%20Condominium%20Owners">Click here to find out more</a></td>					</tr>					<tr>						<td style="padding: 10px 15px; text-align: center; color: rgb(54, 58, 62) !important; line-height: 24px; font-size: 20px; font-weight: 100;">Did you know that if you are a renter or a condominium owner, you can purchase insurance similar to homeowners coverage.</td>					</tr>				</tbody>			</table>			</td>		</tr>		<tr>			<td align="left" colspan="2" style="margin: 0px; padding: 5px; width: 28%; vertical-align: top;" valign="top">			<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size:14px;"><strong>Humor for the day - Taken from real customer events.</strong></span></p>			<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>In Case Of Emergency, Use Brain</strong></p>			<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>I am working in the insurance field service. One of many things I have to deal with is containing damages on the telephone.</strong></p>			<p><strong>Agent:</strong> Thank you for calling Digital Insurance. How may I assist you?</p>			<p><strong>Customer:</strong> My house is burning!</p>			<p><strong>Agent</strong>: *confused* Your house is burning?</p>			<p><strong>Customer:</strong> My house is burning! What should I do?</p>			<p><strong>Agent:</strong> Have you called the fire department?</p>			<p><strong>Customer: </strong>No, I thought the insurance wanted to see the damage before.</p>			</td>		</tr>		<tr>			<td align="left" colspan="2" style="margin: 0px; padding: 5px; width: 28%; vertical-align: top;" valign="top">			<div dir="ltr">			<ul dir="ltr" style="margin: 0px auto; padding: 4em 0px; width: 700px; font-family: roboto, helvetica, Arial;">				<li style="padding:15px; width: 100%; overflow: hidden; vertical-align: top; display: inline-block; box-sizing: border-box; background-color: rgba(50, 92, 128, 0.8);">				<h2 style="margin: 0px; color: rgb(255, 255, 255) !important;"><span style="font-size: 1.7em; font-weight: 600;">The Digital Insurance Team</span></h2>				&nbsp;				<ul style="width: 100%; font-family: roboto, helvetica, Arial;">					<li style="width: 33%; display: inline-block;">					<h4 style="color: rgb(255, 255, 255) ! important;">Home Insurance</h4>					<div class="staffLeft" role="presentation" style="float: none !important;"><span class="staffComm"><a class="fn url" href="/profiles/html/profileView.do?key=69e8faa9-49ec-4b43-9106-9de27c198446" title=""><img alt="Amy Blanks" class="staffPeople32" height="85" src="/profiles/photo.do?key=69e8faa9-49ec-4b43-9106-9de27c198446" title="Amy Blanks" width="85" /></a></span></div>					</li>					<li style="width: 33%; display: inline-block;">					<h4 style="color: rgb(255, 255, 255) !important;">Auto Insurance</h4>					<div class="staffLeft" role="presentation" style="float: none !important;"><span class="staffComm"><a class="fn url" href="/profiles/html/profileView.do?key=93b73c63-43b0-46d1-a5f4-e2ed9a7245bd" title=""><img alt="Dan Mishkey" class="staffPeople32" height="85" src="/profiles/photo.do?key=93b73c63-43b0-46d1-a5f4-e2ed9a7245bd" title="Dan Mishkey" width="85" /></a></span></div>					</li>					<li style="width: 33%; display: inline-block;">					<h4 style="color: rgb(255, 255, 255) !important;">Life Insurance</h4>					<div class="staffLeft" role="presentation" style="float: none !important;"><span class="staffComm"><a class="fn url" href="/profiles/html/profileView.do?key=d89bb6d8-0699-41df-b050-9bce9d670588" title=""><img alt="Rebecca Gestner" class="staffPeople32" height="85" src="/profiles/photo.do?key=d89bb6d8-0699-41df-b050-9bce9d670588" title="Rebecca Gestner" width="85" /></a></span></div>					</li>				</ul>				<p style="margin: 0px; color: rgb(255, 255, 255); font-size: 1.2em;">&nbsp;</p>				</li>			</ul>			</div>			</td>		</tr>	</tbody></table></div></div>]]></content>
                  </page>
                  <page user="ablanks">
                     <title>Home insurance policy types</title>
                     <label>Home insurance policy types</label>
                     <content><![CDATA[<div><p class="gray_text" dir="ltr">Insurers offer four types of policies for single-family homes. They are generally referred to in the industry by the labels HO-2, HO-3, HO-5, and HO-8, though individual companies often market them under other names.Â </p><p class="gray_text" dir="ltr">The HO-3 policy, which is by far the biggest seller, covers your house against all types of risksincluding fire, windstorms, theft, vandalism, frozen pipes, accidental damage, etc. except risks that are specifically excluded. The risks that most companies exclude under this policy form are: floods; sewer backups; earthquakes; damage from termites, pets, or other animals; damage from mold, mildew, dry rot, and wet rot (unless the damage was the result of a covered peril, such as a water-pipe burst); war; and nuclear accidents and explosions. But some companies may exclude additional risks, so it is important to check. The HO-3 policy also covers your personal property, but only for named perils generally the same list of perils covered by the HO-2 policy, described below and covers the personal property for replacement cost after adjustment for depreciation, not the full replacement cost.;</p><p class="gray_text" dir="ltr">The HO-5 policy form gives the same coverage as the HO-3 form except that HO-5 policies include replacement cost coverage for personal property and insure personal property against all perils except specifically excluded perils. (We discuss personal property coverage later in this article.) If you're thinking about buying an HO-5 policy, make sure that you can't get an HO-3 policy with a special provision for full replacement cost coverage on personal property for a lower premium.;<img height="195" src="http://connections6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/home1v2.jpg" style="margin: 10px; float: right;" width="293" /></p><p class="gray_text" dir="ltr">The HO-2 policy form, which was developed and used for many years before the HO-3 and HO-5 forms were developed, covers only named risks. But the list of risks is long. As a practical matter, the main difference from the HO-3 and HO-5 forms is that an HO-2 policy won't cover damage from accidental loses for example, if you drop a ladder through your bay window or if you knock over a bucket of paint onto your new carpet. Since such accidental losses are likely to be small relative to the total value of your house, you might decide that you can accept the risk and just purchase an HO-2 policy. But most companies don't even offer HO-2 policies today, and most homeowners opt for the HO-3 form since its extra costs are low.Â </p><p class="gray_text" dir="ltr">If you own an older home, you might have to purchase an HO-8 policy. The main difference between an HO-8 policy and the HO-2, HO-3, and HO-5 policies is that an HO-8 policy typically will pay only for damages up to the actual cash value of what is lost, while the other policies allow you to insure for full replacement cost. HO-8 policies are intended to take into account the fact that older homes often have ornate woodwork and other features that are very expensive to replace; since replacing these features may cost more than the home is actually worth, HO-8 policies will promise to repair or replace what is damaged, but don't promise to pay for an exact replica of what was lost.Â </p><p class="gray_text" dir="ltr">Another difference between HO-8 policies and the other homeowners insurance forms is that HO-8 policies cover only named risks, which do not include certain risks for which older homes are vulnerable, such as sudden bursting of pipes.Â </p><p class="gray_text" dir="ltr">Insurance companies also offer coverage for renters and condominium owners. Renter coverage doesn't include full coverage for the dwelling itself, since insuring it is the responsibility of the landlord. Instead, renter coverage insures the tenant's personal property and provides liability insurance. Policies for condominium owners are similar.Â </p><p class="gray_text" dir="ltr">Both renters and condominium owners can get coverage for damage to portions of the dwelling for which they are responsible, including additions and improvements such as carpeting, cabinets, or interior walls that they have made to the premises.Â </p></div>]]></content>
                     <tags>coverage,home,insurance,policy</tags>
                  </page>
                  <page user="ablanks">
                     <title>Insurance for Renters and Condominium Owners</title>
                     <label>Insurance for Renters and Condominium Owners</label>
                     <content><![CDATA[<div><p class="gray_text" dir="ltr">If you are a renter or a condominium owner, you can purchase insurance similar to homeowners coverage. The renters policy, referred to as form and the condominium owners policy, referred to as form provide coverage for personal property, for additional living expenses, for personal liability (typically up to $100,000 or $300,000), and for medical payments to others (typically up to $1,000 or $2,000).Â </p><p class="gray_text" dir="ltr">As with homeowners insurance policies, rates for renters and condo owners vary significantly from company to company, so you'll want to shop around.Â <img height="193" src="http://connections6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/apartment.JPG" style="margin: 10px; float: left;" width="352" /></p><p class="gray_text" dir="ltr">Renter and condo policies usually cover personal property for its actual cash value. You can purchase an endorsement for replacement cost coverage. As with homeowners insurance, special limits of liability apply to certain categories of items. If you are unsure whether your valuables are covered, ask your agent for clarification. If they are not, you may choose to increase the special limits or you can purchase an individual floater for each item.Â </p><p class="gray_text" dir="ltr">The coverage for additional living expenses (expenses that result from loss of use of your dwelling) usually is for an amount up to 30 percent of the coverage of your personal property under a renters policy and for an amount up to 40 percent of the coverage of your personal property under a condominium owners policy.Â </p><p class="gray_text" dir="ltr">Renters and condominium owners policies are not intended to cover damage to your building's basic structure. The landlord or condominium association should have insurance to cover such losses. But condominium owners policies do provide some coverage for structural damage. The extent of this coverage varies significantly, and how much structural coverage you will need depends on how much coverage is provided by the condominium association's own policy. Some condominium associations have policies that include built-in fixtures like sinks, bathtubs, and electrical wiring. Others have policies that stop coverage at the unfinished walls, leaving you responsible for any fixtures or improvements inside. You should purchase a condominium owners policy that takes over where the condominium association policy's coverage ends. (It is also possible under some renters policies to purchase coverage for improvements you have made to an apartment.)Â </p><p class="gray_text" dir="ltr">If you negligently <i>cause</i> damage to your building, the landlord's or condominium association's insurance company may sue you to recover its expenses. The liability coverage in your policy should protect you in such an event.Â </p><p class="gray_text" dir="ltr">Most condominium policies provide loss assessment coverage, for up to $1,000. This coverage protects you if your building association assesses you an amount to make up for a loss it has incurred. For example, the association might make an assessment, if there is damage to the building, to cover the deductible in the association's policy or for the difference between an actual cash value settlement and the cost to replace a loss.Â </p><p class="gray_text" dir="ltr">Consider purchasing your condominium owners policy from the insurance company that sold your association's policy. If they offer you a competitive rate, insuring with them will probably reduce the time it takes to settle claims where the loss is partly the association's and partly your own.Â </p></div>]]></content>
                     <tags>condominium,insurance,policy,rent</tags>
                  </page>
               </pages>
            </wiki>
         </wikis>
         <subcommunities nav="false"/>
      </community>
</communities>
</icda>
