<icda>
   <activities/>
   <blogs/>
   <bookmarks/>
   <communities>
      <community user="dmishkey">
         <title>Auto Community</title>
         <content><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">If you&#39;re looking for information about auto insurance, you can access our helpful articles, videos, tools and more.</p>]]></content>
         <type>public</type>
         <isExternal>false</isExternal>
         <logo>9a4dd0f5-37ff-4347-91ed-5ba3a5ae573b.png</logo>
         <tags>automobile,car,insurance</tags>
         <members>
            <member role="owner" user="rgestner"/>
            <member role="owner" user="dmishkey"/>
            <member role="owner" user="ablanks"/>
            <member role="member" user="nolmos"/>
            <member role="member" user="lschonfeld"/>
            <member role="member" user="hreeds"/>
            <member role="member" user="fadams"/>
            <member role="member" user="bjordan"/>
         </members>
         <forums>
            <forum user="dmishkey">
               <title>Auto Community</title>
               <content/>
               <topics>
                  <topic user="lschonfeld">
                     <title>Does Car Insurance Cover Hail Damage?</title>
                     <content><![CDATA[
    <p dir="ltr">
      My car was outside during a hail storm am I covered?
    </p>
  ]]></content>
                     <question>true</question>
                     <likes>
                        <like user="dmishkey"/>
                     </likes>
                     <replies>
                        <reply user="dmishkey">
                           <title>Re: Does Car Insurance Cover Hail Damage?</title>
                           <content><![CDATA[<h3 dir="ltr">
      Hailstorms Can Produce Significant Damage
    </h3>
    <div class="ParagraphText" dir="ltr">
      <p>
        We've all seen photos on the news of hailstones as large as golf balls and baseballs. But, according to the <a href="https://stormdamagecenter.org/hail-storm.php" target="_blank">National Storm Damage Center (NSDC)</a>, even hail larger than three-fourths of an inch can cause serious damage. Furthermore, the NSDC says hail can fall at speeds of up to 120 miles per hour. That means during a hailstorm, your car may suffer significant damage.
      </p>
      <h3>
        Does Your Insurance Cover Hail Damage?
      </h3>
      <div class="ParagraphText">
        <p>
          So, how do you know whether your auto insurance policy covers hail damage?
        </p>
        <p>
          If you carry comprehensive coverage, you're likely covered. Comprehensive coverage can help reimburse you for damages not related to a collision. That typically includes hail damage, which could result in dents in your car's body, cracked or shattered glass, and even interior water damage.<img alt="" src="http://umb-c6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/storm.jpg" style="width: 172px; height: 109px; margin: 10px; float: right;" />
        </p>
        <p>
          The Insurance Information Institue says comprehensive coverage is usually sold with a $100 to $300 deductible, the amount you'll pay out of pocket when you make a claim. The III says policies with a higher deductible may help lower your premium -- however, if you live in an area where hailstorms occur more often, you may want to consider whether you can afford the out-of-pocket deductible after a hail claim.
        </p>
        <p>
          It's also helpful to know that, under some circumstances, your insurer may waive the deductible on the glass portion of your comprehensive coverage. For instance, if the glass is repaired, rather than replaced, your insurer may waive the deductible. Additionally, you may be able to buy full glass coverage as part of your policy, which typically means you won't have to pay a deductible on glass claims. Check with your agent to see if these options are available on your policy.
        </p>
        <p>
          When it comes to hailstorms and the potential damage they can cause to your car, it's better to be safe than sorry. Speak with your insurance agent to help decide whether comprehensive coverage might be right for you.
        </p>
      </div>
    </div>]]></content>
                        </reply>
                     </replies>
                  </topic>
                  <topic user="fadams">
                     <title>How do I know if my child is in the right car seat?</title>
                     <content><![CDATA[
    <p dir="ltr">
      I have three children and I want to make sure they are in the right car seat.&nbsp; Can anyone give me some advice?
    </p>
  ]]></content>
                     <question>true</question>
                     <answered>true</answered>
                     <likes>
                        <like user="dmishkey"/>
                        <like user="fadams"/>
                     </likes>
                     <replies>
                        <reply user="dmishkey">
                           <title>Re: How do I know if my child is in the right car seat?</title>
                           <content><![CDATA[<div class="entry-content" dir="ltr">
      <p>
        Sure, we all want our kids to be safe in the car, but a recent study shows that 73% of car seats are not being used properly. In fact, the risk of fatalities among kids could be reduced by 71% if we'd simply install the right seat the right way in the right place in the car.
      </p>
      <p>
        This becomes even more vital in light of the fact that motor vehicle accidents are the leading cause of death in children ages 3 to 14. In fact, 500 children are injured and four kids die every day in cars, trucks, and SUVs across the nation.
      </p>
      <p>
        The bottom line is that babies and children need to ride in a car seat from the time they're born until they are 7 or 8 years old in most cases. This potentially means that up to four seats per child will need to be researched, purchased, installed, and evaluated until the child is large enough to safely ride sitting in a seat with only a seatbelt.
      </p>
      <p>
        <strong>A NATIONAL CAUSE</strong>
      </p>
      <p>
        The National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA) has named Sept. 16 - 22 Child Passenger Safety Week and children's safety advocates are out in full force to raise awareness with parents and caregivers to pay closer attention to buckle up their babies in the right way. This sounds fundamental, but it may be more difficult to do that than you think.
      </p>
      <p>
        <strong>WHAT'S OUR PROBLEM?</strong>
      </p>
      <p>
        So what are we doing wrong? There are rules and 73% of us either break them or are unaware of them. Both the car and the car seat have detailed installation instruction manuals - typically, we don't read them and install correctly. Car seats have height and weight limits - we don't always follow them. Babies should be kept in rear-facing seats for as long as possible (sometimes until they are 3 years old, depending on their weight and height) - we flip them back around prematurely or put them in the front seat. Car seats have recalls and we may not have noticed. And then there's the straps; the LATCH, the angles, the correct tightening of the harness - the list is seemingly endless.
      </p>
      <p>
        <strong>CORRECTING THE FIVE MOST COMMON MISTAKES</strong>
      </p>
      <p>
        Thankfully, Safe Kids USA organization has culled some of the most important tips for parents, grandparents, and caregivers to check out immediately before taking another trip to the grocery store.
      </p>
      <p>
        1. Right Seat<br />
        Check the label on your car seat to make sure it's appropriate for your child's age, weight, and height. Like milk, your car seat has an expiration date. Just double check the label on your car seat to make sure it is still safe.
      </p>
      <p>
        2. Right Place<br />
        Tell your kids they are VIPs and we know all VIPs ride in the back seat, so keep all children in the back seat until they are 13.
      </p>
      <p>
        3. Right Direction<br />
        You want to keep your child in a rear-facing car seat for as long as possible, usually until around age 2. When he or she outgrows the seat, move your child to a forward-facing car seat. Make sure to attach the top tether after you tighten and lock the seat belt or lower anchors.
      </p>
      <p>
        4. Inch Test<br />
        Once your car seat is installed, give it a good shake at the base. Can you move it more than an inch side to side or front to back? A properly installed seat will not move more than an inch.
      </p>
      <p>
        5. Pinch Test<br />
        Make sure the harness is tightly buckled and coming from the correct slots (check car seat manual). Now, with the chest clip placed at armpit level, pinch the strap at your child's shoulder. If you are unable to pinch any excess webbing, you're good to go.
      </p>
      <p>
        <strong>PRODUCTS AND PRICING</strong>
      </p>
      <p>
        With 22 children's car seat manufacturers, building more than 30 brands of various products, the research and purchase choices are almost as baffling as buying a new car. Each seat has a definitive height and weight limit and, just like milk, an expiration date. Pricing is all over the map, but two excellent resources for ratings and reviews are <em>Consumer Reports Car Seats Buying Guide</em> and the NHTSA's Ease of Use Ratings.
      </p>
      <p>
        There are actually five types of seats on the market:
      </p>
      <p>
        Convertible car seats: Can accommodate children rear facing - most up to 35 lbs. - then can be turned forward facing for up to 80 lbs. in some cases. Convertible car seats range in price from $45 - $360 retail.
      </p>
      <p>
        Infant car seats: An array of infant car seats - some only accommodating a child up to 22 lbs. and some going slightly over that weight - range in price from $55 - $230.
      </p>
      <p>
        All-in-one car seats: Only a few all-in-one seats are on the market that range in price from $150 - $300, but they give you the benefit of providing every function from rear-facing to front-facing to booster seat on one unit. Some grow with your child from birth to 100 lbs.
      </p>
      <p>
        Toddler booster seats: These are forward-facing seats with an internal harness for toddlers weighing between 20 - 90 lbs. Although these seats allow for babies as small as 20 lbs., it is recommended by safety experts that a child should be in a rear-facing seat until they are 30 - 35 lbs. Toddler booster seats range in price from $50 - $255.
      </p>
      <p>
        Booster seats: For children weighing 40 to 100 lbs., boosters should be used until a child is at least 57 inches tall which is the minimum height at which a car's seatbelt will fit him/her properly. Booster seats are the least expensive of the group - ranging from $14 - $95 retail.
      </p>
    </div>]]></content>
                           <answer>true</answer>
                        </reply>
                     </replies>
                  </topic>
                  <topic user="nolmos">
                     <title>Will self-driving cars lower my car insurance?</title>
                     <content><![CDATA[
    <p dir="ltr">
      With Google and other companies working on driver-less cars.&nbsp; How will this affect my car insurance?
    </p>
  ]]></content>
                     <question>true</question>
                     <likes>
                        <like user="dmishkey"/>
                        <like user="ablanks"/>
                     </likes>
                     <replies>
                        <reply user="dmishkey">
                           <title>Re: Will self-driving cars lower my car insurance?</title>
                           <content><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">
      In 2020 Google plans to launch a self-driving car which has already driven nearly one million miles without causing an accident; it doesn't get tired and irritable, swerve into lamp posts or require a driving test. The in-built chauffeur comes in the form of a rotating LIDAR laser taking 1.3 million recordings per second, and it's a better driver than you. By eliminating the element of human blunders, driverless cars are forecast to reduce motor accidents by up to 90% in the US. That might imply a substantial impact on the insurance industry, with liability potentially shifting to car manufacturers. Such developments would pose challenging questions for the PRA in regulating UK insurance firms.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      &nbsp;
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      In the UK 23% of all car insurance claims result from parking incidents of which 71% occur during reversing. A switch to driverless cars could largely eliminate these costs. This is a double edged sword for UK insurers who underwrote around £8bn in private motor insurance premiums last year. What they could save in falling claims costs and frequency, they stand to lose in shrinking premiums - one estimate being as much as 50% by 2025 and 80% by 2040 according to&nbsp; Research.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      The entire basis of motor insurance, which mainly exists because people crash, could also be upended. Harvesting data on individual drivers is key for insurers to predict the riskiness of people - more information means smarter pricing. But self-driving cars take the driver out of the equation - a 17 year old male and 35 year old female could now receive the same car insurance quote - with the vehicle as the key determinant of risk.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      So how might motor insurers adapt in a driverless world?
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <strong>Accelerating challenges to motor insurers: profitability…</strong>
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      There's a lesson to learn from other companies battles in the stock market and plunge into bankruptcy after failing to embrace digitalised photography. Forward-looking investors in the largest publicly traded UK insurers - many of whom write motor insurance as their primary line of business - might not wait till driverless cars are on the road before worrying about this development.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      This doesn't have to be the case. Insurers have an existing customer base, brand value and insurance expertise. They have increasingly sophisticated fraud departments, a gold mine of data and, despite hosting some of TV's most annoying adverts, insurers have profited from the booming popularity of price comparison websites. These resources could be gainfully employed elsewhere.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Naturally, there may be increased focus on expanding into other lines of business such as Household and Commercial insurance.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      But traveling in a driverless car will also free up a lot of time for passengers. That's time that could be spent on iPads, TVs, music systems and computers - all candidates for automobile contents insurance. Alarmingly, there are also concerns over cyber-attacks against cars' smart technology wreaking havoc on roads en masse. Here, the provision of cyber insurance could be both necessary and lucrative.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Yet an even more pressing question for insurers might be the direction that vehicle legislation on liability takes, as the bulk of profitability may be realised from tie-ups with manufacturers.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <strong>…and liability</strong>
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      There are naysayers who claim to enjoy the gratification of driving too much to give it up. Some will even sympathies with branding their Car the 'leader of the human resistance': "An unmanned car driven by a search engine company? We've seen that movie and it ends with robots harvesting our bodies for energy."
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      But the reality is that vehicle technology is already assisting human judgement; parking sensors, automatic braking and cruise control make it 25-45% less likely that an accident will occur, granting drivers up to a 20% reduction in car insurance. As human drivers become replaced by lasers and sensors, the placement of liability may start to shift towards manufacturers.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      A case in point: Volvo has aspirationally declared that by 2020 no-one will die in one of its cars - a claim which will hinge on the robustness of Volvo's technology. This could make them liable in the event of a car collision caused by faulty sensors if Volvo guarantees to cover the costs of accidents to lure customers. Volvo could become the de facto insurer of its own product.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      It's still a legal grey area however, particularly for partially autonomous cars. Floridian law exempts manufacturers from liability for cars retrofitted with automating technology whilst German lawyers argue that the legality of autonomous vehicles on German roads is contingent upon the presence of a fully liable driver operating them. Bridging the legislative gap between cars which allow for manual override and those in which a driver is unnecessary is still an area under consideration by the Department for Transport.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <strong>Will this wipe out traditional motor insurance?</strong>
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Maybe not. It's feasible that some motor incidents may still require traditional insurance, even if driving habits change significantly. Damage and injuries caused by trees falling onto driverless cars could be subsumed under health insurance or shift to household contents insurance, according to a study by RAND.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Second, manufacturers may want to partner with insurance companies. After all, insurers will have the existing organizational structures, customer links and expertise to provide insurance. The success of UK insurers in securing such business from manufacturers would likely depend on their ability to price competitively, although core supporting services are likely to remain operational in the UK. If a Japanese car crashes on UK soil, then contesting the claim remains in the jurisdiction of UK courts and not Japan. International car manufacturers may therefore want to keep ties with localized claims divisions.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Retail motor insurance - currently based on the relationship between a driver and their insurance company - might increasingly mould into commercial, inter-company insurance contracts. Regulators will have to be mindful of such potential reconfigurations in the insurance industry, especially in the light of three US Insurers recognizing driver-less cars as a risk factor in their SEC filings, and would expect to discuss these and other strategic challenges with firms as part of their on-going supervision.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <strong>Driverless cities?</strong>
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Communal ownership of autonomous cars and designated 'driverless zones' in major cities could evolve. M-City is one such area; 32 acres on the University of Michigan devoted to testing driverless cars in a simulated urban environment. Ultimately, car ownership is expensive and inefficient. Road tax, maintenance, depreciation, parking hassle and insurance all cost on average a year, but cars are only in use for 5% of the time. As the appetite for car ownership has slowed, schemes such as Zip Car and Uber have soared in popularity.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      In such a city, vehicles could be communally insured via pay as you go- hail the car and pay with your contactless card, arrive at your destination and the car will valet park itself. In such a world, insurers could participate in a pooled scheme of insurance. Split the premiums received from the pay as you go scheme, and each pay a levy towards any accidents that occur.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <strong>Is it time we took our hands off the wheel?</strong>
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      The Google Chauffeur for some will still be confined to the realm of science fiction, but at one point so were cars. As Henry Ford is attributed to saying: "If I asked my customers what they wanted, they would have said faster horses". The number of fatalities on UK roads does call for a solution which autonomous cars may address. However, public reception of driverless vehicles will be critical to their evolution, and subsequently, the scale of impact to insurers.
    </p>]]></content>
                           <likes>
                              <like user="dmishkey"/>
                              <like user="ablanks"/>
                           </likes>
                        </reply>
                     </replies>
                  </topic>
               </topics>
            </forum>
         </forums>
         <blogs>
            <communityblog user="dmishkey">
               <title>Looking Backward to See Forward</title>
               <handle>9a4dd0f5-37ff-4347-91ed-5ba3a5ae573b</handle>
               <summary><![CDATA[</a...]]></summary>
               <posts>
                  <post user="dmishkey">
                     <title>Looking Backward to See Forward</title>
                     <content><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr"><a href="http://umb-c6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/bike.png" target="_blank"><img alt="image" height="126" src="http://umb-c6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/bike.png" style="display: block; margin: 1em 1em 0pt 0pt; float: left;" width="192"></img></a>What a crisp fall day to find oneself on the road astride a bicycle yesterday. In the North East of the US, there was just a whisper of fall in the wind, and still a warm burning sun. We are lucky where I live as we have a county sponsored &lsquo;Bicycle Sunday&rsquo; where car traffic is shut down to give a safe two-lane highway to two-wheeled vehicles.</p>



<p dir="ltr">It was sublime conditions. It reminded me we are only a few weeks away from walk and bike to school day, so it seems a good time to bring up the topic of safety.</p>



<p dir="ltr">Cyclists have been having a tougher time out on the road for a variety of reasons. Besides the statistic of 8.9 percent increase in fatalities, there is also the informal statistic that when I started seriously riding, I didn&rsquo;t know many people who had an impact with a car. Now it&rsquo;s getting hard to find a fellow cyclist who hasn&rsquo;t had a direct accident involving a car or truck. While I&rsquo;m personally sure distracted driving is part of the problem, there is also the fact that there are simply more cars and more bicycles out on the road. In fact, cycling&rsquo;s popularity has caused it to be dubbed by some as &ldquo;the new golf,&rdquo; as a business relationship sport. With this renewed popularity, cycling&rsquo;s future on US roads will look different than it&rsquo;s past. Therefore, as a risk pool, and individually speaking, risk simply goes up with every ride, and I know it. I wonder if insurance is accounting for this risk in any way?</p>



<p dir="ltr">This is not just true of cycling. There are other risks that are changing, like fire risk in parts of the US. The future is clearly not emulating the past in this case, too. Yet the way risk is assessed on individuals in P&amp;C is not as dynamic a model or as predictive of the future.</p>



<p dir="ltr">With a world that is changing drastically on so many fronts, I wonder how long it will be that insurance leans primarily on historical data as an assessment of future risk. When it seems so evident that the future, with all its benefits, potential and &ndash; yes, risks &mdash; may not resemble the past in any way we might imagine. Therefore, insurance, like cycling, needs to make assessments based more on the road ahead than on what is left on the road behind.</p>



<p dir="ltr">One potential source of that data may be from smart phones and cars, data which could provide deeper analytics insights that could let me cycle even safer, through location and tracking that can calculate roads, traffic patterns and times of day that are most dangerous to recreational cycling.</p>



<p dir="ltr">Insurance can be a leader in gathering and sharing this type of data and helping protect drivers and cyclists &ndash; both of which are their insured &mdash; from accidents neither of them want to have. I&rsquo;m hoping to hear how analytics might make us all safer at Insight2015 in a month from now, so my eyes are on the road ahead.</p>]]></content>
                     <tags>car,insurance,bicycle</tags>
                  </post>
                  <post user="dmishkey">
                     <title>Learning a Vehicle’s Past: What to Look for in a Vehicle History Report</title>
                     <content><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr"><a href="http://umb-c6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/keys2.JPG" target="_blank"><img alt="image" height="137" src="http://umb-c6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/keys2.JPG" style="display: block; margin: 1em 1em 0pt 0pt; float: left;" width="208"></img></a>No matter how much research or shopping around you do, purchasing a used vehicle always feels like a gamble. If you&rsquo;re currently in the market for a pre-owned vehicle, there are several factors you definitely need to consider, such as previous maintenance, accidents and more. Sure, you will get some of this information from whomever is coordinating the sale &ndash; be it the previous owner or a third-party dealership &ndash; but it&rsquo;s also important to dig deeper than what they are telling you. They are, after all, trying to make a sale, so they may omit any information they think might deter you from making the purchase.</p>



<p dir="ltr">That being said, it&rsquo;s always a good idea to do a little homework on your own. A great way to gather hard facts about a vehicle&rsquo;s past is to request a vehicle history report from a reputable organization. The National Motor Vehicle Title Information System provides consumers with a list of approved providers, to help ensure they only get 100% accurate information on the vehicle in question.</p>



<p dir="ltr">However, running a vehicle history report is not enough to ensure you don&rsquo;t get stuck with a clunker. You also have to understand the data the report is giving you. In an effort to spread awareness, DMW.org provides a free sample report on their website to help people become more familiar with the format. If you feel like you still need some help analyzing the information, read on for some tips on what to look for when you have a vehicle history report done on a potential purchase.</p>



<p dir="ltr"><span style="font-size:14px;"><strong>Number of Owners</strong></span></p>



<p dir="ltr">Any good, worthwhile vehicle history report should include a rough estimate of the previous number of owners. It&rsquo;s a general rule that the quality of a car goes down the more owners it has. Sure, there are exceptions to this rule, but if a rather &ldquo;young&rdquo; vehicle has had a dozen owners, it&rsquo;s highly unlikely it has been given the care and maintenance it needs to be a top-performer.</p>



<p dir="ltr"><span style="font-size:14px;"><strong>Mileage</strong></span></p>



<p dir="ltr">Another detail included on most reports is the mileage on a vehicle. Sure, you can see this yourself on the odometer if you are purchasing it in person. Yet seeing the build-up over time on the report helps give a more accurate picture of the car or truck&rsquo;s actual activity over its lifetime. A car owned by a traveling salesman or used by a rental agency will likely have more wear and tear than one used by a person who has a 9-5 desk job.</p>



<p dir="ltr"><strong><span style="font-size:14px;">Accident and Theft Records</span></strong></p>



<p dir="ltr">The number of accidents should also be noted on the report, along with any records of theft. Both of these details can greatly impact a vehicle&rsquo;s future performance. For instance, if a vehicle has previously been reported stolen, there&rsquo;s a chance any number of the parts were tampered with and altered, potentially improperly. The same goes for any repair work done to the car. Sure, it might seem fine, but, depending on how detailed your report is, you will likely have no information on where or who repaired the car or truck, leaving the quality of work done a complete mystery to you. A minor mistake made during a repair five years ago might not be currently causing problems, but over time the quick-fix could wear down and cause more harm than good.</p>



<p dir="ltr"><span style="font-size:14px;"><strong>Overview</strong></span></p>



<p dir="ltr">Obviously the specific details reported will vary by provider, but the three points listed above are pretty standard and should be included on most reports. Scrutinize your vehicle history report with a keen, sharp eye and investigate any discrepancies you find between the data and the story you&rsquo;ve been told about the car, truck or SUV in question. A little extra work now could potentially save you lots of time and money later.</p>]]></content>
                     <tags>report,history,car,vehicle</tags>
                     <likes>
                        <like user="ablanks"/>
                        <like user="dmishkey"/>
                     </likes>
                  </post>
                  <post user="rgestner">
                     <title>Deadly Driving: A Look At Teen Drivers</title>
                     <content><![CDATA[<div class="entry-content" dir="ltr">

<p>If you&rsquo;re seeking a car insurance plan, there are many, many factors that get taken into account, particularly if you have a family with kids in it&mdash;kids who will one day likely be sitting behind the wheel of your family car. Getting your teen started down the road with a learner&rsquo;s permit can be one of the most nerve-wracking experiences in your entire adult life. Most teens are ready and eager to hit the open road, but there&rsquo;s a lot of consideration that needs to go into making sure your teen is safe and insured properly for any circumstance that may arise. Teenagers and younger drivers are hands-down the most accident prone demographic on the road: They crash more, seem to think less, and tend to engage in more risky behaviors, like drinking and driving or texting while behind the wheel. You want your teen to be safe, and you also want them to be taken care of by your insurance plan. If you&rsquo;re curious about the proper way to be sure your teen is well cared for by your insurance plan, check out this handy <a href="http://www.carinsurance.org/guide/">guide</a> to the best insurance for your young driver. Every parent&rsquo;s ultimate desire is for their teen to stay safe, but the odds of your 16-year-old getting into a fender bender are too high to not make entirely sure that your insurance policy is reliable and effective for any situation. Whether you&rsquo;re the parent of a soon-to-be-driving teen yourself or you simply want to be more aware of those young folk you share the road with, the following infographic takes an in-depth look at some of the dangers that are present among teen drivers today.</p>



<p><a href="http://umb-c6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/teen.jpg" style="width: 100%; display: inline-block;" target="_blank"><img alt="image" src="http://umb-c6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/teen.jpg" style="  display:block; margin: 0 auto;text-align: center;"></img></a></p>

</div>]]></content>
                     <tags>driver,accidents,deadly,teen</tags>
                     <likes>
                        <like user="ablanks"/>
                        <like user="dmishkey"/>
                        <like user="bjordan"/>
                        <like user="hreeds"/>
                     </likes>
                     <comments>
                        <comment user="ablanks">
                           <content><![CDATA[Great article ]]></content>
                        </comment>
                        <comment user="bjordan">
                           <content><![CDATA[This graphic about teen drivers is sobering. And we parents should talk more with our teens to get them to understand the ramifications of, say, wearing a seat belt ALL THE TIME.]]></content>
                           <likes>
                              <like user="dmishkey"/>
                           </likes>
                        </comment>
                        <comment user="eelamon">
                           <content><![CDATA[Heather, the best thing we did to help our daughter was to buy her a car she absolutely adores.  She is do careful because she knows she will not be getting another one.]]></content>
                        </comment>
                        <comment user="hreeds">
                           <content><![CDATA[I am sending this to all of my children who have children!]]></content>
                           <likes>
                              <like user="eelamon"/>
                           </likes>
                        </comment>
                     </comments>
                  </post>
                  <post user="dmishkey">
                     <title>The Case for Car Seats: Never Leave Home Without One</title>
                     <content><![CDATA[<div class="entry-content" dir="ltr">

<p dir="ltr">Motor vehicle accidents are the leading cause of injury and death among children of all ages in the U.S. The lifesaving power of seat belts and booster seats is well-proven, but with safety recommendations and regulations changing practically yearly, it can be difficult for parents to keep up. How can parents know when a high-priced booster seat is worth it? When is a rear-facing seat safer than a front-facing seat? And now that you can buy booster seats for kids who weigh up to 90 lbs, does that mean we really need to?</p>



<p dir="ltr">Luckily, consumer safety organizations like the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, breaks down the latest research in child car safety and provides extensive guides for parents who need to know more about choosing and using the booster seat that&rsquo;s right for their child. In the event of an accident the way you fit and fasten your car seat is more important than how many bells and whistles it came with. Unfortunately, as you&rsquo;ll see in the graphic below, it turns out that many well-meaning parents or caregivers aren&rsquo;t actually their child seats properly.</p>



<p dir="ltr"><a href="http://umb-c6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/carseat.gif" style="width: 100%; display: inline-block;" target="_blank"><img alt="image" src="http://umb-c6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/carseat.gif" style="  display:block; margin: 0 auto;text-align: center;"></img></a></p>

</div>]]></content>
                     <tags>care_seat,seat_belts,children</tags>
                     <likes>
                        <like user="dmishkey"/>
                     </likes>
                  </post>
               </posts>
            </communityblog>
         </blogs>
         <wikis>
            <wiki user="dmishkey">
               <title>Auto Community</title>
               <summary><![CDATA[If you're looking for information about auto insurance, you can access our helpful articles, videos, tools and more.]]></summary>
               <label>W9ffd358304dd_4115_8ba6_8fee6780babf</label>
               <visibility>PUBLIC_TO_VIEWERS</visibility>
               <pages>
                  <page user="dmishkey">
                     <title>Auto Community</title>
                     <label>Auto Community</label>
                     <content><![CDATA[<div><div dir="ltr">
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size:26px;"><strong>This is the place to discuss all things about cars</strong></span></p>

<table align="center" border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" dir="ltr" height="1291" style="font-family: helvetica neue,helvetica,arial,sans-serif;" width="883">
	<tbody>
		<tr>
			<td align="left" style="margin: 0px; padding: 5px; width: 28%;" valign="top">
			<table border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" height="524" style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px; border: 1px solid rgb(175, 175, 175); box-shadow: 2px 2px 1px 1px rgb(225,225,225);" width="417">
				<tbody>
					<tr>
						<td height="25" style="padding: 10px 15px 0px; width: 357px; text-align: center; color: rgb(4, 80, 115) !important; font-size: 15px;">If you have questions we have the answers.</td>
					</tr>
					<tr>
						<td style="padding: 10px 15px 0px; width: 357px; text-align: center;"><img height="331" src="http://umb-c6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/question3.jpg" width="355" /></td>
					</tr>
					<tr>
						<td height="40" style="padding: 10px 15px 0px; width: 357px; text-align: center; color: rgb(4, 80, 115) !important; line-height: 30px; font-size: 28px; font-weight: 200;" valign="middle"><a href="http://umb-c6.ibmcollabcloud.com/communities/service/html/communityoverview?communityUuid=9a4dd0f5-37ff-4347-91ed-5ba3a5ae573b#fullpageWidgetId=W1e9e966957fa_4233_9429_22d656905674">The&nbsp;Car&nbsp;Forums</a></td>
					</tr>
					<tr>
						<td style="padding: 10px 15px; width: 357px; text-align: center; color: rgb(54, 58, 62) !important; line-height: 24px; font-size: 20px; font-weight: 100;">Please ask your question here</td>
					</tr>
				</tbody>
			</table>
			</td>
			<td align="left" style="margin: 0px; padding: 5px; width: 28%; vertical-align: top;" valign="top">
			<table border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px; border: 1px solid rgb(175, 175, 175); box-shadow: 2px 2px 1px 1px rgb(225,225,225);" width="100%">
				<tbody>
					<tr>
						<td height="25" style="padding: 10px 15px 0px; text-align: center; color: rgb(4, 80, 115) !important; font-size: 15px;">Share your ideas on cars here</td>
					</tr>
					<tr>
						<td style="padding: 10px 15px 0px; text-align: center; vertical-align: middle;"><img height="359" src="http://umb-c6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/toycar.JPG" width="234" /></td>
					</tr>
					<tr>
						<td height="40" style="padding: 10px 15px 0px; text-align: center; color: rgb(4, 80, 115) !important; line-height: 30px; font-size: 28px; font-weight: 200;" valign="middle"><a href="http://umb-c6.ibmcollabcloud.com/blogs/9a4dd0f5-37ff-4347-91ed-5ba3a5ae573b?lang=en_us">The&nbsp;Car&nbsp;Blogs</a></td>
					</tr>
					<tr>
						<td style="padding: 10px 15px; text-align: center; color: rgb(54, 58, 62) !important; line-height: 24px; font-size: 20px; font-weight: 100;">Fun place to share stories about cars, insurance, and safety.</td>
					</tr>
				</tbody>
			</table>
			</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td align="left" style="margin: 0px; padding: 5px; width: 28%; vertical-align: top;" valign="top">
			<table border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" height="513" style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px; border: 1px solid rgb(175, 175, 175); box-shadow: 2px 2px 1px 1px rgb(225,225,225);" width="412">
				<tbody>
					<tr>
						<td height="25" style="padding: 10px 15px 0px; color: rgb(4, 80, 115) !important; font-size: 15px;">
						<p style="text-align: center;">Advanced Defensive Driving - Take it to the Next Level</p>
						</td>
					</tr>
					<tr>
						<td style="padding: 10px 15px 0px;"><img height="251" src="http://umb-c6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/truck2.jpg" width="379" /></td>
					</tr>
					<tr>
						<td height="40" style="padding: 10px 15px 0px; text-align: center; color: rgb(4, 80, 115) !important; line-height: 30px; font-size: 28px; font-weight: 200;" valign="middle"><a href="/wikis/home#!/wiki/Wf0f8d99d4e20_4604_a371_a3611b08ada2/page/Advanced%20Defensive%20Driving%20-%20Take%20it%20to%20the%20Next%20LevelNew%20Page" lconnwikimacro="wikilink" lconnwikiparamwikipage="Advanced Defensive Driving - Take it to the Next LevelNew Page" target="_blank">Click here to find out more</a></td>
					</tr>
					<tr>
						<td style="padding: 10px 15px; text-align: center; color: rgb(54, 58, 62) !important; line-height: 24px; font-size: 20px; font-weight: 100;">According to the National Safety Council, a preventable accident is one in which the driver failed to do everything that reasonably could have been done to avoid the crash.</td>
					</tr>
				</tbody>
			</table>
			</td>
			<td align="left" style="margin: 0px; padding: 5px; width: 28%; vertical-align: top;" valign="top">
			<table border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px; border: 1px solid rgb(175, 175, 175); box-shadow: 2px 2px 1px 1px rgb(225,225,225);" width="100%">
				<tbody>
					<tr>
						<td height="25" style="padding: 10px 15px 0px; color: rgb(4, 80, 115) !important; font-size: 15px;">
						<p style="text-align: center;">Study Shows Car Owners Keeping Vehicles Longer</p>
						</td>
					</tr>
					<tr>
						<td style="padding: 10px 15px 0px; text-align: center;"><img height="288" src="http://umb-c6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/tall%20car2.jpg" width="252" /></td>
					</tr>
					<tr>
						<td height="40" style="padding: 10px 15px 0px; text-align: center; color: rgb(4, 80, 115) !important; line-height: 30px; font-size: 28px; font-weight: 200;" valign="middle"><a href="/wikis/home#!/wiki/Wf0f8d99d4e20_4604_a371_a3611b08ada2/page/Study%20Shows%20Car%20Owners%20Keeping%20Vehicles%20Longer" lconnwikimacro="wikilink" lconnwikiparamwikipage="Study Shows Car Owners Keeping Vehicles Longer">Click here to find out more</a></td>
					</tr>
					<tr>
						<td style="padding: 10px 15px; text-align: center; color: rgb(54, 58, 62) !important; line-height: 24px; font-size: 20px; font-weight: 100;">Today's typical new car buyer keeps their vehicle for almost six years, or 71.4 months to be exact.</td>
					</tr>
				</tbody>
			</table>
			</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td align="left" colspan="2" style="margin: 0px; padding: 5px; width: 28%; vertical-align: top;" valign="top">
			<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><span style="font-size:20px;"><span style="color: rgb(0, 128, 128);">Humor for the day - Take from real customer events.</span></span></strong></p>

			<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size:14px;"><span style="color: rgb(0, 128, 128);"><strong>Signs You Should Probably Stop Driving</strong></span></span></p>

			<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>(An elderly customer calls about her policy, which has increased at the most recent renewal due to an accident she's had pulling out of the drive from her retirement community.)</strong></p>

			<p><strong>Customer:</strong> You know, I'm really a good driver. I just didn't see the other car. It came from nowhere.</p>

			<p><strong>Agent:</strong> I'm sure you wouldn't have attempted to pull out if you'd seen it.</p>

			<p><strong>Customer:</strong> Many of my neighbors sold their cars and ride the bus; several routes go right by our complex. I can't do that, though, because I don't see so well anymore. I can't read those signs they have on the buses that say where they are going.</p>

			<p><strong>Agent: ....</strong></p>
			</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td align="left" colspan="2" style="margin: 0px; padding: 5px; width: 28%; vertical-align: top;" valign="top">
			<div dir="ltr">
			<ul dir="ltr" style="margin: 0px auto; padding: 4em 0px; width: 700px; font-family: roboto, helvetica, Arial;">
				<li style="padding:15px; width: 100%; overflow: hidden; vertical-align: top; display: inline-block; box-sizing: border-box; background-color: rgba(50, 92, 128, 0.8);">
				<h2 style="margin: 0px; color: rgb(255, 255, 255) ! important; text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 1.7em; font-weight: 600;">The Digital Insurance Team</span></h2>
				&nbsp;

				<ul style="width: 100%; font-family: roboto, helvetica, Arial;">
					<li style="width: 33%; display: inline-block;">
					<h4 style="color: rgb(255, 255, 255) ! important;">Home Insurance</h4>

					<div class="staffLeft" role="presentation" style="float: none !important;"><span class="staffComm"><a class="fn url" href="/profiles/html/profileView.do?key=c71b6bfe-a058-4985-9a69-d3c926327241" title=""><img alt="Amy Blanks" class="staffPeople32" height="85" src="/profiles/photo.do?key=c71b6bfe-a058-4985-9a69-d3c926327241" title="Amy Blanks" width="85" /></a></span></div>
					</li>
					<li style="width: 33%; display: inline-block;">
					<h4 style="color: rgb(255, 255, 255) !important;">Auto Insurance</h4>

					<div class="staffLeft" role="presentation" style="float: none !important;"><span class="staffComm"><a class="fn url" href="/profiles/html/profileView.do?key=6cb64a59-1bc1-497b-baa7-38d25bb2afd9" title=""><img alt="Dan Mishkey" class="staffPeople32" height="85" src="/profiles/photo.do?key=6cb64a59-1bc1-497b-baa7-38d25bb2afd9" title="Dan Mishkey" width="85" /></a></span></div>
					</li>
					<li style="width: 33%; display: inline-block;">
					<h4 style="color: rgb(255, 255, 255) !important;">Life Insurance</h4>

					<div class="staffLeft" role="presentation" style="float: none !important;"><span class="staffComm"><a class="fn url" href="/profiles/html/profileView.do?key=ceca5296-cab4-4f51-a897-045c9b458bf1" title=""><img alt="Rebecca Gestner" class="staffPeople32" height="85" src="/profiles/photo.do?key=ceca5296-cab4-4f51-a897-045c9b458bf1" title="Rebecca Gestner" width="85" /></a></span></div>
					</li>
				</ul>

				<p style="margin: 0px; color: rgb(255, 255, 255); font-size: 1.2em;">&nbsp;</p>
				</li>
			</ul>
			</div>
			</td>
		</tr>
	</tbody>
</table>
</div>
</div>]]></content>
                     <tags>auto,cars,community</tags>
                  </page>
                  <page user="dmishkey">
                     <title>Advanced Defensive Driving - Take it to the Next LevelNew Page</title>
                     <label>Advanced Defensive Driving - Take it to the Next LevelNew Page</label>
                     <content><![CDATA[<div><p dir="ltr">According to the <a href="http://www.nsc.org/Pages/Home.aspx">National Safety Council</a>, a preventable accident is one in which the driver failed to do everything that reasonably could have been done to avoid the crash. Experts agree that driving defensively is your best bet at making sure a crash, collision, or accident doesn't happen to you. We've already discussed the basic concepts behind defensive driving, which include scanning and visualizing everything, having an escape route, and not becoming distracted. Now let's consider some more advanced, preventive measures a responsible driver can take to avoid a potentially life-threatening crash.</p>

<h3 dir="ltr">Maintain Your Car</h3>

<p dir="ltr">Regular maintenance on your car significantly helps its road performance, especially in potentially hazardous driving situations. You can't drive a car defensively if its tires are in need of air, windows, rearview mirror, and signal lights are dirty, and brake pads are worn to shreds. Here are a few steps you should take to keep your car running safely and efficiently:</p>

<ul dir="ltr">
	<li><b>Check Your Tires</b> Make sure your tire pressure is where it should be. The recommended pressure for your car's tires will be in your owner's manual or in the driver's side door jamb. When it comes to purchasing new tires, take into account the weather in your part of the country. Four snow tires total is the safest way to go if you anticipate driving in snow and ice.</li>
	<li><b>Align Your Tires</b> If while driving your car seems to drift to one side or the steering wheel vibrates, you may need to have the tires aligned. Alignment actually refers to a car's suspension, which can move out of alignment over time due to normal driving, a minor accident, or bumping against a curb. Check your owner's manual to see how often your car's manufacturer recommends aligning your car's tires. Alignment helps to insure better handling, which is crucial for good defensive driving, as well as better gas mileage.<img height="116" src="http://umb-c6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/tools2.jpg" style="margin: 10px; float: right;" width="173" /></li>
	<li><b>Clean Your Car</b> A dirty windshield or rearview mirror will prevent you from scanning and visualizing the road for potential dangers. And grimy signal lights or head lights will prevent other drivers from seeing you in bad weather or at night, which pretty much negates any effort you make to be a good defensive driver.</li>
	<li><b>Change Your Brake Pads</b> If when braking, you hear squeaking or grinding, your brake pads may be worn out and in need of replacement. Knowing how and when to brake, especially in inclement weather, is a crucial skill for defensive driving. If you have an antilock brake system and need to stop in on an icy road, stomp on the pedal and when you feel the system's pulses or hear it working, ease up a bit on the pedal until it's only pulsing about once a second. If you don't have ABS, you should push the brake hard and when the wheels stop turning, lift your foot so the wheels turn and rapidly press the brake again.</li>
</ul>

<h3 dir="ltr">Other Advanced Defensive Driving Tips</h3>

<ul dir="ltr">
	<li><b>Yield, Move, Get Out Of The Way</b> Driving defensively for the most part involves avoiding overly aggressive drivers. It may be frustrating to just step aside in order to give a bad driver room to do whatever they want, but it is the safest thing to do, not only for yourself but for everyone else on the road. When you encounter a speeding driver pressuring you to go faster, move into another lane, even if it means going slower. As a defensive driver, accept the fact that you may have to sacrifice your right of way in order to avoid a speeding ticket or collision.</li>
	<li><b>Plan a Route</b> To avoid a time-consuming and potentially dangerous drive, plan out your route out in advance based on current weather, traffic, and road conditions. Local websites, radio, and even iPhone apps can provide you with the information you need before you hit the road and find yourself navigating road construction or an end-of-the-week traffic jam.</li>
	<li><b>Take a Course</b> There's nothing wrong with taking a driving course to brush up your skills, even if you've been driving for years. Check with your agent to see if completing a driving course will give you discount on your car insurance or on roadside assistance plans.</li>
</ul>
</div>]]></content>
                     <tags>defensive,driving,safety</tags>
                  </page>
                  <page user="fadams">
                     <title>Study Shows Car Owners Keeping Vehicles Longer</title>
                     <label>Study Shows Car Owners Keeping Vehicles Longer</label>
                     <content><![CDATA[<div><p dir="ltr">According to a study from the automotive research firm, Americans are now holding on to their new care purchases much longer than in years past. Today's typical new car buyer keeps their vehicle for almost six years, or 71.4 months to be exact. That number has increased by 18 months since 2006 alone. It should also be noted that new car sales figures are boosted by leases, which typically only last for two to four years, which bring the overall length of time owners keep their new cars down.</p>

<p dir="ltr">They also found that used car buyers are keeping their vehicles longer as well. Consumers of used passenger cars and trucks kept their vehicles an average of 49.9 months, which is 17.6 months longer than the 32.3 months reported in 2003. In addition, the trend of buyers keeping cars for longer periods of time has also pushed the average age of vehicles on U.S. roads to a record 10.8 years.<img height="164" src="http://umb-c6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/hummer2.jpg" style="margin: 10px; float: left;" width="182" /></p>

<p dir="ltr">One of the biggest reasons for the decline in new car sales and the increase in overall vehicle age is attributed to the decline in the U.S. economy since 2008. With less disposable income available for a number of Americans, would-be buyers are choosing to hold on to their cars and pay off auto loans rather than trading in their vehicles for newer models.</p>

<p dir="ltr">They also said that people are holding on to their cars because of an increase in vehicle quality. In the past, the prevailing belief was that cars generally reached their performance limit at 100,000 miles, pushing drivers to purchase new vehicles once their vehicles perceived life spans were up. However, a lot of today's drivers have been forced to keep their cars longer than this period, so they've consequently learned that their cars actually still performed quite well despite being over the established distance limitation.</p>

<p dir="ltr">To add to this, automakers have also lengthened their warranties. While most new, non-luxury brands already come with a three-year or 36,000-mile bumper-to-bumper warranty, many have opted to also extend coverage on drive train components like the engine and transmission for up to 10 years or 100,000 miles. Additionally, most luxury brands, and even Hyundai, typically carry a four- or five-year warranty that typically extends to 60,000 miles.</p>

<p dir="ltr">One bright spot for auto manufacturers is that the recent upswing in the economy, combined with the high average age of vehicles on the road today, has helped boost new car sales. Americans bought 12.8 million vehicles in 2014, which was up from 11.6 million in 2013. The number is expected to rise again in 2015, ranging from 13.7 million to 14.5 million this year.</p>
</div>]]></content>
                  </page>
               </pages>
            </wiki>
         </wikis>
         <bookmarks/>
         <files/>
      </community>
   </communities>
   <files/>
   <forums/>
   <profiles/>
   <wikis/>
</icda>
