<icda>
   <activities/>
   <blogs/>
   <bookmarks/>
   <communities>
      <community user="dmishkey">
         <title>Auto Community</title>
         <content><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">If you&#39;re looking for information about auto insurance, you can access our helpful articles, videos, tools and more.</p>]]></content>
         <type>public</type>
         <isExternal>false</isExternal>
         <logo>9a4dd0f5-37ff-4347-91ed-5ba3a5ae573b.png</logo>
         <tags>automobile,car,insurance</tags>
         <members>
            <member role="owner" user="rgestner"/>
            <member role="owner" user="dmishkey"/>
            <member role="owner" user="ablanks"/>
            <member role="member" user="nolmos"/>
            <member role="member" user="hreeds"/>
            <member role="member" user="fadams"/>
            <member role="member" user="bjordan"/>
         </members>
         <wikis>
            <wiki user="dmishkey">
               <title>Auto Community</title>
               <summary><![CDATA[If you're looking for information about auto insurance, you can access our helpful articles, videos, tools and more.]]></summary>
               <label>W9ffd358304dd_4115_8ba6_8fee6780babf</label>
               <visibility>PUBLIC_TO_VIEWERS</visibility>
               <pages>
                  <page user="dmishkey">
                     <title>Auto Community</title>
                     <label>Auto Community</label>
                     <content><![CDATA[<div><div dir="ltr">
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size:26px;"><strong>This is the place to discuss all things about cars</strong></span></p>

<table align="center" border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" dir="ltr" height="1291" style="font-family: helvetica neue,helvetica,arial,sans-serif;" width="883">
	<tbody>
		<tr>
			<td align="left" style="margin: 0px; padding: 5px; width: 28%;" valign="top">
			<table border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" height="524" style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px; border: 1px solid rgb(175, 175, 175); box-shadow: 2px 2px 1px 1px rgb(225,225,225);" width="417">
				<tbody>
					<tr>
						<td height="25" style="padding: 10px 15px 0px; width: 357px; text-align: center; color: rgb(4, 80, 115) !important; font-size: 15px;">If you have questions we have the answers.</td>
					</tr>
					<tr>
						<td style="padding: 10px 15px 0px; width: 357px; text-align: center;"><img height="331" src="http://umb-c6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/question3.jpg" width="355" /></td>
					</tr>
					<tr>
						<td height="40" style="padding: 10px 15px 0px; width: 357px; text-align: center; color: rgb(4, 80, 115) !important; line-height: 30px; font-size: 28px; font-weight: 200;" valign="middle"><a href="http://umb-c6.ibmcollabcloud.com/communities/service/html/communityoverview?communityUuid=9a4dd0f5-37ff-4347-91ed-5ba3a5ae573b#fullpageWidgetId=W1e9e966957fa_4233_9429_22d656905674">The&nbsp;Car&nbsp;Forums</a></td>
					</tr>
					<tr>
						<td style="padding: 10px 15px; width: 357px; text-align: center; color: rgb(54, 58, 62) !important; line-height: 24px; font-size: 20px; font-weight: 100;">Please ask your question here</td>
					</tr>
				</tbody>
			</table>
			</td>
			<td align="left" style="margin: 0px; padding: 5px; width: 28%; vertical-align: top;" valign="top">
			<table border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px; border: 1px solid rgb(175, 175, 175); box-shadow: 2px 2px 1px 1px rgb(225,225,225);" width="100%">
				<tbody>
					<tr>
						<td height="25" style="padding: 10px 15px 0px; text-align: center; color: rgb(4, 80, 115) !important; font-size: 15px;">Share your ideas on cars here</td>
					</tr>
					<tr>
						<td style="padding: 10px 15px 0px; text-align: center; vertical-align: middle;"><img height="359" src="http://umb-c6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/toycar.JPG" width="234" /></td>
					</tr>
					<tr>
						<td height="40" style="padding: 10px 15px 0px; text-align: center; color: rgb(4, 80, 115) !important; line-height: 30px; font-size: 28px; font-weight: 200;" valign="middle"><a href="http://umb-c6.ibmcollabcloud.com/blogs/9a4dd0f5-37ff-4347-91ed-5ba3a5ae573b?lang=en_us">The&nbsp;Car&nbsp;Blogs</a></td>
					</tr>
					<tr>
						<td style="padding: 10px 15px; text-align: center; color: rgb(54, 58, 62) !important; line-height: 24px; font-size: 20px; font-weight: 100;">Fun place to share stories about cars, insurance, and safety.</td>
					</tr>
				</tbody>
			</table>
			</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td align="left" style="margin: 0px; padding: 5px; width: 28%; vertical-align: top;" valign="top">
			<table border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" height="513" style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px; border: 1px solid rgb(175, 175, 175); box-shadow: 2px 2px 1px 1px rgb(225,225,225);" width="412">
				<tbody>
					<tr>
						<td height="25" style="padding: 10px 15px 0px; color: rgb(4, 80, 115) !important; font-size: 15px;">
						<p style="text-align: center;">Advanced Defensive Driving - Take it to the Next Level</p>
						</td>
					</tr>
					<tr>
						<td style="padding: 10px 15px 0px;"><img height="251" src="http://umb-c6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/truck2.jpg" width="379" /></td>
					</tr>
					<tr>
						<td height="40" style="padding: 10px 15px 0px; text-align: center; color: rgb(4, 80, 115) !important; line-height: 30px; font-size: 28px; font-weight: 200;" valign="middle"><a href="/wikis/home#!/wiki/Wf0f8d99d4e20_4604_a371_a3611b08ada2/page/Advanced%20Defensive%20Driving%20-%20Take%20it%20to%20the%20Next%20LevelNew%20Page" lconnwikimacro="wikilink" lconnwikiparamwikipage="Advanced Defensive Driving - Take it to the Next LevelNew Page" target="_blank">Click here to find out more</a></td>
					</tr>
					<tr>
						<td style="padding: 10px 15px; text-align: center; color: rgb(54, 58, 62) !important; line-height: 24px; font-size: 20px; font-weight: 100;">According to the National Safety Council, a preventable accident is one in which the driver failed to do everything that reasonably could have been done to avoid the crash.</td>
					</tr>
				</tbody>
			</table>
			</td>
			<td align="left" style="margin: 0px; padding: 5px; width: 28%; vertical-align: top;" valign="top">
			<table border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px; border: 1px solid rgb(175, 175, 175); box-shadow: 2px 2px 1px 1px rgb(225,225,225);" width="100%">
				<tbody>
					<tr>
						<td height="25" style="padding: 10px 15px 0px; color: rgb(4, 80, 115) !important; font-size: 15px;">
						<p style="text-align: center;">Study Shows Car Owners Keeping Vehicles Longer</p>
						</td>
					</tr>
					<tr>
						<td style="padding: 10px 15px 0px; text-align: center;"><img height="288" src="http://umb-c6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/tall%20car2.jpg" width="252" /></td>
					</tr>
					<tr>
						<td height="40" style="padding: 10px 15px 0px; text-align: center; color: rgb(4, 80, 115) !important; line-height: 30px; font-size: 28px; font-weight: 200;" valign="middle"><a href="/wikis/home#!/wiki/Wf0f8d99d4e20_4604_a371_a3611b08ada2/page/Study%20Shows%20Car%20Owners%20Keeping%20Vehicles%20Longer" lconnwikimacro="wikilink" lconnwikiparamwikipage="Study Shows Car Owners Keeping Vehicles Longer">Click here to find out more</a></td>
					</tr>
					<tr>
						<td style="padding: 10px 15px; text-align: center; color: rgb(54, 58, 62) !important; line-height: 24px; font-size: 20px; font-weight: 100;">Today's typical new car buyer keeps their vehicle for almost six years, or 71.4 months to be exact.</td>
					</tr>
				</tbody>
			</table>
			</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td align="left" colspan="2" style="margin: 0px; padding: 5px; width: 28%; vertical-align: top;" valign="top">
			<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><span style="font-size:20px;"><span style="color: rgb(0, 128, 128);">Humor for the day - Take from real customer events.</span></span></strong></p>

			<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size:14px;"><span style="color: rgb(0, 128, 128);"><strong>Signs You Should Probably Stop Driving</strong></span></span></p>

			<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>(An elderly customer calls about her policy, which has increased at the most recent renewal due to an accident she's had pulling out of the drive from her retirement community.)</strong></p>

			<p><strong>Customer:</strong> You know, I'm really a good driver. I just didn't see the other car. It came from nowhere.</p>

			<p><strong>Agent:</strong> I'm sure you wouldn't have attempted to pull out if you'd seen it.</p>

			<p><strong>Customer:</strong> Many of my neighbors sold their cars and ride the bus; several routes go right by our complex. I can't do that, though, because I don't see so well anymore. I can't read those signs they have on the buses that say where they are going.</p>

			<p><strong>Agent: ....</strong></p>
			</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td align="left" colspan="2" style="margin: 0px; padding: 5px; width: 28%; vertical-align: top;" valign="top">
			<div dir="ltr">
			<ul dir="ltr" style="margin: 0px auto; padding: 4em 0px; width: 700px; font-family: roboto, helvetica, Arial;">
				<li style="padding:15px; width: 100%; overflow: hidden; vertical-align: top; display: inline-block; box-sizing: border-box; background-color: rgba(50, 92, 128, 0.8);">
				<h2 style="margin: 0px; color: rgb(255, 255, 255) ! important; text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 1.7em; font-weight: 600;">The Digital Insurance Team</span></h2>
				&nbsp;

				<ul style="width: 100%; font-family: roboto, helvetica, Arial;">
					<li style="width: 33%; display: inline-block;">
					<h4 style="color: rgb(255, 255, 255) ! important;">Home Insurance</h4>

					<div class="staffLeft" role="presentation" style="float: none !important;"><span class="staffComm"><a class="fn url" href="/profiles/html/profileView.do?key=c71b6bfe-a058-4985-9a69-d3c926327241" title=""><img alt="Amy Blanks" class="staffPeople32" height="85" src="/profiles/photo.do?key=c71b6bfe-a058-4985-9a69-d3c926327241" title="Amy Blanks" width="85" /></a></span></div>
					</li>
					<li style="width: 33%; display: inline-block;">
					<h4 style="color: rgb(255, 255, 255) !important;">Auto Insurance</h4>

					<div class="staffLeft" role="presentation" style="float: none !important;"><span class="staffComm"><a class="fn url" href="/profiles/html/profileView.do?key=6cb64a59-1bc1-497b-baa7-38d25bb2afd9" title=""><img alt="Dan Mishkey" class="staffPeople32" height="85" src="/profiles/photo.do?key=6cb64a59-1bc1-497b-baa7-38d25bb2afd9" title="Dan Mishkey" width="85" /></a></span></div>
					</li>
					<li style="width: 33%; display: inline-block;">
					<h4 style="color: rgb(255, 255, 255) !important;">Life Insurance</h4>

					<div class="staffLeft" role="presentation" style="float: none !important;"><span class="staffComm"><a class="fn url" href="/profiles/html/profileView.do?key=ceca5296-cab4-4f51-a897-045c9b458bf1" title=""><img alt="Rebecca Gestner" class="staffPeople32" height="85" src="/profiles/photo.do?key=ceca5296-cab4-4f51-a897-045c9b458bf1" title="Rebecca Gestner" width="85" /></a></span></div>
					</li>
				</ul>

				<p style="margin: 0px; color: rgb(255, 255, 255); font-size: 1.2em;">&nbsp;</p>
				</li>
			</ul>
			</div>
			</td>
		</tr>
	</tbody>
</table>
</div>
</div>]]></content>
                     <tags>auto,cars,community</tags>
                  </page>
                  <page user="dmishkey">
                     <title>Advanced Defensive Driving - Take it to the Next LevelNew Page</title>
                     <label>Advanced Defensive Driving - Take it to the Next LevelNew Page</label>
                     <content><![CDATA[<div><p dir="ltr">According to the <a href="http://www.nsc.org/Pages/Home.aspx">National Safety Council</a>, a preventable accident is one in which the driver failed to do everything that reasonably could have been done to avoid the crash. Experts agree that driving defensively is your best bet at making sure a crash, collision, or accident doesn't happen to you. We've already discussed the basic concepts behind defensive driving, which include scanning and visualizing everything, having an escape route, and not becoming distracted. Now let's consider some more advanced, preventive measures a responsible driver can take to avoid a potentially life-threatening crash.</p>

<h3 dir="ltr">Maintain Your Car</h3>

<p dir="ltr">Regular maintenance on your car significantly helps its road performance, especially in potentially hazardous driving situations. You can't drive a car defensively if its tires are in need of air, windows, rearview mirror, and signal lights are dirty, and brake pads are worn to shreds. Here are a few steps you should take to keep your car running safely and efficiently:</p>

<ul dir="ltr">
	<li><b>Check Your Tires</b> Make sure your tire pressure is where it should be. The recommended pressure for your car's tires will be in your owner's manual or in the driver's side door jamb. When it comes to purchasing new tires, take into account the weather in your part of the country. Four snow tires total is the safest way to go if you anticipate driving in snow and ice.</li>
	<li><b>Align Your Tires</b> If while driving your car seems to drift to one side or the steering wheel vibrates, you may need to have the tires aligned. Alignment actually refers to a car's suspension, which can move out of alignment over time due to normal driving, a minor accident, or bumping against a curb. Check your owner's manual to see how often your car's manufacturer recommends aligning your car's tires. Alignment helps to insure better handling, which is crucial for good defensive driving, as well as better gas mileage.<img height="116" src="http://umb-c6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/tools2.jpg" style="margin: 10px; float: right;" width="173" /></li>
	<li><b>Clean Your Car</b> A dirty windshield or rearview mirror will prevent you from scanning and visualizing the road for potential dangers. And grimy signal lights or head lights will prevent other drivers from seeing you in bad weather or at night, which pretty much negates any effort you make to be a good defensive driver.</li>
	<li><b>Change Your Brake Pads</b> If when braking, you hear squeaking or grinding, your brake pads may be worn out and in need of replacement. Knowing how and when to brake, especially in inclement weather, is a crucial skill for defensive driving. If you have an antilock brake system and need to stop in on an icy road, stomp on the pedal and when you feel the system's pulses or hear it working, ease up a bit on the pedal until it's only pulsing about once a second. If you don't have ABS, you should push the brake hard and when the wheels stop turning, lift your foot so the wheels turn and rapidly press the brake again.</li>
</ul>

<h3 dir="ltr">Other Advanced Defensive Driving Tips</h3>

<ul dir="ltr">
	<li><b>Yield, Move, Get Out Of The Way</b> Driving defensively for the most part involves avoiding overly aggressive drivers. It may be frustrating to just step aside in order to give a bad driver room to do whatever they want, but it is the safest thing to do, not only for yourself but for everyone else on the road. When you encounter a speeding driver pressuring you to go faster, move into another lane, even if it means going slower. As a defensive driver, accept the fact that you may have to sacrifice your right of way in order to avoid a speeding ticket or collision.</li>
	<li><b>Plan a Route</b> To avoid a time-consuming and potentially dangerous drive, plan out your route out in advance based on current weather, traffic, and road conditions. Local websites, radio, and even iPhone apps can provide you with the information you need before you hit the road and find yourself navigating road construction or an end-of-the-week traffic jam.</li>
	<li><b>Take a Course</b> There's nothing wrong with taking a driving course to brush up your skills, even if you've been driving for years. Check with your agent to see if completing a driving course will give you discount on your car insurance or on roadside assistance plans.</li>
</ul>
</div>]]></content>
                     <tags>defensive,driving,safety</tags>
                  </page>
                  <page user="fadams">
                     <title>Study Shows Car Owners Keeping Vehicles Longer</title>
                     <label>Study Shows Car Owners Keeping Vehicles Longer</label>
                     <content><![CDATA[<div><p dir="ltr">According to a study from the automotive research firm, Americans are now holding on to their new care purchases much longer than in years past. Today's typical new car buyer keeps their vehicle for almost six years, or 71.4 months to be exact. That number has increased by 18 months since 2006 alone. It should also be noted that new car sales figures are boosted by leases, which typically only last for two to four years, which bring the overall length of time owners keep their new cars down.</p>

<p dir="ltr">They also found that used car buyers are keeping their vehicles longer as well. Consumers of used passenger cars and trucks kept their vehicles an average of 49.9 months, which is 17.6 months longer than the 32.3 months reported in 2003. In addition, the trend of buyers keeping cars for longer periods of time has also pushed the average age of vehicles on U.S. roads to a record 10.8 years.<img height="164" src="http://umb-c6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/hummer2.jpg" style="margin: 10px; float: left;" width="182" /></p>

<p dir="ltr">One of the biggest reasons for the decline in new car sales and the increase in overall vehicle age is attributed to the decline in the U.S. economy since 2008. With less disposable income available for a number of Americans, would-be buyers are choosing to hold on to their cars and pay off auto loans rather than trading in their vehicles for newer models.</p>

<p dir="ltr">They also said that people are holding on to their cars because of an increase in vehicle quality. In the past, the prevailing belief was that cars generally reached their performance limit at 100,000 miles, pushing drivers to purchase new vehicles once their vehicles perceived life spans were up. However, a lot of today's drivers have been forced to keep their cars longer than this period, so they've consequently learned that their cars actually still performed quite well despite being over the established distance limitation.</p>

<p dir="ltr">To add to this, automakers have also lengthened their warranties. While most new, non-luxury brands already come with a three-year or 36,000-mile bumper-to-bumper warranty, many have opted to also extend coverage on drive train components like the engine and transmission for up to 10 years or 100,000 miles. Additionally, most luxury brands, and even Hyundai, typically carry a four- or five-year warranty that typically extends to 60,000 miles.</p>

<p dir="ltr">One bright spot for auto manufacturers is that the recent upswing in the economy, combined with the high average age of vehicles on the road today, has helped boost new car sales. Americans bought 12.8 million vehicles in 2014, which was up from 11.6 million in 2013. The number is expected to rise again in 2015, ranging from 13.7 million to 14.5 million this year.</p>
</div>]]></content>
                  </page>
               </pages>
            </wiki>
         </wikis>
         <bookmarks/>
         <files/>
      </community>
   </communities>
   <files/>
   <forums/>
   <profiles/>
   <wikis/>
</icda>
