<icda>
 <communities>
      <community user="rgestner">
         <title>Life Community</title>
         <content><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">Our goal is to share information here to help you understand the importance of life, disability and long-term care insurance in a sound financial plan, so you&rsquo;re able to better protect yourself and your family.</p>]]></content>
         <type>public</type>
         <isExternal>false</isExternal>
         <logo>1f788644-3c82-4a69-9af5-c3eb7e8bb972.png</logo>
         <tags>community,insurance,life</tags>
         <members>
            <member role="owner" user="rgestner"/>
            <member role="member" user="vhanley"/>
            <member role="member" user="samcurman"/>
            <member role="member" user="siduma"/>
            <member role="member" user="jlendler"/>
            <member role="member" user="gbandini"/>
            <member role="member" user="fadams"/>
            <member role="member" user="eelamon"/>
            <member role="member" user="dmishkey"/>
            <member role="member" user="ablanks"/>
         </members>
         <forums>
            <forum user="rgestner">
               <title>Life Community</title>
               <content/>
               <topics>
                  <topic user="fadams">
                     <title>Can I get life insurance if I have high cholesterol?</title>
                     <content><![CDATA[
    <p dir="ltr">
      I have very high cholesterol.&nbsp; Will be able to get life insurance?
    </p>
  ]]></content>
                     <question>true</question>
                     <answered>true</answered>
                     <replies>
                        <reply user="rgestner">
                           <title>Re: Can I get life insurance if I have high cholesterol?</title>
                           <content><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">
      One of the many reasons Americans do not have life insurance is they believe that they won't qualify, or that if they do qualify, the price will be too expensive. This is not always the case.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Many people are able to find affordable coverage despite having common health conditions. Life insurance companies will determine rates based on the severity of the health condition and whether or not it is currently being treated. With the help of a doctor, a condition can be managed so that it has minimal impact on life insurance rates.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Life insurance companies deal with risk by assigning customers a health rating. Generally the three ratings are standard, preferred and preferred plus. Typically there can be a 20% to 30% change in price from one rating to the next, depending on the company. Here are several examples of common health conditions and how life insurance companies may respond.<img alt="" height="199" src="http://connections6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/presure.jpg" style="margin: 10px; float: right;" width="298" />
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <strong>High blood pressure:</strong> High blood pressure, or hypertension, can lead to serious health problems if left unmanaged. Life woman taking medicationinsurance companies will determine a customer's rate class depending on the severity of the condition and whether or not it is being managed with medication. Typically, someone with 150/90 or lower with medication can qualify for standard rates. A preferred rate would likely be for someone with 140/90 or lower without medication.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <strong>High cholesterol:</strong> Over 102 million Americans over the age of 20 have high cholesterol. This is defined as total cholesterol over 200mg/dL. Life insurance companies may classify you as regular with cholesterol no higher than 300-350 mg/dL. Less than 250 mg/dL may qualify you for a preferred rate, while 220 mg/dL or less with medication could place you in the preferred class.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <strong>Anxiety:</strong> 18% of the American population suffers from anxiety, making it the most common form of mental illness. Life insurance companies consider it a risk because it can lead to other health conditions such as depression, substance abuse and insomnia. Applicants with managed anxiety that are on one medication prescribed by a primary care physician can typically qualify for the preferred plus health class.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <strong>Obesity:</strong> With more than 33% of Americans being affected by obesity, it is one of the most common health conditions that life insurance companies deal with. Most companies use the body mass index (BMI) number to determine if an applicant's rate class. Usually an individual with a BMI of 26-28 can qualify for preferred plus, while a BMI of 27-34 can be preferred, and 35-38 or higher will be standard.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <strong>Acid reflux:</strong> With almost 19 million Americans diagnosed with acid reflux (GERD), it ranks as one of the most common health conditions. Since it can lead to ulcers and potentially cancer, life insurance companies see it as a risk. The good news is that most people that treat their mild GERD with over the counter medications can qualify for preferred plus rates. Those taking prescriptions for mild to moderate GERD can qualify for preferred, and moderate to severe GERD with ongoing treatment or surgery would qualify for standard rates.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Don't let the fear of high prices keep you from getting the life insurance coverage that you need. Millions of people suffer from these common health conditions, and many of them could qualify for a preferred or preferred plus rate class. Remember that many of these conditions can be improved with the help of a doctor, medication, proper diet and exercise.
    </p>]]></content>
                           <answer>true</answer>
                        </reply>
                     </replies>
                  </topic>
                  <topic user="jlendler">
                     <title>Do I need life insurance after retirement</title>
                     <content><![CDATA[
    <p dir="ltr">
      I am retiring soon and wondered if I will still need life insurance?
    </p>
  ]]></content>
                     <question>true</question>
                     <answered>true</answered>
                     <likes>
                        <like user="jlendler"/>
                        <like user="ablanks"/>
                        <like user="gbandini"/>
                     </likes>
                     <replies>
                        <reply user="ablanks">
                           <title>Re: Do I need life insurance after retirement</title>
                           <content><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">
      <span style="font-size:14px;"><strong>Life Insurance After Retirement: Oxymoron?</strong></span>
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <img alt="" src="http://connections6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/oldman.jpg" style="width: 209px; height: 139px; margin: 10px; float: left;" />Unlike health and car insurance, many retirees opt to drop their life insurance policies when they drop their jobs. The logic being that if someone is in a position to retire, they are generally financially stable enough that their death will not leave a spouse or other loved one struggling to make ends meet. While you don't need life insurance under these circumstances, there are a few reasons why you might want to hold onto your policy.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <strong>Posterity</strong>
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Whether or not your children are grown-hey, some of us get a later start than others-it is human nature to want the best for your kids. In today's world, that often translates to monetary support. Your life insurance policy can provide your children extra financial security for years to come. And if you have younger kids at home, a life insurance policy can ensure they are able to attend college or pursue other professional opportunities.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <strong>The Greater Good</strong>
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      If your family is already protected in the event of your passing, you may want your life insurance policy to be paid out to an organization or charity whose mission you support. Naming a charity as your primary beneficiary is a feel-good way to leave behind a lasting legacy.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <strong>Estate Purposes</strong>
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Individuals and families with large estates must develop a financial plan that enables them to afford estate taxes into the future. A permanent or universal life insurance policy promises payout no matter how long you live. The money from this type of policy can provide your heirs with the necessary funds to maintain the family estate without having to tap into their personal assets.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <strong>Business Security</strong>
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Business owners and partners may want to consider keeping their life insurance policies after retirement as private company interests are illiquid assets subject to both taxation and market flux. As the value of these high-risk securities grows, so too does tax liability. This is especially true during times of economic instability. In these cases, a life insurance policy can ensure that your business won't have to liquidate corporate assets after you've gone.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      There is no one-size-fits-all approach to retirement. The same is true of life insurance. Regardless of your financial situation, it is a good idea to speak with an insurance or financial professional to determine which life insurance options make the most sense for you, your family and your assets.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      &nbsp;
    </p>]]></content>
                           <answer>true</answer>
                           <reply user="vhanley">
                              <title>Re: Do I need life insurance after retirement</title>
                              <content><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">
      Don't forget about Social Security offset!
    </p>]]></content>
                              <reply user="samcurman">
                                 <title>Re: Do I need life insurance after retirement</title>
                                 <content><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">
      I think that this is great, having insurance at any stage of life is so important, and I think its so important that the older generation can get benefits of health insurance to suit their age and their lifestyle.
    </p>]]></content>
                                 <reply user="gbandini">
                                    <title>Re: Do I need life insurance after retirement</title>
                                    <content><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">
      Really life insurance after retirement is a must. In my opinion every retirees should consult a financial professional to make sure which life insurance options would suit their family.
    </p>]]></content>
                                 </reply>
                              </reply>
                           </reply>
                        </reply>
                     </replies>
                  </topic>
                  <topic user="siduma">
                     <title>Will being a smoker increase my insurance cost?</title>
                     <content><![CDATA[
    <p dir="ltr">
      I was a smoker for 20 years but now I have stopped.&nbsp; Will this affect my life insurance premiums?
    </p>
  ]]></content>
                     <question>true</question>
                     <likes>
                        <like user="jlendler"/>
                     </likes>
                     <replies>
                        <reply user="rgestner">
                           <title>Re: Will being a smoker increase my insurance cost?</title>
                           <content><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">
      <strong>This Is What Smoking Will Cost You When It Comes to Life Insurance</strong>
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      Smoking is an expensive habit, given that a pack of cigarettes can cost anywhere from $5 in Kentucky to $14 in New York, but there are many other hidden costs, like the extra $50,000+ you might need to spend on life insurance over a 20 year term. The good news, after quitting for just a year, you can turn that cost around.
    </p>
    <p dir="ltr">
      <img alt="" src="http://connections6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/smokers.jpg" />
    </p>]]></content>
                           <likes>
                              <like user="jlendler"/>
                           </likes>
                           <reply user="jlendler">
                              <title>Re: Will being a smoker increase my insurance cost?</title>
                              <content><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">
      Smoking isn't a pre-existing condition, it's a self-destructive behavior.
    </p>]]></content>
                           </reply>
                        </reply>
                     </replies>
                  </topic>
               </topics>
            </forum>
         </forums>
         <bookmarks/>
         <files/>
         <blogs>
            <communityblog user="rgestner">
               <title>Why I Wish My Father Would Have Had Life Insurance</title>
               <handle>1f788644-3c82-4a69-9af5-c3eb7e8bb972</handle>
               <summary/>
               <posts>
                  <post user="rgestner">
                     <title>Are Your Financial Priorities Out of Sync?</title>
                     <content><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">None of us likes to think about death. But it happens, even to young people. What happens to your loved ones after your death (whenever that may be) depends on what you do today with your money: spend a few hundred dollars on an upgrade to a perfectly fine smartphone, or put a portion of that into life insurance to protect your family.</p>



<p dir="ltr">If you were to die, would your family remember that phone? Or that they didn&rsquo;t have to move from your home, your neighborhood or school? You have a choice. How do you want to be remembered?</p>



<p dir="ltr"><a href="http://connections6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/FinancialPriorities2.jpg" target="_blank"><img alt="image" height="1809" src="http://connections6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/FinancialPriorities2.jpg" style="display: block; margin: 1em 1em 0pt 0pt; float: left;" width="617"></img></a></p>]]></content>
                     <likes>
                        <like user="fadams"/>
                        <like user="rgestner"/>
                        <like user="eelamon"/>
                     </likes>
                     <comments>
                        <comment user="eelamon">
                           <content><![CDATA[Great infographic – easy to read and understand.]]></content>
                        </comment>
                        <comment user="vhanley">
                           <content><![CDATA[This is one of the best articles I’ve read in a while. It’s extremely clear and simple and has a lot of good practices and tips which I’m surely going to follow when looking for a life insurance package. I believe, this article shared a great amount of light on the topic. Thank you so much. Keep up the good work.]]></content>
                        </comment>
                     </comments>
                  </post>
                  <post user="rgestner">
                     <title>7 Smart Financial Moves for New (and Experienced) Parents</title>
                     <content><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">My wife and I had our first child in May. The moment they let us take our beautiful daughter home from the hospital without a nurse to guide us was when we realized the new found responsibility that a child brings!</p>



<p dir="ltr">For the past nine years working as an advisor, I have been helping others plan for many of the important events in their lives, including marriage, children, retirement and leaving a legacy for their family. As I enter a new stage myself, I thought I would share some of the financial steps I took to help secure the financial future of my family.</p>



<p dir="ltr"><strong>Create a will and contingent trust.</strong> This is one of the most important first steps. Choosing a guardian for your children helps make sure they are raised by someone who you think will share the same values. A contingent trust helps ensure that the money your child receives from all of your hard work and planning is distributed according to your wishes instead of giving them complete control over everything the minute they turn 18. <a href="http://connections6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/family1.jpg" target="_blank"><img alt="image" height="141" src="http://connections6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/family1.jpg" style="display: block; margin: 1em 0pt 0pt 1em; float: right;" width="213"></img></a></p>



<p dir="ltr"><strong>Update beneficiary forms.</strong> Make sure you double check all of your retirement plans and insurance policies so something doesn&rsquo;t fall through the cracks. Many accounts with beneficiary designations never pass through your will, so it is important that these are also updated.</p>



<p dir="ltr"><strong>Begin saving for college.</strong> There are various options available. You should consult a tax advisor and financial advisor to help determine what is best suited for your family&rsquo;s financial situation. I opened a 529 plan for our daughter. The money in this plan can be used at almost any accredited higher education institute in the world.</p>



<p dir="ltr"><strong>Purchase life insurance.</strong> My wife and I both increased the amount of life insurance we have. We did a combination of term and permanent insurance to make sure we have the total amount we need at a price we can afford.</p>



<p dir="ltr"><strong>Buy disability insurance.</strong> When you are young, your future earning potential is your biggest asset. Get as much disability insurance coverage as you can to comfortably cover your income if you get sick or injured and can&rsquo;t work. A disability lasting longer than three months is much more common than you think.</p>



<p dir="ltr"><strong>Consider a small whole life insurance policy</strong>. I purchased a policy on my daughter. This accumulates tax-free savings and has a guaranteed purchase option, which gives her the option to purchase additional insurance when she is an adult, regardless of her health at that time.</p>



<p dir="ltr"><strong>Look into a dependent care FSA.</strong> Many companies have these plans in place and they are a way to pay for some of your childcare costs with tax-free money. It is a &ldquo;use it or lose it&rdquo; design, so you want to make sure you will be spending at least the amount you elect to have withheld.</p>



<p dir="ltr">&nbsp;</p>]]></content>
                     <likes>
                        <like user="rgestner"/>
                        <like user="vhanley"/>
                        <like user="hreeds"/>
                     </likes>
                     <comments>
                        <comment user="vhanley">
                           <content><![CDATA[I love your tips for new parents. I know it’s difficult at first, but I know you will get through it financially if you work together. ]]></content>
                        </comment>
                        <comment user="samcurman">
                           <content><![CDATA[My friend told me that 529 is taxed & invested? What’s the benefit of having 529?]]></content>
                        </comment>
                        <comment user="vhanley">
                           <content><![CDATA[Where I live 529 plans are not taxed if used for the intended purpose. They have some deductibility on your state income tax.]]></content>
                        </comment>
                        <comment user="hreeds">
                           <content><![CDATA[529 Plans are great for educational purposes, but if your daughter/son do not intend to go to college, or if they want to start their own business, buy a car to go to work, unless it is “qualified” you will be taxed/ given a penalty for touching that money. Therefore, the benefits: it will grow tax free and can be used for college. A con is that you can’t use that money for anything other than educational expenses… so sometimes you want to look into a dividend paying whole life insurance that allows you to access the cash without any penalty and restrictions.]]></content>
                        </comment>
                        <comment user="eelamon">
                           <content><![CDATA[Or, how about a retirement account where you can pull expenses for college education with no penalties.]]></content>
                        </comment>
                     </comments>
                  </post>
                  <post user="dmishkey">
                     <title>Why I Wish My Father Would Have Had Life Insurance</title>
                     <content><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">One afternoon my parents sat my sister and me down for a family meeting that would change our lives forever. &ldquo;I have cancer,&rdquo; my father told us.</p>



<p dir="ltr">He had previously one of his kidneys removed that was cancerous. My father never told us because he was assured it was a low-grade cancer. This time it was different. He was immediately referred to the MD Anderson Cancer Center. The doctors confirmed he had stage 4 cancer. It was an incurable and inoperable cancer and his life expectancy was limited.<a href="http://connections6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/father.JPG" target="_blank"><img alt="image" height="202" src="http://connections6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/father.JPG" style="display: block; margin: 1em 0pt 0pt 1em; float: right;" width="308"></img></a></p>



<p dir="ltr">It was the beginning of the end. His condition worsened, and he was admitted into the intensive care unit due to renal failure followed by a brain aneurysm and coma. At the time, I didn&rsquo;t know what to think, but the worst feelings came over me. I was scared I would never be able to say good bye to my dad or tell him that I loved him.</p>



<p dir="ltr">The day before my 15th birthday, I watched my father take his last breath at 4:20 A.M.</p>



<p dir="ltr">My father&rsquo;s death impacted me emotionally. He was my best friend. We were inseparable! My freshmen year of high school was one of the most difficult times in my life. His death made me realize that my life would never be the same.</p>



<p dir="ltr"><strong>All the repercussions of my dad&rsquo;s death</strong></p>



<p dir="ltr">My father&rsquo;s death greatly affected our family financially. After three years of treatment, our savings were completely depleted.</p>



<p dir="ltr">My mother was faced with medical bills and major house repairs. The exterior walls of the house, chimney and duct units in the attic had holes. Rodents were in the attic and walls of the house. My mother had not worked so she could care for my father.</p>



<p dir="ltr">My father didn&rsquo;t have adequate life insurance coverage. I have had to grow up quickly and work to help my mother.</p>



<p dir="ltr">Had my father had life insurance we would not be in the position we find ourselves today. His death has made my future plans to attend college even harder to achieve. With the values my parents taught me, I have worked hard to achieve high academic accomplishments and was inducted into the National Honor Society. Recently, I was accepted into a University. I received a Life Lessons scholarship, which is helping me reach my college dreams.</p>



<p dir="ltr">Life would certainly be different if my father was still here and cancer free. However, this isn&rsquo;t the case and my only hope is that I would be blessed with financial help in order to pursue my educational goal. With all I went through with my father, it has inspired me to become a doctor of radiology. With that degree I hope to help others in similar situations as my father. I am a strong and better person today as a result of all the obstacles I have overcome. I have learned how important life insurance is to a family and at the age of 18 I have purchased my first policy.</p>]]></content>
                     <tags>death,life,insurance</tags>
                     <likes>
                        <like user="dmishkey"/>
                        <like user="jlendler"/>
                        <like user="vhanley"/>
                     </likes>
                     <comments>
                        <comment user="vhanley">
                           <content><![CDATA[Your story touched me as it hit home. At the age of 11 my mom was diagnosed with stage 4 breast cancer. She was sent to Cancer Center. She was sick for less than a year, and passed away 8 days before her 34 birthday – I was 12. That day changed the path of mine and my entire families lives. My heart goes out to you. I wish you the best in life and with your medical career.]]></content>
                        </comment>
                     </comments>
                  </post>
               </posts>
            </communityblog>
         </blogs>
         <wikis>
            <wiki user="rgestner">
               <title>Life Community</title>
               <summary><![CDATA[Our goal is to share information here to help you understand the importance of life, disability and long-term care insurance in a sound financial plan, so you’re able to better protect yourself and your family.]]></summary>
               <label>W63d3c5044ed4_40ae_b434_e6f28619aa30</label>
               <visibility>PUBLIC_TO_VIEWERS</visibility>
               <pages>
                  <page user="rgestner">
                     <title>Welcome to the Life Community</title>
                     <label>Welcome to the Life Community</label>
                     <content><![CDATA[<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!DOCTYPE html [<!ENTITY amp "&#38;#38;"><!ENTITY lt "&#60;#60;"><!ENTITY gt "&#62;#62;"><!ENTITY nbsp "&#160;"><!ENTITY apos "&#39;"><!ENTITY quot "&#34;">]><div><div dir="ltr"><p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size:26px;"><strong>This is the place to discuss all things about the fullness of Life</strong></span></p><table align="center" border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" dir="ltr" height="1291" style="font-family: helvetica neue,helvetica,arial,sans-serif;" width="883">	<tbody>		<tr>			<td align="left" style="margin: 0px; padding: 5px; width: 28%;" valign="top">			<table border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" height="570" style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px; border: 1px solid rgb(175, 175, 175); box-shadow: 2px 2px 1px 1px rgb(225, 225, 225);" width="417">				<tbody>					<tr>						<td height="25" style="padding: 10px 15px 0px; width: 357px; text-align: center; color: rgb(4, 80, 115) !important; font-size: 15px;">If you have questions we have the answers.</td>					</tr>					<tr>						<td style="padding: 10px 15px 0px; width: 357px; text-align: center;"><img height="331" src="http://connections6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/question3.jpg" width="355" /></td>					</tr>					<tr>						<td height="40" style="padding: 10px 15px 0px; width: 357px; text-align: center; color: rgb(4, 80, 115) !important; line-height: 30px; font-size: 28px; font-weight: 200;" valign="middle"><a href="http://connections6.ibmcollabcloud.com/communities/service/html/communityoverview?communityUuid=1f788644-3c82-4a69-9af5-c3eb7e8bb972#fullpageWidgetId=W35d7defd4206_4f5a_bf75_26180600378e">The&nbsp;Life&nbsp;Forums</a></td>					</tr>					<tr>						<td style="padding: 10px 15px; width: 357px; text-align: center; color: rgb(54, 58, 62) !important; line-height: 24px; font-size: 20px; font-weight: 100;">Please ask your question here</td>					</tr>				</tbody>			</table>			</td>			<td align="left" style="margin: 0px; padding: 5px; width: 28%; vertical-align: top;" valign="top">			<table border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px; border: 1px solid rgb(175, 175, 175); box-shadow: 2px 2px 1px 1px rgb(225,225,225);" width="100%">				<tbody>					<tr>						<td height="25" style="padding: 10px 15px 0px; text-align: center; color: rgb(4, 80, 115) !important; font-size: 15px;">We hope that by reading and sharing stories you will find inspiration and practical advice to make positive changes in your own life.</td>					</tr>					<tr>						<td style="padding: 10px 15px 0px; text-align: center; vertical-align: middle;"><img height="362" src="http://connections6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/lifeblogs.jpg" width="293" /></td>					</tr>					<tr>						<td height="40" style="padding: 10px 15px 0px; text-align: center; color: rgb(4, 80, 115) !important; line-height: 30px; font-size: 28px; font-weight: 200;" valign="middle"><a href="http://connections6.ibmcollabcloud.com/blogs/1f788644-3c82-4a69-9af5-c3eb7e8bb972?lang=en_us">The&nbsp;Life&nbsp;Blogs</a></td>					</tr>					<tr>						<td style="padding: 10px 15px; text-align: center; color: rgb(54, 58, 62) !important; line-height: 24px; font-size: 20px; font-weight: 100;">Fun place to share stories about Life, insurance, and retirement.</td>					</tr>				</tbody>			</table>			</td>		</tr>		<tr>			<td align="left" style="margin: 0px; padding: 5px; width: 28%; vertical-align: top;" valign="top">			<table border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" height="591" style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px; border: 1px solid rgb(175, 175, 175); box-shadow: 2px 2px 1px 1px rgb(225, 225, 225);" width="416">				<tbody>					<tr>						<td height="25" style="padding: 10px 15px 0px; color: rgb(4, 80, 115) !important; font-size: 15px;">						<p style="text-align: center;">The Basics of Estate Planningl</p>						</td>					</tr>					<tr>						<td style="padding: 10px 15px 0px;"><img height="253" src="http://connections6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/estate.jpg" width="383" /></td>					</tr>					<tr>						<td height="40" style="padding: 10px 15px 0px; text-align: center; color: rgb(4, 80, 115) !important; line-height: 30px; font-size: 28px; font-weight: 200;" valign="middle"><a  lconnwikiparamwikipage="The Basics of Estate Planning" lconnwikimacro="wikilink" href="/wikis/home/wiki/W63d3c5044ed4_40ae_b434_e6f28619aa30/page/The%20Basics%20of%20Estate%20Planning">Click here to find out more</a></td>					</tr>					<tr>						<td style="padding: 10px 15px; text-align: center; color: rgb(54, 58, 62) !important; line-height: 24px; font-size: 20px; font-weight: 100;">Death is inevitable and, regardless of how you feel about that, there will be family left behind who will have to manage your estate. With this estate-planning checklist, you will learn how to prepare so your loved ones don't have to.</td>					</tr>				</tbody>			</table>			</td>			<td align="left" style="margin: 0px; padding: 5px; width: 28%; vertical-align: top;" valign="top">			<table border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" height="597" style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px; border: 1px solid rgb(175, 175, 175); box-shadow: 2px 2px 1px 1px rgb(225, 225, 225);" width="407">				<tbody>					<tr>						<td height="25" style="padding: 10px 15px 0px; color: rgb(4, 80, 115) !important; font-size: 15px;">						<p style="text-align: center;">6 Reasons Millennials Should Consider Life Insurance (even if you don't have kids)</p>						</td>					</tr>					<tr>						<td style="padding: 10px 15px 0px; text-align: center;"><img src="http://connections6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/dependents.jpg" /></td>					</tr>					<tr>						<td height="40" style="padding: 10px 15px 0px; text-align: center; color: rgb(4, 80, 115) !important; line-height: 30px; font-size: 28px; font-weight: 200;" valign="middle"><a  lconnwikiparamwikipage="6 Reasons Millennials Should Consider Life Insurance (even if you donâ€™t have kids)" lconnwikimacro="wikilink" href="/wikis/home/wiki/W63d3c5044ed4_40ae_b434_e6f28619aa30/page/6%20Reasons%20Millennials%20Should%20Consider%20Life%20Insurance%20%28even%20if%20you%20don%E2%80%99t%20have%20kids%29">Click here to find out more</a></td>					</tr>					<tr>						<td style="padding: 10px 15px; text-align: center; color: rgb(54, 58, 62) !important; line-height: 24px; font-size: 20px; font-weight: 100;">If you're not sure whether you need insurance or not, consider the following:</td>					</tr>				</tbody>			</table>			</td>		</tr>		<tr>			<td align="left" colspan="2" style="margin: 0px; padding: 5px; width: 28%; vertical-align: top;" valign="top">			<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><span style="font-size:20px;"><span style="color: rgb(0, 128, 128);">Humor for the day - Take from real customer events.</span></span></strong></p>			<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size:14px;"><span style="color: rgb(0, 128, 128);"><strong>Zombies Need Life Insurance Too</strong></span></span></p>			<p><strong>Agent: </strong>Thank you for calling [company]. How may I help you?</p>			<p><strong>Customer: </strong>Yes, I'd like to find out about getting life insurance for my sister.</p>			<p><strong>Agent: </strong>Okay, I can connect you with an agent.</p>			<p><strong>Customer: </strong>Wait, I have a question.</p>			<p><strong>Agent: </strong>No problem, what is your question?</p>			<p><strong>Customer: </strong>Well, my sister died two days ago. Is that going to make it more expensive?</p>			</td>		</tr>		<tr>			<td align="left" colspan="2" style="margin: 0px; padding: 5px; width: 28%; vertical-align: top;" valign="top">			<div dir="ltr">			<ul dir="ltr" style="margin: 0px auto; padding: 4em 0px; width: 700px; font-family: roboto, helvetica, Arial;">				<li style="padding:15px; width: 100%; overflow: hidden; vertical-align: top; display: inline-block; box-sizing: border-box; background-color: rgba(50, 92, 128, 0.8);">				<h2 style="margin: 0px; color: rgb(255, 255, 255) ! important; text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 1.7em; font-weight: 600;">The Digital Insurance Team</span></h2>				&nbsp;				<ul style="width: 100%; font-family: roboto, helvetica, Arial;">					<li style="width: 33%; display: inline-block;">					<h4 style="color: rgb(255, 255, 255) ! important;">Home Insurance</h4>					<div class="staffLeft" role="presentation" style="float: none !important;"><span class="staffComm"><a class="fn url" href="/profiles/html/profileView.do?key=69e8faa9-49ec-4b43-9106-9de27c198446" title=""><img alt="Amy Blanks" class="staffPeople32" height="85" src="/profiles/photo.do?key=69e8faa9-49ec-4b43-9106-9de27c198446" title="Amy Blanks" width="85" /></a></span></div>					</li>					<li style="width: 33%; display: inline-block;">					<h4 style="color: rgb(255, 255, 255) !important;">Auto Insurance</h4>					<div class="staffLeft" role="presentation" style="float: none !important;"><span class="staffComm"><a class="fn url" href="/profiles/html/profileView.do?key=93b73c63-43b0-46d1-a5f4-e2ed9a7245bd" title=""><img alt="Dan Mishkey" class="staffPeople32" height="85" src="/profiles/photo.do?key=93b73c63-43b0-46d1-a5f4-e2ed9a7245bd" title="Dan Mishkey" width="85" /></a></span></div>					</li>					<li style="width: 33%; display: inline-block;">					<h4 style="color: rgb(255, 255, 255) !important;">Life Insurance</h4>					<div class="staffLeft" role="presentation" style="float: none !important;"><span class="staffComm"><a class="fn url" href="/profiles/html/profileView.do?key=d89bb6d8-0699-41df-b050-9bce9d670588" title=""><img alt="Rebecca Gestner" class="staffPeople32" height="85" src="/profiles/photo.do?key=d89bb6d8-0699-41df-b050-9bce9d670588" title="Rebecca Gestner" width="85" /></a></span></div>					</li>				</ul>				<p style="margin: 0px; color: rgb(255, 255, 255); font-size: 1.2em;">&nbsp;</p>				</li>			</ul>			</div>			</td>		</tr>	</tbody></table></div></div>]]></content>
                  </page>
                  <page user="rgestner">
                     <title>6 Reasons Millennials Should Consider Life Insurance (even if you don’t have kids)</title>
                     <label>6 Reasons Millennials Should Consider Life Insurance (even if you don’t have kids)</label>
                     <content><![CDATA[<div><p dir="ltr">There is facial recognition software that will name your friends and ask you if you want to tag them on your social media profile. You can text someone a message from half a world away, and you can play a video game with a complete stranger on another continent. Technology has accomplished so many amazing things in the past 20 years, but there's still no way to bypass our own mortality.</p><p dir="ltr">While it's never pleasant to discuss, your death is inevitable. It is easy to forget this when you're young. Everything seems to be going as planned and most young people have little connection to the heartache of death, outside of the passing of their grandparents.</p><p dir="ltr">But early adulthood is an advantageous time to purchase life insurance. The benefits to doing so are many. If you're not sure whether you need insurance or not, consider the following:</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>1. You have dependents.</strong> First of all, life insurance is not for you. It's for those you leave behind. The people who depend on you your dependents. <img src="http://connections6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/dependents.jpg" style="width: 128px; height: 193px; margin: 10px; float: left;" />Dependents don't have to be children. For insurance purposes, these are people who father with son on shoulders rely on your income, who would have to go without, should something happen to you. This could be a spouse, a live-in boyfriend/girlfriend with whom you own a house. You should also consider your children, parents, grandparents, siblings with special needs, etc.</p><p dir="ltr">If you have any dependents in a long-term care situation (or those you could envision requiring this help in the near future), either due to old age or disability, life insurance is a necessity. Most young people simply do not have the financial means necessary to cover these sorts of long-term care expenses. An insurance policy can help with that.</p><p dir="ltr">Additionally, if you have a stay-at-home spouse, consider the ramifications of your death. Not only would this person be forced to secure employment outside of the home, but pay for childcare as well. How quickly do you think your spouse could find something that would cover these expenses?</p><p dir="ltr">Life insurance gives you peace of mind, knowing your loved ones wouldn't be financially affected by your death.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>2. Costs are lower</strong>. Life insurance premiums are risk calculations based on mortality. Since average life expectancy is somewhere around 79 years old, there's less risk for a company to insure a Millennial in good health. Less risk for the company, means relatively inexpensive premiums for you. Coverage can usually be obtained for pennies on the dollar. (Think about the cost of a fancy latte every week.)</p><p dir="ltr">Premiums are based on the age of the applicant and rates usually increase with age. If you purchase a policy as a 20-something, it will be at a lower rate than if you wait until you're 40. You could save a couple hundred dollars a year, for as many as 30 years, if you act now versus later.</p><p dir="ltr">Plus, qualifying for coverage as a healthy Millennial can be a lot easier and less expensive than applying after you've been diagnosed with a health condition. Don't wait. A health issue can crop up over night and qualifying for a life insurance policy can be a very different experience once you've been diagnosed.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>3. You'd like an additional savings vehicle</strong>. If you always have a reason to dig into your savings, consider purchasing a permanent life insurance policy that not only has a death benefit but a savings component as well. You can borrow against it as well as use it in retirement, depending on the policy and company behind it.</p><p dir="ltr">Think of a permanent life insurance plan as a portfolio asset that will help secure your loved ones and your retirement. Your generation understands the importance of saving for its future. A permanent life insurance policy can help you do that with minimal effort on your part plus there's no limit to what you can contribute to the savings portion, unlike a 401(k) or a Roth IRA. Once you're retired, you can draw on the savings portion of the policy tax-free.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>4. You'd like to supplement your company-backed insurance.</strong> Millennials who are fortunate enough to have a good paying job with excellent benefits may receive life insurance through their company. While this provides some peace of mind, consider purchasing other, independent coverage. If you become sick and are no longer able to work, your work policy will no longer cover you. Since you've been diagnosed with a terminal illness, you may not be able to secure a life insurance policy at this time. Now, when your family needs the benefit the most, they no longer have it. Plus most basic coverage will not cover everything your family needs at a time when they are ill-equipped to provide for themselves.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>5. You want your funeral expenses and debts covered</strong>. Even if no one depends on your income, such as a spouse or children, you should consider your debts and your burial expenses. The average funeral alone costs between $10,000 and $15,000. Some debts would be waived with your death while others would be collected through whatever assets you left. Are your parents in a position to handle these sorts of expenses or will this create a financial hardship for them?</p><p dir="ltr">Millennials will want to decide what amount of coverage they need to pay for both funeral expenses and their recoverable debts when deciding an amount of insurance coverage.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>6. You'd like to leverage riders for more coverage.</strong> Life insurance is not all about the death benefit paid out to your loved ones. There are also riders that can be added to policies to address needs for things like long-term care and disability. You are more likely as a young person to be injured in an accident than you are to be killed in one. If you were injured and unable to work for a certain period, or permanently disabled, do you have a plan in place to cover your expenses? A disability rider to your life insurance policy could safeguard against the unexpected.</p><p dir="ltr">Frankly, most people will never need the financial comfort provided by a life insurance policy while they're young. But if your family is the one who does, your forward thinking and planning will ease their concerns during a very difficult time. How will you plan for your future?</p><p dir="ltr">Â </p></div>]]></content>
                     <tags>dependents,insurance,life,millennials</tags>
                  </page>
                  <page user="rgestner">
                     <title>The Basics of Estate Planning</title>
                     <label>The Basics of Estate Planning</label>
                     <content><![CDATA[<div><p dir="ltr">Death is inevitable and, regardless of how you feel about that, there will be family left behind who will have to manage your estate. Now the word estate may conjure up images of Downton Abbey or an oil baron's fortune, but if you are leaving anything behind, that is your estate.</p><p dir="ltr">The key is to ensure that those who depend on you financially aren't left with more grief and hardship than 3 gen family necessary. With this estate-planning checklist, you will learn how to prepare so your loved ones don't have to.<img height="184" src="http://connections6.ibmcollabcloud.com/images/estate.jpg" style="margin: 10px; float: right;" width="277" /></p><p dir="ltr">1. <strong>Decide who the recipients will be.</strong> If you died today, who would be your beneficiaries of what you leave behind? If you've recently gotten married or divorced, you need to make changes to your bank accounts, will, life insurance policy, 401Ks, IRAs, corporate benefits programs, and any other account that list a recipient. This assures that your financial dependents, current spouse, next of kin or whomever you wish to be your beneficiary is properly listed.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>2. Decide on an estate plan.</strong> Having an estate plan can help your loved ones avoid unnecessary legal and financial hassles and expenses, while guaranteeing that your final wishes are carried out as intended. When it comes to an estate plan, here are some factors to think about:</p><ul dir="ltr">	<li>Have you created a will? A will specifies who takes possession of your belongings/assets when you die. You don't have to hire an attorney to create a will; you can do it yourself. There are professional sites online that can help you create one together.</li>	<li>Do you have a living will or proxy? An advanced directive, or living will, details your wishes for end of life care. For example, if you are in a car accident resulting in a vegetative state requiring life support, a living will determines whether or not your appointed proxy can 'pull the plug.'</li>	<li>Who has power of attorney? A person who has power of attorney makes decisions for you should you be in a position where you are unable or unavailable to do so. This includes signing any legal documents and dealing with all of your financial and legal affairs. This can be an actual attorney or a friend or family member you've deemed appropriate.</li>	<li>Who will care for your children? If you are a parent, you will need to think about guardianship and decide who will look after your children in case you and your spouse die.</li>	<li>Do you have a revocable trust? Also known as a living trust, a revocable trust details who your heirs are; however, unlike a will, it cannot be challenged in court. While a living trust determines who will receive your assets upon your death, until then, the owner retains full control of the assets.</li>	<li>Or should you have an irrevocable trust? Irrevocable trusts are their own legal entities. Should you need to remove some assets from your estate for tax purposes, you can put them in an irrevocable trust, which in essence becomes the owner of those assets.</li></ul><p dir="ltr">Because life is in a constant state of flux, estate plans should be reviewed every five to seven years. If you don't already have one, you can meet with an estate-planning professional for a free consultation.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>3. Purchase life insurance.</strong></p><p dir="ltr">You absolutely need life insurance when someone else depends on you financially. With the proceeds from a life insurance policy, your spouse and/or children can continue to meet their everyday expenses and plan for the future, such as college or retirement. Term life insurance is an inexpensive safety net. Here are some questions you should ask yourself before buying a policy:</p><ul dir="ltr">	<li>How much and what type of insurance do I need?</li>	<li>How long of a term is necessary? Should it be permanent?</li>	<li>Can I keep my life insurance through my employer if I lose my job, resign or retire?</li>	<li>How much can I afford to pay and how do I get affordable rates?</li></ul><p dir="ltr">In addition, you'll want to consider disability insurance in case you become ill or injured and unable to work.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>4. Organized yourself and finances.</strong></p><p dir="ltr">Create a spreadsheet of all of your accounts, their numbers and locations. Print out a copy and keep it with your will, insurance policies and any other financial documents. Keep a copy in a safe deposit box, your attorney's office and/or a safe at home. If you ever need to update your information, revise all existing versions.</p><p dir="ltr">Whether you hire a lawyer, financial advisor or take care of the documents yourself, basic estate planning will ensure that your finances and their allocation are dealt with properly.</p><p dir="ltr">Have you gone through the estate planning process'written a will, purchased life insurance or established a trust? If so, what tips do you have for other financially responsible families?</p><p dir="ltr">Â </p></div>]]></content>
                     <tags>estate,finances,insurance,planning</tags>
                     <comments>
                        <comment user="gbandini">
                           <content><![CDATA[My wife of 31 years just passed and I’m finding the legal hoops to jump through can be exhausting.  Make sure a beneficiary is named in all your bank accounts and RRSP’s otherwise they all go to probate.]]></content>
                        </comment>
                        <comment user="vhanley">
                           <content><![CDATA[Item #4 is key: “Whether you hire a lawyer, financial advisor or take care of the documents yourself.” Another type of trusted advisor to consider having is a daily money manager (dmm) to do this type of record-keeping and organizing.]]></content>
                        </comment>
                     </comments>
                  </page>
               </pages>
            </wiki>
         </wikis>
         <subcommunities nav="false"/>
      </community>
 </communities>
</icda>
